<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerja.me/tag/research/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerja.me/tag/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Research</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work by Neerja Thakkar is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
© Neerja Thakkar 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 11:03:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerja.me/images/icon_hu709051646b5c016a474294f302c76519_2025058_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/tag/research/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #11: FAT*</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written February 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I closed out the insane month of January with a 4-day trip to Barcelona for the FAT* conference, which pulled together computer scientists, lawyers, people in the tech industry, and social scientists to talk about fairness, accountability and transparency in computing. This was my first academic conference ever, and I had an incredible time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go to the conference because it was conveniently a 1-hour train ride away, Fulbright was going to fund my attendance, and it seemed important and relevant to my interests. It ended up being much more meaningful than I had anticipated -  I&amp;rsquo;m so happy I had the opportunity to go! Beyond just talking to CS academics and people in the tech industry, I got to talk to lawyers and professors in non-CS fields. There were so many cool talks that exposed me to ways of thinking I had never experienced before. There were also a handful of Berkeley PhD students there and it was great to meet them and learn about ways I can be involved in similar discussions once I go there. I&amp;rsquo;m definitely excited for what&amp;rsquo;s ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always understood that thinking about the implications and ethics of CS is important, and put effort into educating myself in those areas, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never learned as much about bias in computing, or how to make AI explainable, or challenges in creating AI policies, as I did during this conference. The talks I attended definitely changed my personal evaluation of different AI systems I encounter - right now, neural networks optimize for some loss function that minimizes error, but what they instead were optimized in a way that penalizes bias? I also thought AI explainability was an extremely interesting and important area, since frequently a neural network will give us a result and but we have no idea why it is returning that result, and as a result neural networks lead to all sorts of problems (read 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1710.08864.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; about how a single pixel change can completley fool a neural network).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-miranda-and-anna-at-fat&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/fat*.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me, Miranda, and Anna at FAT*!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/fat*.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me, Miranda, and Anna at FAT*!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the conference, being in Barcelona and with the other Fulbright researchers was incredible. There&amp;rsquo;s a cohort of about 10 Fulbright researchers in Barcelona and they are all amazing people. We had a lot of fun group dinners in the 3 nights I was there, including one with most of us crammed into the corner of a tapas bar and being unnecessarily crazy after one round of beers. At some point in this visit, the Barcelona crew officially adopted me as one of their own, adding me to the group chat and everything, which was adorable. Audrey, a neuroscience researcher who is going to go to med school next year, very graciously hosted me the entire time I was there, and we bonded incredibly. It&amp;rsquo;s rare that you can spend 6 hours one on one with someone, have nonstop conversation the whole time, and then be shocked that 6 whole hours have passed. I attended the conference with Anna and Miranda, the two other CS researchers (both of who are so cool and brilliant and wonderful), and while none of us have explicitly done research in AI fairness or related fields, we had a great time exploring the conference together and talking about how our views on our own research changed throughout it.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-for-some-reason-our-group-photo-after-dinner-one-night-involved-me-being-carried&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_din.HEIC&#34; data-caption=&#34;For some reason, our group photo after dinner one night involved me being carried&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_din.HEIC&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    For some reason, our group photo after dinner one night involved me being carried
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Involved in Pre-Phd Research</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/getting-involved-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 11:03:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/getting-involved-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neerja Thakkar graduated from Dartmouth in 2019 with a BA in Computer Science and Mathematics. For the past year, she was doing computational photography research in Spain on a Fulbright research scholarship, and in Fall 2020 she will be starting her PhD in EECS at UC Berkeley.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research experience is extremely important for anyone considering a PhD (or for anyone who simply wants to explore an academic field, connect with a professor and learn valuable skills). However, for many students, getting involved in research isn&amp;rsquo;t straightforward, so in this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to break down how I got involved in my various research experiences throughout high school and college, and some additional advice for undergraduates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first research experience was the summer after my junior year of high school, when I worked at an immunology research lab at a local university, assisting a PhD student with wet lab research. This experience helped me both in the college application process and in getting involved in research at college. I continued with this kind of bench research when I started college, assisting an immunology professor at Dartmouth Hitchcock Medical Center. I soon realized that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t as interested in bench research, but wanted to do computational research, so I switched to computational biology research, utilizing my immunology knowledge and newfound computer science skills. As I went through college and took more courses, I realized I was more interested in other areas of computer science, so I started research in visual computing, a field which I then continued in during my Fulbright and into my PhD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting involved as a high schooler&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting involved in any kind of research as a high schooler is extremely difficult - professors have their PhD students and plenty of undergrads who already want to work with them, and as a high schooler you have much less experience and coursework. I would recommend cold emailing several (by several, I mean many) professors in an area that you&amp;rsquo;re interested in, describing the STEM courses you have taken and any relevant extracurriculars, and expressing a willingness to learn and be helpful in any possible way. Also, if your high school has any connections with professors at a local university, try to use those - ask your science teachers. If you hear back that there are no positions in the lab you contacted, ask if the PI could recommend another lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience: I cold emailed several (more than a dozen) professors at a local university. I think I ended up hearing back from only about three of them, and two of them were emails indicating that they didn&amp;rsquo;t take high schoolers, but one of them did let me into their lab and it ended up being an invaluable experience!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Getting involved as a college student&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a few ways I would recommend trying to get involved in undergrad research. I have done the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to a professor who taught a class that you enjoyed. Introduce yourself, remind them of the class you took with them and anything special about your performance in it (ex. a final project), and tell them about your other relevant experience in their area. Express interest in doing research with them and ask if they would be open to meeting with you to discuss their research and the possibility of you working with them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cold email a professor who you have never met and send them a similar email as above&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use connections - if there is a professor you are already close with, see if they can introduce you to another professor and vouch for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some other ways you can get involved that I didn&amp;rsquo;t utilize personally, but many friends have:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When you start college, look for programs for freshman and sophomore students to get involved in research - these often exist especially for women, underrepresented minority and first gen students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Look for summer research programs (ex. UROP) at your institution or others. While it can be tempting to only look for internships in industry, research is the single most important thing if you are seriously considering a PhD, so consider spending a summer doing research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also keep your eye out for other opportunities! Professors often ask for people to apply for research positions or contribute to databases of available research projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My experience: I was lucky to go to a college with a huge undergraduate focus, where it was relatively easy to get involved in research, so a disclaimer that I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to try very hard to get involved in research. Here&amp;rsquo;s how I got involved in my 3 undergraduate research experiences:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First research position: immunology research with a professor at DHMC. When I told the PI of the lab I worked at in high school that I was going to go to Dartmouth and intended to continue immunology research, she offered to introduce me to a few of her colleagues. This ended up with me working with an immunology professor at DHMC starting my freshman fall.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Second research position: computational immunology research with Professor Chris Bailey-Kellogg. By the middle of my freshman year, I realized I wanted to pursue research more closely related to computer science (but didn&amp;rsquo;t completely want to abandon biology yet). I decided to leverage my immunology experince and reach out to a professor doing computational immunology research. I cold emailed him, introducing myself and describing my immunology research experience/the computer science courses I had taken. Our conversation went well, and he was happy to have me join his group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Third research position: undergraduate senior thesis in visual computing with Professor Wojciech Jarosz. I took Professor Jarosz&amp;rsquo;s Computational Photography class my junior winter and loved it. A few weeks into spring term, I emailed him to ask about the possibility of being advised by him on my senior thesis. He ended up having the capacity to take me on, and I started brainstormining topics with him over the summer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, getting a research position is far from the hardest part of research, but definitely a crucial one. For my thoughts on acquiring research positions pre-PhD but post-undergrad, read 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neerja.me/post/phd_gap_year_options/&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #4: My Research Grant</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 11:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written October 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe that I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Spain for over a month. It&amp;rsquo;s flown by, and strangely feels like this is my life now, and I&amp;rsquo;m loving it! There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of exciting non-work related stuff happening, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for the next update - I want to take this one to explain what I&amp;rsquo;m doing here work-wise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://graphics.unizar.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Graphics and Imaging lab&lt;/a&gt; at University of Zaragoza. There are 3 or 4 professors in the lab, a handful of postdocs, and a decent amount of PhD students, making for a total of about 20 people, which is pretty large. The lab is full of incredibly smart, impressive people. &lt;em&gt;(In addition to being smart, they&amp;rsquo;re also very nice and fun - I ended up having some fun adventures with my lab mates and am still close to many of them).&lt;/em&gt; They publish at amazing conferences, collaborate with places such as MIT and Stanford (and Dartmouth), and the students intern at top graphics places in industry such as Adobe Research and Disney. I&amp;rsquo;m really honored to get to be working with people that know so much, and I&amp;rsquo;ve already learned a ton. They also seem to be very well-funded, and have encouraged me to attend a conference (there&amp;rsquo;s a few in France/Switzerland in the next few months), which is awesome and such a cool opportunity!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m getting started on a really interesting project here: combining deep learning and compressed sensing, and important technique in signal processing. Here&amp;rsquo;s the basic idea of compressed sensing: Normally when we acquire a signal (I&amp;rsquo;ll use the example of taking a picture), we get way more data than we can actually transport, so we immediately compress it. So an image is always immediately reduced to a JPEG or another form, by finding all of the unimportant information and getting rid of it. With compressed sensing, we only acquire a small fraction of the information (so for a 100x100 pixel image, instead of getting values for all 10,000 pixels, we might just get values for 1,000 of them) through a measurement mask, and then we can reconstruct the original image. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fascinating math that shows that we can with very high probability reconstruct the image if certain conditions hold, and we can perform these computations in a reasonable amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-left-the-measurement-mask-used-to-capture-an-image-of-a-scene-middle-the-captured-image-with-missing-information-right-the-reconstructed-image&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/CS_overview.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;left: the measurement mask used to capture an image of a scene; middle: the captured image, with missing information; right: the reconstructed image&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/CS_overview.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    left: the measurement mask used to capture an image of a scene; middle: the captured image, with missing information; right: the reconstructed image
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some very cool results with this. One of my favorite is a paper where researchers took a single image, that to the naked eye just looks like a normal, slightly blurry photo, but were actually able to get pixels at slightly different times and then from that single photo reconstruct 30 frames for a resulting 1 second video! More recently, with the rise of machine learning, people are combining the mathematical basis of compressed sensing with neural networks to get amazing results in a lot of applications. So my research is generally within this area! I&amp;rsquo;ve only had one meeting for my project so far, but it went well, and I like the people I&amp;rsquo;m working with. &lt;em&gt;(It&amp;rsquo;s fun remembering the beginnings of my project, now seeing what it has evolved into.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my daily/weekly schedule, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much what I want. We have a weekly lab meeting, and I have regular meetings for my deep compressed sensing project. Aside from those meetings, there isn&amp;rsquo;t any time I am required to be in the lab, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found a regular schedule to be helpful. I also have a lot of flexibility to work remotely and take vacation when I want to, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s not in excess, which is really nice. My daily routine is typically something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~8:15 wake up, get ready&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:00 head to take the tram to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:30 get to work, say hi to everyone, and start working. This involves a mixture of reading papers, coding, data analysis, and writing, depending on what I have to do for the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1:30 break for lunch. We all go eat together and take a full hour for lunch or sometimes more. This is an early lunch by Spanish standards, but the cafeteria fills up at 2 so we try to get there before that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2:30 hit the coffee machine after lunch. There&amp;rsquo;s a vending machine that will make you any sort of coffee/hot chocolate beverage you want (very common in Europe, we need these in America), but I prefer these machines - 40 cents for some of the best coffee! My lab mates think it&amp;rsquo;s unremarkable and that the bad coffee in America has ruined my standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/coffee_machine.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/coffee_machine.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~2:45/3, depending on how long a coffee break we take: back to work! Often around now I&amp;rsquo;ll start getting distracted because all my friends/family in the US will wake up and start sending me messages :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5:30 head out, though sometimes I stay longer if I have more to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6:00 go to gym or go for a run!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7:30 make dinner, I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to eat at 8:30/9 but often am hungry much earlier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:00 until bedtime: sometimes more work if I have to, oftentimes reading/watching Spanish TV/talking to friends in America. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll go out for dinner or grab a drink with friends, which will always be at 9 pm or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loving this lifestyle. I might try to join a club or take formal Spanish lessons soon, but for now it&amp;rsquo;s nice to just focus on work and then on enjoying life. I adore doing research full time. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to not have to put time into classes and to be able to make doing research/learning what I need to learn for research my top priority. I love spending my days making progress on my projects and learning a TON and having freedom in what to work on. I&amp;rsquo;m learning a lot about my research style and strengths/weaknesses, which I think will be super helpful when I pursue my PhD back in America. There are definitely stressful points, when code doesn&amp;rsquo;t work or something doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense, or the fact that in research you&amp;rsquo;re literally trying to stretch the boundaries of knowledge which means a lot of times ideas won&amp;rsquo;t pan out. &lt;em&gt;(I ended up feeling these points a lot, but nontheless really enjoyed what I did).&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m also working on 2 projects right now, since I&amp;rsquo;m continuing a project I started at Dartmouth last year, but the intensity of Dartmouth prepared me well, and it&amp;rsquo;s so nice to focus on doing fewer things but doing them well. I also really like the lab environment - I&amp;rsquo;m so happy that I ended up here!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
