<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Minnesota | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerja.me/places/minnesota/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerja.me/places/minnesota/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Minnesota</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work by Neerja Thakkar is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
© Neerja Thakkar 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 10:39:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerja.me/images/icon_hu86b94514bc44f7650ad97bf1bd4dbea1_2402_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Minnesota</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/places/minnesota/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Working From Home</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/work-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 10:39:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/work-from-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to the pandemic, a lot of us who are fortunate to have jobs where we can work from home have been dealing with a new normal. This was an adjustment for me, but after I got used to it, I actually love working from home. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot going on, so it&amp;rsquo;s really important to prioritize taking care of yourself and being okay with not always being at your most productive right now. There are some days where it&amp;rsquo;s really hard for me to focus, but more and more where I&amp;rsquo;m getting a lot done. Here are some things that have really worked for me when working from home:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a few things to think about in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invest in your work space.&lt;/strong&gt; (Or, get your company to.) Buying a monitor made it much easier to stare at my computer for hours. I also bought an ergonomic keyboard, and I have a kneeling desk chair. My back feels so much better compared to when I was a student and lugging around textbooks/studying in a not ideal posture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try to have a distinct work space.&lt;/strong&gt; Then, only do work in this work space, so that you associate it with work and the rest of your home with rest and relaxation. I used to do work in my bed in college, and this was probably horrible for my productivity and my sleep. I&amp;rsquo;m lucky that I was able to take over the spare bedroom in my house, but even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough space to physically shut a door on your work at the end of your workday, designate a corner as your &amp;ldquo;office&amp;rdquo; and only go there to do your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicate with your family or housemates.&lt;/strong&gt; Let them know that during your work hours, you need to focus and aren&amp;rsquo;t able to hang out. Come up with a system that works for you guys and gives you the space that you need. This obviously varies a lot depending on your personal situation, but is definitely worth discussing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, here are some habits I&amp;rsquo;ve found to be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wear real clothes.&lt;/strong&gt; I love wearing comfortable clothes, and my sweats have gotten a lot more use during this time. However, I find that wearing clothes that are a little less comfortable than and least distict from my pajamas is really helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let your phone in your work space.&lt;/strong&gt; I leave my phone in my bedroom while I do work, and only check it when I take breaks. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how much this simple action impacts my productivity! I also recently got an Apple Watch and appreciate the ability to filter only important notifications into my watch, so that even if I&amp;rsquo;m expecting something important, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to have my phone nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take frequent breaks.&lt;/strong&gt; Try to stand up and stretch at least once, if not multiple times, each hour. I take a little extra time after lunch every day to go for a short walk, and this time away from my computer often helps me think through my work with a different perspective, and give me a break that then helps me focus in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give yourself set work hours.&lt;/strong&gt; Decide what hours of the day you&amp;rsquo;re going to do your work, and then constrain yourself to these. I have found that this makes me much more productive when I&amp;rsquo;m doing work, and much happier when I am not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these ideas were taken from the book 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.calnewport.com/books/deep-work/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Deep Work&lt;/a&gt; by Cal Newport, which I would strongly recommend reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello!</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 23:29:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for making your way to my blog! I am excited to see where this new adventure takes me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By way of introducing myself: I grew up in St. Paul, Minnesota with my parents and my little sister, Nitya. In middle school and high school, most of my time outside of school was spent practicing the violin, doing bharatanatyam (a form of Indian dance), and being a part of the math team. In 2015, I moved to Hanover, New Hampshire, to start at Dartmouth College. There, I discovered computer science and fell in love with both a new way of thinking and the potential to make an important impact. I continued violin in my college orchestra and had a lot of fun spending time in the outdoors, getting into hiking and climbing. I also became very involved with sexual violence prevention, eventually serving as a chair on the Student and Presidential Committee on Sexual Assault. I graduated with a double major in Computer Science and Mathematics, experiences both in academia and industry, and admission to the EECS PhD program at UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was excited to start my PhD, but decided to defer for a year. After graduation, I moved to Zaragoza, Spain for a Fulbright research scholarship. I spent the most incredible 6 months in Spain before I had to leave early and return home due to the pandemic. I&amp;rsquo;ve been staying busy at home finishing up my Fulbright research remotely, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make the most of this time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying photography, running, reading, cooking, and now starting this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been good about keeping a consistent journal for years, but when I was in Spain, I started writing more for other people. I sent semi-regular email updates to several friends and family about my adventures in Spain, and really enjoyed sharing what I was up to. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been asked by several people about the process of applying to Fulbright/grad school/scholarships, and I want to post information about that that is hopefully helpful to others, especially other women considering computer science. I have been incredibly fortunate to have so many wonderful mentors and access to resources at an elite institution, and I would love to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned with those who may not have as easy access to this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting lightly edited versions of the emails I sent to my friends (but I won&amp;rsquo;t omit things I have since changed my mind about - it&amp;rsquo;s been fun to reread them and see how things evolved) covering most of my Fulbright experience in Spain, several posts about research/grad school/applying to Fulbright, and other things that come across my mind. If there is anything you would like to hear about, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://neerja.me/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
