<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Minnesota | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerja.me/places/minnesota/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerja.me/places/minnesota/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Minnesota</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work by Neerja Thakkar is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
© Neerja Thakkar 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 13:00:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerja.me/images/icon_hu709051646b5c016a474294f302c76519_2025058_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Minnesota</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/places/minnesota/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #16: Reflections on My Time in Spain</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 13:00:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe that exactly one year ago I landed in Madrid for my Fulbright orientation! So much has happened in the past year, and as cliche as it sounds, I feel like a pretty different person now than I was then. This post will shine a little light on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny because at the time I was leaving for Spain, I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually want to go. When I found out that I got the Fulbright, part of me was really excited and honored, but another part of me was hoping to just stay in the US with my friends and family. My Spanish was rusty and after spending the past 4 years in Hanover, New Hampshire, I felt very comfortable with my college friends, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to move somewhere where I knew literally no one. But a few weeks into being in Spain, that feeling started to turn around, and now I am grateful in so many ways that I had the opportunity I did to live in Zaragoza for 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my reflections from my Fulbright year on a bunch of different facets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Spain and cultural differences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few things about adjusting to life in Spain were particularly stressful. Spanish bureaucracy is a nightmare to deal with, especially when your Spanish is far from perfect. Getting my &lt;em&gt;empadonamiento&lt;/em&gt; and TIE took way too long and far too much effort. Spanish food culture largely revolves around eating meat, so being vegetarian was difficult when eating at a lot of Spanish restaurants, especially with the addition of my nut allergy. The Spanish schedule is very different, and while I largely ignored the traditional schedule and worked a more regular 9-5, whenever I wanted to go out to eat with friends dinner was at 9 or later, and &amp;ldquo;going out&amp;rdquo; meant it was difficult to be home before 5 am. The sun rising absurdly late also never sat sit right with me. On the bright side, I was forced to improve my cooking skills, and I discovered some foods in Spain that I really loved - Spain does mushrooms &lt;strong&gt;so&lt;/strong&gt; well. And paella is always at least pretty good. Wow, 6 months out, I actually miss some Spanish food, even though when I was in Spain I craved all the food I eat in America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there were some frustrations, life in Spain was mostly positive and mind-expanding! In general, I felt much less stressed in Spain, compared to undergrad. While a significant part of this had to do with not having schoolwork, it was also also in large part due to being in Spain in particular. People aren&amp;rsquo;t in a rush in Spain. They wait for other people, and want to enjoy life and make lots of time for their friends and family. Although many of my friends in Spain were a bit older than my friends back in America, it was still interesting to note that a much larger portion of my Spanish friends were in committed relationships. It just seems like people in Spain value friends and family over themselves much more. In fact, I told some of my Spanish friends that it seemed like young people here more wanted to invest in relationships, while young people in America wanted to prioritize themselves, and they told me that just the notion of &amp;ldquo;investing&amp;rdquo; in someone else is so American and representative of the capitalism engrained in our society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of capitalism, I really appreciated the fact that in Spain, people have accepted that a place to live and healthcare and education should be human rights. It&amp;rsquo;s the norm in Spain, and many other parts in the world, to not pay exorbitant amounts of money for college or healthcare. College at the most expensive private university in Spain is under 10,000 euros a year, and on financial aid college can often be completely free and come with a stipend generous enough to cover rent, food and books. The simple fact that Spanish people don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about healthcare or college expenses really changes people&amp;rsquo;s relationships with money, and the lack of obsession with money in Spain was very refreshing after coming from a undergrad instution where many people wanted to go work on Wall Street. In Spain, it’s completely normal for businessmen to be friends with janitors or software engineers to be friends with nail salon workers, and I loved the replacement of social stratification/classism with a general appreciation for humanity. The fact that beer is a euro on average makes going out to bars accessible to everyone, which also makes it easier for software engineers and nail salon workers to get a drink together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On new friends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My lab was incredible. It was really nice to make some Spanish friends in Spain (which sounds weird, but meeting international people was so much easier than meeting Spainards), and I loved going to work every day and seeing my lab friends. Work was very social, since we ate lunch and took coffee breaks together every day, and also hung out on weekends or juepincho nights occasionally, and as a result I got pretty close to them. I talked the most to 3 of the guys in my building, and a lot of our conversations involved us just joking around and correcting each other&amp;rsquo;s Spanish/English (but half of the time when I corrected their English because something was phrased awkwardly they said &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s British&amp;rdquo;), but I also gained so much from learning about their culture and approach to life and work. As a bonus, since we&amp;rsquo;re in the same field, I know with pretty high probability that I&amp;rsquo;ll see them for many more years at conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of the lab, I met a lot of international people in Zaragoza, through the &lt;em&gt;auxiliares&lt;/em&gt; program (English teaching assistants funded by the Spanish government), my roommates, and through Aiko&amp;rsquo;s Spanish class. I enjoyed meeting so many different people and just seeing how many things there are to do with your life besides the paths Dartmouth students often choose. These people were from all walks of life and have gone on such cool journeys that led them to Spain, and I had a lot of fun adventures with these friends and loved getting out of the Dartmouth/research lab bubble. Just our converstaions were so different - in America, people would always start by asking me where I went to school or what I was doing professionaly, whereas here, people would start by asking me where I was from, what I thought of Spain, and other questions that felt more personal in a good way. Being around people very different from me gave me a new perspective on my own life path and decisions that I am so appreciative of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, my Fulbright friends are amazing and truly some of the most incredible people I have ever met. I went from being overwhelmed by what felt like networking at orientation to making incredibly genuine friendships with them. We had a blast exploring Spain and going to bars together, and also had wonderful deep and intellectual conversations. Everyone I met through Fulbright is so passionate, caring, kind, and doing awesome things. I&amp;rsquo;m still closely in touch with so many of my fellow Fulbrighters and I absolutely cherish those friendships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a global network of friends now is amazing, though slightly painful when you&amp;rsquo;re in the country that&amp;rsquo;s handling a pandemic the worst, while your friend in New Zealand has been living a pandemic-free life for months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On research and academic/professional benefits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been so many of these! While I had a wonderful time traveling and exploring and socializing, I also got some good work done, and here&amp;rsquo;s what came out of it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I made wonderful connections with the lab in Spain that I had the privilege to work at. Since academia is really small, I am definitely expecting to run into them at conferences in the future, or maybe continue collaborations as I see how my research interests evolve. I still WhatsApp my labmates with random research questions, or about the tapas bars we&amp;rsquo;ll go to when I come back to Spain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel more prepared for my PhD. I got better at reading papers and synthesizing important points from them, and I had time to take online courses and read up on things I need to learn. I also learned how to swap out the GPU in a desktop which is a useful skill!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focusing primarily on advanced research in a new area showed me how much knowledge exists that I don&amp;rsquo;t have yet. However, I think that realizing you have a lot to learn is an important part of the PhD process, and learning about the gaps in my knowledge meant that I could start filling them, which I did!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got to do research in a completely different lab and country from undergrad, so now when I go to Berkeley I won&amp;rsquo;t see the way things are done at Berkeley as the only way to do things. It was generally great to get a different perspective on my field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immersing myself in research full-time made the frustrations of research much more clear. When you&amp;rsquo;re doing research, you can spend days or weeks or months on an approach that ultimately pans out to nothing. While I had experienced this in college and knew it was a part of research, doing full time research made the extent of frustration I can feel that much clearer, but recognizing this also strengthened my ability to cope with it and showed me what to expect during my PhD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I respect all research and can recognize scientific merit, I realized that I care most about research that has an immediate societal impact (espcially when I got to attend the FAT* conference), which helped me hone my research interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Personal Growth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve definitely became more independent and comfortable with new situations, as comes with moving to a foreign country. One surprise was actually realizing that I love alone time. Before, I always thought I was extroverted, but now I think I’m  equally introverted and extroverted. My alone time in Spain was a nice mix between relaxing and intentional time, where I thought about my goals and journaled. I also adored just walking around different Spanish cities and getting lost in my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely got a lot better at meeting new people and figuring out how to navigate cocktail parties or house parties where I know almost no one - I was shy before, but I actually started to enjoy those situations and always getting to know more people. Before Spain, I would often make close friends and then have fun experiences with them, but in Spain I had a lot of fun experiences with near strangers, a decent amount of who then became good friends. Now, it’s a bummer to not be able to go out and make new friends, but after the pandemic ends I’m very excited to do so again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really happy with the fitness progress I was able to make in Spain. I wanted to start running for a while, but when I got to Zaragoza, I could barely run for 5 minutes. I was able to get to the point where I could run 3 straight miles, and was inspired by some of my Fulbright friends to run a 10K in the spring. I had started training when I had to go home, and it became clear that no races would be happening anywhere for a while, but it’s still great to have gotten to a point where I know I can run a race when it’s safe to again. Overall, I feel much healthier in general - it was really nice to take care of myself and actually prioritize my health, which I hope I can continue doing for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just felt (and still feel) so much healthier in every way - it was great to learn how to take care of myself, prioritize my physical and mental health, and learn how to relax. Spanish culture was exactly what I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, my Fulbright year (or I guess 6 months), was incredible. When I studied abroad during my junior year in Budapest, I only talked to other Americans and acted like a tourist the whole time. I knew that I did Budapest wrong, and I was ready to do Spain right. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; looked like, but I went to Spain with an attitude of opennes and spirit ready for adventure, and now looking back, my 6 months were so much more fulfilling than I ever thought my whole 9 month grant could be! I am excited to return to Spain and see my friends, but I also want to approach the rest of my life with the attitudes I honed in Spain and see where my next adventures take me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #15: Remote Fulbright</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 13:00:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s crazy that it&amp;rsquo;s been almost 6 months since I was in Spain! In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about what finishing up a Fulbright remotely was like. My next and final post in this series will reflect on the academic/professional side of my time in Spain and the personal side of my thoughts on my Fulbright year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got back to the US, everything still felt so chaotic. Many people were very unhappy with the way that Fulbright had handled the pandemic and that we were sent home to a country with an inferior healthcare system. I think that the Fulbright Spain Comission did a wonderful job dealing with a completely unprecedented situation, but that the US goverment&amp;rsquo;s lack of leadership/direction made things really crazy and bad for many people. It&amp;rsquo;s also absolutely horrible that many Fulbrighters lost their health insurance abroad and had to come back to the US uninsured in the middle of a &lt;em&gt;pandemic&lt;/em&gt;, but that is completely the fault of American values and our current administration. After some pressure from Fulbrighters, the Fulbright program did provide reimbursements for all of the travel back and a little extra money to aid the sudden transition back. I was extremely lucky to be able to come back to Minnesota and life with my family, and I won&amp;rsquo;t get into my feelings on this chaos too much more, but you can read some of my friends&amp;rsquo; very well-articulated thoughts 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baltimoresun.com/opinion/op-ed/bs-ed-op-0320-coronavirus-spain-20200319-ssm2ppsfhvhopmwns22ciwxusm-story.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tennessean.com/story/opinion/2020/03/23/coronavirus-tennessee-native-fulbright-scholar-barcelona/2898350001/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The month of March felt a bit rough between watching the world fall apart, mourning the loss of my time in Spain, and remembering how cold Minnesota is until the end of April. However, as spring started to appear (the second spring of the year for me, actually), I realized that a lot of good things were happening. I had been really burnt out after college, and had regained some of my energy the previous summer, but after a few weeks at home I started to feel extremely energized and ready to take on all sorts of new personal and research-related projects again (like starting this blog, and you can read about some other things I did during this time 
&lt;a href=&#34;%28https://neerja.me/post/how-im-spending-quarantine/%29&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). I felt deeply re-invested in research and learning, which has been wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also felt extremely connected to other people. There were so many college friends and friends from back home that it had been hard to stay in touch with, between traveling all the time and time zone differences, but now I was able to talk to them more often. I also have stayed in contact with many friends in Spain and friends I made in Spain who returned home to other places, like New Zealand, and it&amp;rsquo;s been really fun and interesting to talk to friends all over the world during a global situation such as this one. It was additionally wonderful to have more time with family than I had ever thought I would at once (I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t understand why American culture takes so much pride in independence and moving away from family).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also ironic that in leaving my Fulbright program early, I got much closer to many Fulbright friends than I had ever anticipated. Going through the same crazy situation was a great way to bond, and we filled the strange time with game nights and lots of Zoom calls. We even had a virtual Research + Masters journal club a few times, which was really successful and interesting. Overall, I so value my friendships with the other Fulbrighters. A few close friends of mine have also been starting their PhDs/med school right now, and it&amp;rsquo;s been lovely to have good friends who understand the crazy situation I&amp;rsquo;m going through right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually finishing my Fulbright remotely was definitely a very different experience from being in-person. The time difference was significant, and it is completely different to meet once a week over a call than to be in a physical place for ~40 hours a week. So much of the benefit that I got from being at my lab in Spain came through the chats that we had over lunch/coffee breaks, learning from my labmates, getting to go to group meetings, and generally being in a new environment. Going to another country is really about the place, culture, and people, and unfortunately so much cannot be replicated over a computer screen. Of course, staying in Spain and being confined to my apartment wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have fixed any of this, and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy that I was able to return home and spend time with family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fulbright end of year event (over Zoom, of course), was not the weekend of celebration in Madrid that I thought it would be, but nevertheless it was still a fun time. It was fun to see people&amp;rsquo;s faces, and hear recaps of different groups&amp;rsquo; times in Spain. I was also extremely honored to have been voted for two different superlatives - Most Growth from Orientation to Mid-Year (I guess not that hard when you&amp;rsquo;re fresh off a plane and very disoriented when you first meet people), and Best Instagram Documentation (I do love to capture fun moments).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While having to finish up a Fulbright remotely was not what I expected, the 6 months that I did have in Spain were so extremely fulfilling and honestly far exceeded my expectations, so I have absolutely nothing but gratitude for the opportunity and everyone that made my experience what it was!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I&#39;m Spending Quarantine</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/how-im-spending-quarantine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 21:49:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/how-im-spending-quarantine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first came home from Spain, I was overwhelmed by the craziness of having to suddenly pack up and move back to the US, sadness at my Fulbright suddenly ending and not getting to say goodbye to my new friends, and exhaustion. It took me some time to adjust to a new lifestyle, but since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve been staying busy and having a good time. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed continuing some things I started prioritizing in Spain, and learning new things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s nice to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m still living a fulfilling life, even if it&amp;rsquo;s different from the life I thought I would be living right now. It&amp;rsquo;s also been great to finally do things I wanted to do at some point but never would have made time for otherwise. I can honestly say I haven&amp;rsquo;t been bored once since the pandemic started. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research + Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bulk of my time has been spent finishing up research I worked on during my Fulbright grant and also starting to meet with my future PhD advisor and joining in on lab meetings. In addition to spending a lot of time on research projects, I have been trying to stay up to date on current work in my fields by reading papers and attending conferences virtually (so far, ICCP, and parts of Eurographics and CVPR). I&amp;rsquo;m also doing an online course on how to get more familiar with various tools that computer science students and researchers use, which has so far been insanely useful - there will likely be a blog post to come on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family + Friend Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loving all of this time with my family - we were definitely not expecting to have this much time together ever. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to eat all of our meals together, even lunch in the middle of our workdays, and to all go for a walk together every evening. I&amp;rsquo;m very close to my little sister so I have especially adored all of this extra time for us to truly be a part of each others everyday lives! She is a rising sophomore in college and also studying computer science so we have been taking that online course together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also really valued staying in touch virtually (or on socially distanced walks) with friends from Fulbright, college, and my childhood. In some ways, the pandemic brought me and my Fulbright friends closer together, since we never would have had the crazy shared experience of suddenly leaving Spain and then grappling with the pandemic in the way we faced it otherwise. In general, it&amp;rsquo;s been nice to have time to reconnect with friends I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked with in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritizing Health&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been loving consistently getting a solid 8 hours of sleep every night and never having any super late nights, as fun as going to Spanish clubs until 4/5/6/7 am was. I&amp;rsquo;ve been eating healthy and going on walks every day to get plenty of fresh air. I do miss my gym in Spain a lot, but I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten back into a consistent running/HIIT workout schedule and have also started doing yoga regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Hindi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never learned Hindi as a child, but my parents are fluent in it (as well as English and 2 other Indian languages - they are incredible) and I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up watching Bollywood films, so learning Hindi has always been something I wanted to do but never had time for. I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying learning the alphabet and basic phrases, and then practicing with my entire family and asking them questions, making for another bonding activitiy. Having an excuse to watch some more Bollywood has also been an added bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know a lot about how photography works, since a lot of my research for the past year or so has been in computational photography, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t had access to my parents&amp;rsquo; DSLR for an extended period of time until now. It&amp;rsquo;s been so nice to learn new tricks and practice. My photos mostly only consist of the flowers in my backyard, objects in my house, my family, and a few long exposure waterfall shots, so not the most variety, but definitely a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Involvement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a lot of sexual violence prevention work in college, which I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I was a part of, but also became very exhausting, so after college I needed a break from activism. Especially after George Floyd&amp;rsquo;s death just a couple of miles away from me, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to once again take a more active role in doing helpful, and it&amp;rsquo;s been so nice to have the energy and time to do so. I have been trying to better educate myself and my family/friends, doing research on where to donate, and wrote 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://iamn.org/documents/2020/saari/Youth%20Letter%20to%20IAM.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this letter&lt;/a&gt; with some of my friends to try to better mobilize the South Asian community in Minnesota. If you are reading this, you should go 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blacklivesmatter.carrd.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Gwl9omY8l5dUCkK4Y2llKAsfx5asES9zWn4Tr27QhTU/mobilebasic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to sign petitions, find ways to help, and better educate yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently kept a journal for a while, so it&amp;rsquo;s been nice to keep that up, but starting this blog has been a very different adventure! It&amp;rsquo;s fun to write with a little more purpose and try to write about topics that would hopefully actually be helpful for others, or that friends might want to read about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #10: The Longest Winter Break</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:51:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written January 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so happy to go home for the holidays, even though I had to experience a taste of Minnesota winter. It was incredible to be with my family and see friends back home, as always, but it felt especially comforting to have the familiarity and ease of being around the people I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up with who speak English the same way I do. One of the biggest highlights was food - as a vegetarian, traditional Spanish cuisine is not the best for me, and Spain also lacks good Asian food, so I relished in going to all my favorite restaurants back home and eating my mom&amp;rsquo;s food. Another highlight was trying out a free week of hot yoga with my sister and generally getting to spend time with her. Overall, I  realized that there are things in America I love and feel more comfortable with, but there were things about Spain I missed too, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready to leave Spain (and I&amp;rsquo;m still not&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a hard transition back to America). &lt;em&gt;(My transition back ended up being so premature and jarring in a very different way from how I expected.)&lt;/em&gt; Right after New Years, I stopped in NYC for about 48 hours on the way back to meet up with some friends for a truly glorious 48 hours. I&amp;rsquo;m impressed at how much food I was able to consume in those 48 hours. We also discovered a really cool speakeasy and overall had the best time! &lt;em&gt;(Rip NYC - it&amp;rsquo;s crazy that I was there so recently. Definitely happy that I enjoyed it while I could.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-enjoying-some-ethiopian-food-in-nyc-with-my-best-friend&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ethiopian_nyc.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Enjoying some Ethiopian food in NYC with my best friend&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ethiopian_nyc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Enjoying some Ethiopian food in NYC with my best friend
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to Spain on January 5 so that I could spend January 6, &lt;em&gt;Dia de los Reyes&lt;/em&gt;, with my friend Cristina and her family, who live just outside of Madrid. &lt;em&gt;Dia de los Reyes&lt;/em&gt; is the most important day of Christamas in Spain - the day where everyone opens their presents, and then eats &lt;em&gt;roscon&lt;/em&gt;, a traditional cake. It was very cool to experience Christmas as they do. My family doesn&amp;rsquo;t do traditional Christmas gifts, so it was fun to do that with her family (they were very generous!). Her family is the sweetest and I had a lovely time despite the jet lag.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-cristinas-familys-christmas-tree&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/christmas_tree.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cristina&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;rsquo;s Christmas tree&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/christmas_tree.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Cristina&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;rsquo;s Christmas tree
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-roscon-it-has-a-little-toy-baked-into-it&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/roscon.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;The roscon. It has a little toy baked into it&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/roscon.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The &lt;em&gt;roscon&lt;/em&gt;. It has a little toy baked into it
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I went back to Zaragoza for 5 days before I was off to India for a whirlwind 6 day trip! Those few days were truly a warm, crazy fever dream. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really sleep but I did eat so much good food (I really forget how amazing Indian food in India is) and saw an insane amount of family members. My family in India consists of a few hundred people and so the majority of my trip was just me trying to remember the names of the relative I was talking to&amp;hellip;we really need a pocket family tree.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-reunited-with-my-favorite-person-after-a-whole-week-apart-and-also-with-some-of-my-favorite-food&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/nitya_swatis.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Reunited with my favorite person after a whole week apart, and also with some of my favorite food!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/nitya_swatis.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Reunited with my favorite person after a whole week apart, and also with some of my favorite food!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two major highlights of the trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, going to Ahmedabad, where my nana (grandfather on mom&amp;rsquo;s side) grew up and my mom frequently went as a child. We have some family there that I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen that much, so it was nice to see them. Some of them live in a house that has a backyard with trees that grow little baby guavas and real peacocks that hang out there! There was also a kite flying festival when we visited, where all the kids (and many adults) fly kites all day and night. During the day, people try to &amp;ldquo;cut&amp;rdquo; other people&amp;rsquo;s kites out of the sky (the kite strings are made with broken glass and so you can also easily cut yourself while flying a kite), and at night, people string lanterns on kites. Lots of safety/fire hazards, but still an amazing time, and very pretty.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-flying-kites-with-my-sister-dad-and-some-uncles&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites_daylight.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Flying kites with my sister, dad and some uncles&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites_daylight.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Flying kites with my sister, dad and some uncles
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-kites-at-night-were-so-beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The kites at night were so beautiful!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The kites at night were so beautiful!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, the wedding, which was mostly why we were there. Indian weddings are INSANE. This wedding was only 2.5 days long, and it was the shortest Indian wedding I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard of - it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for most weddings to take place over 5 days or even a week. There were 4 different functions, so I of course had to wear 4 different outfits. One of my favorite parts was the &lt;em&gt;baraat&lt;/em&gt;, where the groom&amp;rsquo;s family dances in the streets directly before the actual wedding ceremony. My dad is such a child at heart and it&amp;rsquo;s adorable - he especially enjoyed a lot of the wedding. Overall, it was fun to be surrounded by so much family, and to see my dad with all the people he grew up with!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-love-a-family-photo&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/family_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;We love a family photo!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/family_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We love a family photo!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-all-the-wedding-outfits-are-a-lot-of-fun&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;All the wedding outfits are a lot of fun&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    All the wedding outfits are a lot of fun
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-my-dad-had-a-great-time-at-the-wedding-with-his-cousins&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/dad_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;My dad had a GREAT time at the wedding with his cousins&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/dad_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    My dad had a GREAT time at the wedding with his cousins
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-maybe-13-of-the-cousins-on-my-dads-side-my-grandmother-on-his-side-is-one-of-7-sisters&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/cousins_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Maybe 1/3 of the cousins on my dad&amp;rsquo;s side (my grandmother on his side is one of 7 sisters&amp;hellip;)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/cousins_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Maybe 1/3 of the cousins on my dad&amp;rsquo;s side (my grandmother on his side is one of 7 sisters&amp;hellip;)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Working From Home</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/work-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 10:39:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/work-from-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neerja Thakkar graduated from Dartmouth in 2019 with a BA in Computer Science and Mathematics. For the past year, she was doing computational photography research in Spain on a Fulbright research scholarship, and in Fall 2020 she will be starting her PhD in EECS at UC Berkeley.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the pandemic, a lot of us who are fortunate to have jobs where we can work from home have been dealing with a new normal. This was an adjustment for me, but after I got used to it, I actually love working from home. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot going on, so it&amp;rsquo;s really important to prioritize taking care of yourself and being okay with not always being at your most productive right now. There are some days where it&amp;rsquo;s really hard for me to focus, but more and more where I&amp;rsquo;m getting a lot done. Here are some things that have really worked for me when working from home:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a few things to think about in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invest in your work space.&lt;/strong&gt; (Or, get your company to.) Buying a monitor made it much easier to stare at my computer for hours. I also bought an ergonomic keyboard, and I have a kneeling desk chair. My back feels so much better compared to when I was a student and lugging around textbooks/studying in a not ideal posture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try to have a distinct work space.&lt;/strong&gt; Then, only do work in this work space, so that you associate it with work and the rest of your home with rest and relaxation. I used to do work in my bed in college, and this was probably horrible for my productivity and my sleep. I&amp;rsquo;m lucky that I was able to take over the spare bedroom in my house, but even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough space to physically shut a door on your work at the end of your workday, designate a corner as your &amp;ldquo;office&amp;rdquo; and only go there to do your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicate with your family or housemates.&lt;/strong&gt; Let them know that during your work hours, you need to focus and aren&amp;rsquo;t able to hang out. Come up with a system that works for you guys and gives you the space that you need. This obviously varies a lot depending on your personal situation, but is definitely worth discussing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, here are some habits I&amp;rsquo;ve found to be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wear real clothes.&lt;/strong&gt; I love wearing comfortable clothes, and my sweats have gotten a lot more use during this time. However, I find that wearing clothes that are a little less comfortable than and least distict from my pajamas is really helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let your phone in your work space.&lt;/strong&gt; I leave my phone in my bedroom while I do work, and only check it when I take breaks. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how much this simple action impacts my productivity! I also recently got an Apple Watch and appreciate the ability to filter only important notifications into my watch, so that even if I&amp;rsquo;m expecting something important, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to have my phone nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take frequent breaks.&lt;/strong&gt; Try to stand up and stretch at least once, if not multiple times, each hour. I take a little extra time after lunch every day to go for a short walk, and this time away from my computer often helps me think through my work with a different perspective, and give me a break that then helps me focus in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give yourself set work hours.&lt;/strong&gt; Decide what hours of the day you&amp;rsquo;re going to do your work, and then constrain yourself to these. I have found that this makes me much more productive when I&amp;rsquo;m doing work, and much happier when I am not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these ideas were taken from the book 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.calnewport.com/books/deep-work/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Deep Work&lt;/a&gt; by Cal Newport, which I would strongly recommend reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello!</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 23:29:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for making your way to my blog! I am excited to see where this new adventure takes me.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_photo.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_photo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By way of introducing myself: I grew up in St. Paul, Minnesota with my parents and my little sister, Nitya. In middle school and high school, most of my time outside of school was spent practicing the violin, doing bharatanatyam (a form of Indian dance), and being a part of the math team. In 2015, I moved to Hanover, New Hampshire, to start at Dartmouth College. There, I discovered computer science and fell in love with both a new way of thinking and the potential to make an important impact. I continued violin in my college orchestra and had a lot of fun spending time in the outdoors, getting into hiking and climbing. I also became very involved with sexual violence prevention, eventually serving as a chair on the Student and Presidential Committee on Sexual Assault. I graduated with a double major in Computer Science and Mathematics, experiences both in academia and industry, and admission to the EECS PhD program at UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was excited to start my PhD, but decided to defer for a year. After graduation, I moved to Zaragoza, Spain for a Fulbright research scholarship. I spent the most incredible 6 months in Spain before I had to leave early and return home due to the pandemic. I&amp;rsquo;ve been staying busy at home finishing up my Fulbright research remotely, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make the most of this time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying photography, running, reading, cooking, and now starting this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been good about keeping a consistent journal for years, but when I was in Spain, I started writing more for other people. I sent semi-regular email updates to several friends and family about my adventures in Spain, and really enjoyed sharing what I was up to. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been asked by several people about the process of applying to Fulbright/grad school/scholarships, and I want to answer those questions in a way that is hopefully helpful to others, especially to women, first gen, and BIPOC students considering computer science or doing research. I have been incredibly fortunate to have so many wonderful mentors and access to resources at an elite institution, and I would love to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned with those who may not have as easy access to this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting lightly edited versions of the emails I sent to my friends (but I won&amp;rsquo;t omit things I have since changed my mind about - it&amp;rsquo;s been fun to reread them and see how things evolved) covering most of my Fulbright experience in Spain, several posts about research/grad school/applying to Fulbright, and other things that come across my mind. If there is anything you would like to hear about, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://neerja.me/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
