<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PhD application | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerja.me/tag/phd-application/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerja.me/tag/phd-application/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>PhD application</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work by Neerja Thakkar is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
© Neerja Thakkar 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 11:07:36 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerja.me/images/icon_hu86b94514bc44f7650ad97bf1bd4dbea1_2402_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>PhD application</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/tag/phd-application/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The GRE</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/gre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 11:07:36 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/gre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before I delve into how I studied for the GRE, I want to point out that it&amp;rsquo;s crucial to understand the importance of the GRE for your application process before you plan how much time you want to allocate to studying and which sections you want to study the hardest for. Some graduate programs might potentially require certain scores or stress that a specific section is important. Other programs, however, see the GRE as relatively unimportant and just more of a sanity check that everyone has decent scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From what I had understood, CS PhD programs were definitely in the latter category - I heard that I should not give the GRE a lot of importance, and that my course selection/grades, letters of recommendation, and research experience carried far more weight. Therefore, I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the GRE too seriously or sacrifice time spent on research to study, and I would strongly recommend you do the same if the GRE is relatively unimportant to your program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, this post is far from comprehensive, and there are many other wonderful resources on how to study for the GRE that I would recommend you consult. A lot of people have asked me how I studied for the GRE, so I simply wanted to provide my two cents. I was incredibly busy around the time I was taking the GRE, so I ended up only having 4 days to study for it. Thankfully, I ended up with scores that were more than sufficient. Here&amp;rsquo;s my recollection of how I went from having no idea what the GRE was to sitting for it in under a week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources used&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ended up studying completely independently (using no prep courses of any kind), with the help of three resources. I used the two free official GRE practice tests available online through ETS, the free Magoosh vocabulary app, and the Manhattan Prep 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/lb-Book-GRE-Practice-Problems/dp/1506247598/ref=tmm_pap_title_0?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=&amp;amp;sr=&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;5 Lb. Book of GRE Practice Problems&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My approach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with one of the two free practice GRE tests online. While taking it, I was reminded of the SAT, but I was incredibly confused by the GRE format. Thankfully, upon opening my prep book, I was able to start diving into the different sections (see below for a breakdown of each section).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The remainder of my 4 days consisted of 6-8 hours a day spent alternating between focusing in on the different sections of the test. Then, the 5th day was the day before the test. I reviewed some more vocab, took the second free practice test online (which felt a lot more comfortable this time), and gave myself the rest of the day off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Math (Quantitative Reasoning)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I majored in math in college, so math tests were a very familiar feeling for me. The GRE math topics, however, were basically all ones I hadn&amp;rsquo;t explicitly been tested on since middle school, so I did have to spend some time reviewing formulas such as the calculation of standard deviation. Then, it was just a matter of becoming familiar with the unusual format of how math questions are asked in the GRE and looking out for certain tricks - I did this by going through every problem that was a multiple of 5 in the book. Doing a few more than 20% of the practice problems would have been ideal, but since I had very limited time, I focused more of my efforts on other sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Essays (Analytical Writing)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two different essays you have to write, both with different kinds of prompts, and I wanted to become aware of and familiar with what the graders look for in both of these essays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To get familiar with the essays, I read a few prompts and example essays with grader comments explaining what was good and bad about them. Then, I fully wrote out 1-2 practice essays for each category, and also outlined essays for 2-3 more prompts. I focused my energy on critically assessing my drafts/outlines and making sure that each practice trial was closer to what the GRE readers were looking for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reading/Vocab (Verbal Reasoning)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely studied the most for this section, since I was the least well versed in this form of thinking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One major concern was the vocabulary, so I used my flashcard app to learn 3-5 words at a time. I wrote sentences that used those words and wrote them down, and then moved on to another chunk of 3-5 words. I can&amp;rsquo;t say I remember many of those words today, but thankfully I did remember many of them when I took the test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The verbal section itself reminded me a lot of the much-dreaded critical reading section of the SAT, which I had studied for a lot 6 years prior, so I tried to harness that part of my brain again. The format of the verbal GRE was different from the SAT, so I did a lot of questions to feel comfortable with the format and find a thought process that worked for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hope the study methods that worked for me are helpful for you in navigating your study process. But again, I want to reiterate that the GRE to grad school applications is not necessarily the same as the SAT/ACT was to college applications. Therefore, make sure you understand its role in your application as you plan out your studying!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Spend A Pre-PhD Gap Year</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/phd_gap_year_options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 23:31:07 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/phd_gap_year_options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the end of my junior year, I was firmly convinced that I wanted to do a PhD, but I knew that I wanted to take at least a year off before I started it. After taking a year off, I am extremely happy that I did so  - it allowed me to recover from burnout after undergrad, explore a new country, meet a lot of new people, and learn a lot that made me feel much more prepared to start my PhD. Therefore, I would strongly recommend considering a gap year. However, deciding how to spend a year off can be tricky. I considered several options, and talked to my professors and older students about them. Here are some bits of advice I gleaned and my thoughts on a non-exhaustive list of ways to spend a year or two before starting a PhD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work in industry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros: You can gain relevant experience and save a lot of money. You can also see if you enjoy software engineering or other traditional roles in tech companies - if you think you would be happier in those jobs, it&amp;rsquo;s probably not worth getting a PhD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons: Since you probably won&amp;rsquo;t be doing research, this won&amp;rsquo;t be as significant a boost to your application as other gap year possibilities. Once you get used to working at a tech company with perks and a large salary for a while, it can be hard to go back to a student lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do research for a year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros: By doing research, you&amp;rsquo;ll get to figure out if you truly like research and want to make a career out of it. More research experience should also be a big boost to your PhD applications, especially if you can publish, and will help you be better prepared for your PhD. You will get to make connections in academia (which is surprisingly small, and can be a huge benefit when you are considering grad school).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons: It can be hard to find research experiences outside of specific academic programs or fellowships, since many professors prefer to work with their PhD/Master&amp;rsquo;s/undergrad students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do research for a year, on a fellowship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros: All of the pros of doing research for a year. Additionally, when you do research on a fellowship, you should have more choice in deciding what you do - you often get to propose your own research project. Through a fellowship, you will be able to make a lot of great connections with other people. You might also get the chance to live abroad, since many fellowships are international.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons: The application process is often extensive and many fellowships are very selective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a Master&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros: Many of the same benefits as doing research for a year (be sure to look into a research vs course-based Master&amp;rsquo;s). You&amp;rsquo;ll get to take advanced courses of your choosing and hone your research interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons: For most programs, you will have to pay (however, be sure to look into 4+1 programs at your undergraduate institution, which are sometimes discounted, and fellowships such as Fulbright that fund Master&amp;rsquo;s programs, and generally Master&amp;rsquo;s programs abroad, since American tuition is more expensive than that of many fantastic universities abroad). Many PhD programs will have higher expectations of you to have at least one, if not more, publications when you apply, compared to applicants with just an undergrad degree. Also, most PhD programs will still require you to take courses when you get there, and so you will likely add additional years of school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Gap Year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I navigated all of this by applying to my 4 top-choice PhD programs, and also applying to fellowships alongside them. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to get into any PhD programs, but I was hoping that a fellowship would work out so that I could do more research and strengthen my application. If nothing worked out, my plan was to try to work in industry for a year, or maybe do a Master&amp;rsquo;s program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I ended up getting into a couple of my top choice programs, and also getting a Fulbright fellowship. I committed to UC Berkeley and deferred for a year so that I could do the Fulbright. My year off was so much more than I expected it to be, and I would highly recommend considering a gap year (or a few) before jumping into a PhD. I&amp;rsquo;m now going into my PhD feeling much more prepared, well rested, and convinced that doing a PhD is right for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
