<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neerja&#39;s Blog Posts | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Neerja&#39;s Blog Posts</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 21:26:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/images/icon_hu86b94514bc44f7650ad97bf1bd4dbea1_2402_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Neerja&#39;s Blog Posts</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying for the Fulbright Part 2</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/fulbright-app-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 21:26:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/fulbright-app-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post, I break down the most significant components of the Fulbright application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This statement is your chance to present who you are and why you deserve a Fulbright grant. The people I met through Fulbright were not only extremely intelligent and accomplished, but they were all incredible humans - caring, passionate, kind, and determined to do good in the world - and I&amp;rsquo;m sure that their personal statements showed this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the content of your statement vary greatly depending on who you are. When brainstorming, consider a wide variety of questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who you are? Where you are from?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is important to you? What are your values?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What unique experiences have shaped you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What you have done in and/or after college?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you want to do with your life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, craft a cohesive narrative about yourself. There are a lot of fantastic sources of advise for personal statement writing, so I won&amp;rsquo;t go too in depth, but a few thoughts relevant to Fulbright in particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you don&amp;rsquo;t need to discuss Fulbright or your host country in this statement, think about the culture and values of Fulbright and the country you are applying to, as well as the research you are proposing, and make sure that they align with what you propose and show you fitting in the Fulbright community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This statement should complement your Statement of Grant Purpose - make sure that they paint a cohesive and complete picture of who you are, both intellectually and personally. When revising, you can move some information from one to the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement of Grant Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this statement, you should explain the research you&amp;rsquo;re going to do during your grant, and also convince the readers of why a Fulbright grant specifically in your country will help you do your research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One very important thing to keep in mind is that the audience of this statement will probably know nothing about your research area, so you will have to make it extremely accessible. This statement is only two pages, so this will mean that you leave a lot of details critical to your project out, and while this can feel very weird, it&amp;rsquo;s completely okay in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also include some information about how you plan to engage with your host country, since your grant isn&amp;rsquo;t just about your research, but also about cultural exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a broad outline of the statement I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broad, accessible introduction to problem/research area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More detailed technical description of research area/problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of previous work and limitations/room for future work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description of what I will be doing and the methods I will use, and a breakdown of how I will spend the 9 months of my grant year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explanation of why I need to be in Spain and working with this lab in particular for this project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other things I will do in Spain to engage with the community, explanation of my Spanish skills and how I plan to improve them before moving to Spain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How my experience has given me the skills and positioned me to be successful at this project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How this grant ties into my future career goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letters of Recommendation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultivating close relationships with professors can only happen far before you apply for a Fulbright, but there&amp;rsquo;s still a lot you can do as you apply to ensure that your letters are the strongest they can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give your letter writers ample time to write for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to ask (reminding them of who you are/what classes you took with them if they might not know), and when they say yes, respond with your CV, a summary of what program and kind of research you are applying for, and a list of things you would like them to talk about. You should absolutely mention small details or accomplishements that feel minor which the professor might not recall - the worst thing that can happen is that the professor chooses to not mention it in the letter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to remind your writers about the letter 1 month before the deadline, and again a week before if they haven&amp;rsquo;t submitted it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language Evaluation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different programs have different language requirements. I was recommended to demonstrate intermediate Spanish proficiency, but this varies by country/program - some have strict requirements and some don&amp;rsquo;t even have recommendations. The evaluation itself likely varies a lot by language and school and program, so I can only speak to my experience. I had studied Spanish in high school, so I knew a lot at one point, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t spoken it in almost 4 years by the time I applied for Fulbright. I brushed up by using Duolingo, watching Spanish TV, and speaking it with friends who spoke Spanish. My actual evaluation consisted of a 15 minute conversation with a Spanish professor at Dartmouth, and since I also used past and future tenses, I ended up getting an advanced rating. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that different levels had different requirements, so check in advance with whoever will be conducting your evaluation in order to tailor your practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips for Working From Home</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/work-from-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 10:39:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/work-from-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Due to the pandemic, a lot of us who are fortunate to have jobs where we can work from home have been dealing with a new normal. This was an adjustment for me, but after I got used to it, I actually love working from home. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot going on, so it&amp;rsquo;s really important to prioritize taking care of yourself and being okay with not always being at your most productive right now. There are some days where it&amp;rsquo;s really hard for me to focus, but more and more where I&amp;rsquo;m getting a lot done. Here are some things that have really worked for me when working from home:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a few things to think about in advance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invest in your work space.&lt;/strong&gt; (Or, get your company to.) Buying a monitor made it much easier to stare at my computer for hours. I also bought an ergonomic keyboard, and I have a kneeling desk chair. My back feels so much better compared to when I was a student and lugging around textbooks/studying in a not ideal posture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Try to have a distinct work space.&lt;/strong&gt; Then, only do work in this work space, so that you associate it with work and the rest of your home with rest and relaxation. I used to do work in my bed in college, and this was probably horrible for my productivity and my sleep. I&amp;rsquo;m lucky that I was able to take over the spare bedroom in my house, but even if you don&amp;rsquo;t have enough space to physically shut a door on your work at the end of your workday, designate a corner as your &amp;ldquo;office&amp;rdquo; and only go there to do your work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communicate with your family or housemates.&lt;/strong&gt; Let them know that during your work hours, you need to focus and aren&amp;rsquo;t able to hang out. Come up with a system that works for you guys and gives you the space that you need. This obviously varies a lot depending on your personal situation, but is definitely worth discussing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, here are some habits I&amp;rsquo;ve found to be helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wear real clothes.&lt;/strong&gt; I love wearing comfortable clothes, and my sweats have gotten a lot more use during this time. However, I find that wearing clothes that are a little less comfortable than and least distict from my pajamas is really helpful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t let your phone in your work space.&lt;/strong&gt; I leave my phone in my bedroom while I do work, and only check it when I take breaks. It&amp;rsquo;s amazing how much this simple action impacts my productivity! I also recently got an Apple Watch and appreciate the ability to filter only important notifications into my watch, so that even if I&amp;rsquo;m expecting something important, I don&amp;rsquo;t need to have my phone nearby.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take frequent breaks.&lt;/strong&gt; Try to stand up and stretch at least once, if not multiple times, each hour. I take a little extra time after lunch every day to go for a short walk, and this time away from my computer often helps me think through my work with a different perspective, and give me a break that then helps me focus in the afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Give yourself set work hours.&lt;/strong&gt; Decide what hours of the day you&amp;rsquo;re going to do your work, and then constrain yourself to these. I have found that this makes me much more productive when I&amp;rsquo;m doing work, and much happier when I am not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some of these ideas were taken from the book 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.calnewport.com/books/deep-work/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Deep Work&lt;/a&gt; by Cal Newport, which I would strongly recommend reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #6</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 23:29:04 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written October 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fiestas del Pilar,&lt;/em&gt; commonly called &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;pilares&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; is an ~11 day long citywide festival in Zaragoza. For these 11 days, there are concerts and events from 8 am to early into the next morning (basically 8 am to 7 am). The biggest event happened towards the end, on Saturday 12/10 (look at me using European dates now - that&amp;rsquo;s October 12) with the &lt;em&gt;ofrenda de flores&lt;/em&gt;, but there were countless social, religious and cultural events throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never experienced anything similar in the US. Let me start by describing the city of Zaragoza a bit more, to situate &lt;em&gt;pilares&lt;/em&gt;: Zaragoza seems to be optimized for socialization. One central tram line runs down the city, and along it, there are endless plazas surrounded by restaurants with ample outdoor seating. You can walk through the main center of the city in about 20 minutes. One major plaza, Plaza España, leads into the &lt;em&gt;casco antiguo&lt;/em&gt;, or old town, known for its narrow, windy streets full of tapas bars. There are very few tourist attractions in this city - it&amp;rsquo;s all about the locals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except maybe this weekend, when hordes of people from the surrounding region of Aragon, and also Madrid, Barcelona, la Rioja and other places, came down for &lt;em&gt;pilares&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Pilares&lt;/em&gt; was a much bigger and culturally-rich version of Green Key, Dartmouth&amp;rsquo;s spring music festival, or any other music festival I&amp;rsquo;ve been to in the states. Instead of being 3 days, it was 11. Instead of being limited to a college campus, it was in the whole city, and you could walk for 45 mins through Zaragoza and hear different concerts throughout the whole walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of just college students celebrating, it was everyone. Entire families, elderly people, literal babies with their parents, college students, people of various ability levels, actually everyone. I loved how so many more partook in Pilar than I normally see when I went to bars/clubs in the US. &lt;em&gt;(This pattern holds for bars in general in Spain - it&amp;rsquo;s normal for whole families to go out together, young children included.)&lt;/em&gt; The amount of people that came out and filled the plazas was genuinely amazing. It was also funny to literally see a beer bottle on the ground next to a child in a stroller. Probably a consequence of people being around alcohol literally since infancy, the people here actually seem to party much more responsibly than I&amp;rsquo;m used to at Dartmouth. I expected everyone partying all the time to be gross, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t see any excessive trash on the ground or vomit or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, some highlights of Pilar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First weekend: checked out some concerts and went to a food/music festival close to the city center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the week: Went to more concerts, hung out in the plaza, etc, but mostly tried to conserve my energy. One valuable thing I did take away from Dartmouth is to treat festivals like a marathon, not a sprint.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-and-aiko-at-a-concert-held-by-the-city-wearing-the-red-and-black-bandanas-that-all-women-traditionally-wear-during-pilares&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/neerja_aiko_pilares.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me and Aiko at a concert held by the city, wearing the red and black bandanas that all women traditionally wear during pilares&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/neerja_aiko_pilares.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me and Aiko at a concert held by the city, wearing the red and black bandanas that all women traditionally wear during pilares
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many people were out at all times like wow look at this PACKED plaza: &lt;em&gt;(It&amp;rsquo;s crazy remembering this, the biggest crowd I ever saw, now in the time of coronavirus)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/pilares_plaza.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/pilares_plaza.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second weekend: More concerts and hanging out. The highlight was on Saturday, with the &lt;em&gt;ofrenda de flores&lt;/em&gt;, where lots of people participate in a parade that ends up with offering flowers, which is then arranged into a literal floral mountain. The folwers were incredible. Aiko decided to walk with the Japanese society of Aragon, so we met a bunch of people through that and ended the day at a cafe with new friends, which made for a very fun day.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/flores.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/flores.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, we went to an event with giant caricatures of famous Spanish people that we realized had a target audience of children aged 2-7, but was nonetheless still fun.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-caricatures-and-an-audience-of-children-with-their-parents&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/caricatures.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Caricatures and an audience of children with their parents&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/caricatures.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Caricatures and an audience of children with their parents
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final day of festivities ended with some of the best fireworks I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. What a wonderful end to an amazing 11 days!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the next week we were all exhausted and got sick but it&amp;rsquo;s okay because basically from the beginning of October until New Year&amp;rsquo;s is lots of holidays (I have a long weekend for Halloween and a 4 day weekend at the beginning of December&amp;hellip;I love Spain).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #5</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 23:18:39 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written October 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, here&amp;rsquo;s an update about everything in my non-work life, which for once is actually a very significant part of my life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loving my apartment. We got a 4th roommate and her name is Genesis. She is from Venezuela but has lived in Spain for a few years and knows so much about life here that I am clueless about. For example, one night she suggested ordering in food, which I had somehow not realized was something you could do in Spain. And then she proceeded to show me 4 or 5 different apps that I had no idea existed.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-aiko-and-genesis-bonding-on-our-way-to-dominos---turns-out-dominos-is-a-roommate-bonding-mechanism-worldwide&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/flatmates.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me, Aiko, and Genesis bonding on our way to Domino&amp;rsquo;s - turns out Domino&amp;rsquo;s is a roommate bonding mechanism worldwide):&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/flatmates.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me, Aiko, and Genesis bonding on our way to Domino&amp;rsquo;s - turns out Domino&amp;rsquo;s is a roommate bonding mechanism worldwide):
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of other friends, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to know Aparna, a woman in Aiko&amp;rsquo;s intensive 20-hours-a-week Spanish class. She&amp;rsquo;s a professional yoga instructor from India and here to learn Spanish to take her yoga business to other countries (I&amp;rsquo;m being exposed to so many meaningful things people do with their lives that would have never occurred to me back at Dartmouth). Aparna, Aiko and I all go to the same gym and have had fun exploring the city together.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-yoga-in-the-park-next-to-my-apartment&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/yoga.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Yoga in the park next to my apartment&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/yoga.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Yoga in the park next to my apartment
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-tapas-y-cerveza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/aikoaparna.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Tapas y cerveza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/aikoaparna.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Tapas y cerveza&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how everyone I hang out with is at least about 4 years older than me - such a change from college! I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying meeting new people, but I still feel pretty connected to people far away (my favorite times of the day are tied between when I have my afternoon cup of coffee and when my family and close friends Sarah and Sean wake up and text me every day without fail). I&amp;rsquo;m also enjoying having more time to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been so cool to live and work with people from completely varied backgrounds. Almost every day at lunch with my labmates, we fall into talking about a given subject and how it compares in Spain vs the US vs France (we have a postdoc from Nice) - meal sizes/times, how leaders are elected, mushrooms, coffee, PhD programs, cheese, really anything&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s funny how the smallest things can be so different from place to place. And the small things really matter. For example, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that people here care more about waiting for others. If we&amp;rsquo;re walking back from a group meeting or lunch and someone for any reason wants to have a quick conversation with someone, we all wait for them and then walk back to our lab together. While this action is unnatural to me after a lifetime in America, I love the concept and practice of treating people like they are more important than maximal productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today during our post-lunch coffee break (a daily ritual here), we were talking about stereotypes people have about other countries. Someone said that Spain is known as being all about &amp;ldquo;siesta and fiesta&amp;rdquo; and honestly&amp;hellip;not an inaccurate way to describe my life. I&amp;rsquo;m actually learning how to chill! (I do have some problems with the concept of &amp;ldquo;chill&amp;rdquo; the way it is frequently used, but I think that relaxing is nice.) When I was in college, I would do work all the time, even on breaks. But now, I&amp;rsquo;ve actually decided to stop working when I leave work, and to relax over the weekends, and to prioritize my sleep and health and friendships over or at least on par with work. I know that there&amp;rsquo;s so much more to life than work, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t always lived my life that way, and right now is the perfect time for me to develop a sustainable balance. I left Dartmouth so burnt out and don&amp;rsquo;t want to feel the same way during/after my PhD, because life is too short to be exhausted and stressed out all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking Spanish has been an adventure. I have a certain sense of humor in English, and I also have a sense of humor in Spanish (or maybe I just make people laugh by sounding stupid), but they&amp;rsquo;re distinct. The way I form thoughts in English is so different from how I have to think through Spanish, and speaking a lot of Spanish has deepened my appreciation of the ease of speaking in my native language. I feel like my Spanish is improving but not as much as I want it to. When I speak with groups of Spainards, I still have a hard time understanding what they are saying, and coming up with responses in the pace of the conversation. When I speak one-on-one with people, I can have a pretty full conversation and am sometimes surprised at perfect phrases I whip out, but there&amp;rsquo;s a depth at which I can&amp;rsquo;t express myself that I can in English. I feel like I can&amp;rsquo;t connect with people when speaking in Spanish in the same way that I can with English-speaking friends, which is a bit frustrating. I&amp;rsquo;m considering taking Spanish classes to improve my language abilities. &lt;em&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m so happy I ended up taking classes!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things have been inevitably frustrating at times: when I misspeak in Spanish, or when I think I said something correctly, but someone still speaks English back to me. When I realize I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing something one way but there was a much easier way. Having to deal with Spanish bureaucracy (don&amp;rsquo;t get me started on empadronamiento or tarjeta identidad extranjeria). But it&amp;rsquo;s kind of cool that my first time adulting for real is here, because it&amp;rsquo;s going to be amazing to go back to America and know with conviction that the bottled sauce I bought is indeed for pasta, or negotiate a lease in my native language, or to be able to find things like tofu and edamame easily. Things haven&amp;rsquo;t been always easy, but I am so grateful for these experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of what&amp;rsquo;s ahead - my parents are visiting soon and we&amp;rsquo;re going to go to Barcelona (or maybe not, because there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of protests happening there right now&amp;hellip;we&amp;rsquo;ll see) and Madrid and I&amp;rsquo;m so excited! Down the line, some friends are going to be spending part of their winter break in Spain which I cannot wait for. I might also make a trip to La Rioja with Aiko to basically just do a bunch of wine tasting sometime in November. Basically, I&amp;rsquo;ll be traveling a little more than every other weekend and then coming home for Christmas, so the rest of 2019 is going to be crazy in the most wonderful way possible. &lt;em&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I traveled while I could.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #4</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 11:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written October 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe that I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Spain for over a month. It&amp;rsquo;s flown by, and strangely feels like this is my life now, and I&amp;rsquo;m loving it! There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of exciting non-work related stuff happening, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for the next update - I want to take this one to explain what I&amp;rsquo;m doing here work-wise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://graphics.unizar.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Graphics and Imaging lab&lt;/a&gt; at University of Zaragoza. There are 3 or 4 professors in the lab, a handful of postdocs, and a decent amount of PhD students, making for a total of about 20 people, which is pretty large. The lab is full of incredibly smart, impressive people. &lt;em&gt;(In addition to being smart, they&amp;rsquo;re also very nice and fun - I ended up having some fun adventures with my lab mates and am still close to many of them).&lt;/em&gt; They publish at amazing conferences, collaborate with places such as MIT and Stanford (and Dartmouth), and the students intern at top graphics places in industry such as Adobe Research and Disney. I&amp;rsquo;m really honored to get to be working with people that know so much, and I&amp;rsquo;ve already learned a ton. They also seem to be very well-funded, and have encouraged me to attend a conference (there&amp;rsquo;s a few in France/Switzerland in the next few months), which is awesome and such a cool opportunity!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m getting started on a really interesting project here: combining deep learning and compressed sensing, and important technique in signal processing. Here&amp;rsquo;s the basic idea of compressed sensing: Normally when we acquire a signal (I&amp;rsquo;ll use the example of taking a picture), we get way more data than we can actually transport, so we immediately compress it. So an image is always immediately reduced to a JPEG or another form, by finding all of the unimportant information and getting rid of it. With compressed sensing, we only acquire a small fraction of the information (so for a 100x100 pixel image, instead of getting values for all 10,000 pixels, we might just get values for 1,000 of them) through a measurement mask, and then we can reconstruct the original image. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fascinating math that shows that we can with very high probability reconstruct the image if certain conditions hold, and we can perform these computations in a reasonable amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-left-the-measurement-mask-used-to-capture-an-image-of-a-scene-middle-the-captured-image-with-missing-information-right-the-reconstructed-image&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/CS_overview.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;left: the measurement mask used to capture an image of a scene; middle: the captured image, with missing information; right: the reconstructed image&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/CS_overview.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    left: the measurement mask used to capture an image of a scene; middle: the captured image, with missing information; right: the reconstructed image
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some very cool results with this. One of my favorite is a paper where researchers took a single image, that to the naked eye just looks like a normal, slightly blurry photo, but were actually able to get pixels at slightly different times and then from that single photo reconstruct 30 frames for a resulting 1 second video! More recently, with the rise of machine learning, people are combining the mathematical basis of compressed sensing with neural networks to get amazing results in a lot of applications. So my research is generally within this area! I&amp;rsquo;ve only had one meeting for my project so far, but it went well, and I like the people I&amp;rsquo;m working with. &lt;em&gt;(It&amp;rsquo;s fun remembering the beginnings of my project, now seeing what it has evolved into.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my daily/weekly schedule, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much what I want. We have a weekly lab meeting, and I have regular meetings for my deep compressed sensing project. Aside from those meetings, there isn&amp;rsquo;t any time I am required to be in the lab, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found a regular schedule to be helpful. I also have a lot of flexibility to work remotely and take vacation when I want to, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s not in excess, which is really nice. My daily routine is typically something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~8:15 wake up, get ready&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:00 head to take the tram to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:30 get to work, say hi to everyone, and start working. This involves a mixture of reading papers, coding, data analysis, and writing, depending on what I have to do for the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1:30 break for lunch. We all go eat together and take a full hour for lunch or sometimes more. This is an early lunch by Spanish standards, but the cafeteria fills up at 2 so we try to get there before that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2:30 hit the coffee machine after lunch. There&amp;rsquo;s a vending machine that will make you any sort of coffee/hot chocolate beverage you want (very common in Europe, we need these in America), but I prefer these machines - 40 cents for some of the best coffee! My lab mates think it&amp;rsquo;s unremarkable and that the bad coffee in America has ruined my standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/coffee_machine.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/coffee_machine.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~2:45/3, depending on how long a coffee break we take: back to work! Often around now I&amp;rsquo;ll start getting distracted because all my friends/family in the US will wake up and start sending me messages :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5:30 head out, though sometimes I stay longer if I have more to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6:00 go to gym or go for a run!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7:30 make dinner, I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to eat at 8:30/9 but often am hungry much earlier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:00 until bedtime: sometimes more work if I have to, oftentimes reading/watching Spanish TV/talking to friends in America. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll go out for dinner or grab a drink with friends, which will always be at 9 pm or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loving this lifestyle. I might try to join a club or take formal Spanish lessons soon, but for now it&amp;rsquo;s nice to just focus on work and then on enjoying life. I adore doing research full time. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to not have to put time into classes and to be able to make doing research/learning what I need to learn for research my top priority. I love spending my days making progress on my projects and learning a TON and having freedom in what to work on. I&amp;rsquo;m learning a lot about my research style and strengths/weaknesses, which I think will be super helpful when I pursue my PhD back in America. There are definitely stressful points, when code doesn&amp;rsquo;t work or something doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense, or the fact that in research you&amp;rsquo;re literally trying to stretch the boundaries of knowledge which means a lot of times ideas won&amp;rsquo;t pan out. &lt;em&gt;(I ended up feeling these points a lot, but nontheless really enjoyed what I did).&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m also working on 2 projects right now, since I&amp;rsquo;m continuing a project I started at Dartmouth last year, but the intensity of Dartmouth prepared me well, and it&amp;rsquo;s so nice to focus on doing fewer things but doing them well. I also really like the lab environment - I&amp;rsquo;m so happy that I ended up here!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Spend A Pre-PhD Gap Year</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/phd_gap_year_options/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 23:31:07 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/phd_gap_year_options/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;By the end of my junior year, I was firmly convinced that I wanted to do a PhD, but I knew that I wanted to take at least a year off before I started it. After taking a year off, I am extremely happy that I did so  - it allowed me to recover from burnout after undergrad, explore a new country, meet a lot of new people, and learn a lot that made me feel much more prepared to start my PhD. Therefore, I would strongly recommend considering a gap year. However, deciding how to spend a year off can be tricky. I considered several options, and talked to my professors and older students about them. Here are some bits of advice I gleaned and my thoughts on a non-exhaustive list of ways to spend a year or two before starting a PhD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work in industry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros: You can gain relevant experience and save a lot of money. You can also see if you enjoy software engineering or other traditional roles in tech companies - if you think you would be happier in those jobs, it&amp;rsquo;s probably not worth getting a PhD.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons: Since you probably won&amp;rsquo;t be doing research, this won&amp;rsquo;t be as significant a boost to your application as other gap year possibilities. Once you get used to working at a tech company with perks and a large salary for a while, it can be hard to go back to a student lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do research for a year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros: By doing research, you&amp;rsquo;ll get to figure out if you truly like research and want to make a career out of it. More research experience should also be a big boost to your PhD applications, especially if you can publish, and will help you be better prepared for your PhD. You will get to make connections in academia (which is surprisingly small, and can be a huge benefit when you are considering grad school).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons: It can be hard to find research experiences outside of specific academic programs or fellowships, since many professors prefer to work with their PhD/masters/undergrad students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do research for a year, on a fellowship&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros: All of the pros of doing research for a year. Additionally, when you do research on a fellowship, you should have more choice in deciding what you do - you often get to propose your own research project. Through a fellowship, you will be able to make a lot of great connections with other people. You might also get the chance to live abroad, since many fellowships are international.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons: The application process is often extensive and many fellowships are very selective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get a Masters&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros: Many of the same benefits as doing research for a year (be sure to look into a research vs course-based masters). You&amp;rsquo;ll get to take advanced courses of your choosing and hone your research interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons: For most programs, you will have to pay (however, be sure to look into 4+1 programs at your undergraduate institution, which are sometimes discounted, and fellowships such as Fulbright that fund Master&amp;rsquo;s programs, and generally Masters programs abroad, since American tuition is more expensive than that of many fantastic universities abroad). Many PhD programs will have higher expectations of you to have at least one, if not more, publications when you apply, compared to applicants with just an undergrad degree. Also, most PhD programs will still require you to take courses when you get there, and so you will likely add additional years of school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Gap Year&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I navigated all of this by applying to my 4 top-choice PhD programs, and also applying to fellowships alongside them. I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to get into any PhD programs, but I was hoping that a fellowship would work out so that I could do more research and strengthen my application. If nothing worked out, my plan was to try to work in industry for a year, or maybe do a masters program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, I ended up getting into a couple of my top choice programs, and also getting a Fulbright fellowship. I committed to UC Berkeley and deferred for a year so that I could do the Fulbright. My year off was so much more than I expected it to be, and I would highly recommend considering a gap year (or a few) before jumping into a PhD. I&amp;rsquo;m now going into my PhD feeling much more prepared, well rested, and convinced that doing a PhD is right for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #3</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 23:29:41 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written September 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After orientation, I hopped on the AVE (a high speed train, we really need this in America) and got to Zaragoza! I was exhausted from the combination of orientation and traveling with 2 suitcases that together weigh about as much as me, so I was ready to eat some food and crash. Despite being really hungry, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go into a restaurant, a little bit because I have a fear of eating alone in public, especially in a country as social as Spain, and mostly because most restaurants don&amp;rsquo;t serve dinner until 9 pm in Zaragoza. Wanting to find a grocery store to make some easy pasta, I typed grocery store in Google maps, and nothing came up. Then, I tried translating &amp;ldquo;grocery store&amp;rdquo; to Spanish, plugged that word in to maps, and the only things that came up were sex shops&amp;hellip;.so not helpful at all. I gave up and had some McDonalds for dinner. (The next day I realized I needed to be searching for &amp;ldquo;supermarket/supemercado&amp;rdquo;, oops). So my start to living in Zaragoza was sitting in my Airbnb alone eating some fries - hopefully it&amp;rsquo;ll all be uphill from there. &lt;em&gt;(Thankfully, it was all very uphill!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was busy the next several days with a lot of adult errands. I opened a bank account, and even before Fulbright had sent me my first payment, it was  exciting that my empty bank account said 0 euros instead of dollars - yay to no international transaction fees! I started the apartment hunt, going to places I had found on idealista. Thankfully, my Spanish somehow sufficed. The first 3 apartments I saw were: a place where 2 other Erasmus students lived (European college students that study abroad in other parts of Europe mostly so that they can party relentlessly for 6 months, and remember that the clubs are open until 7 am here), a place that reeked of cigarette smoke everywhere, and a place that had 4 boys living there (not for me). But then I found &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; apartment and luckily things worked out! I have lots of closet space, a dishwasher, a huge living room, air conditioning, and a kitchen that was gorgeous once we deep cleaned it. My roommates are awesome - there&amp;rsquo;s Miguel, a 29 year old from Madrid who is studying to become some sort of lawyer, and Aiko, a 25 year old from Japan who is here to learn Spanish so she can work in the ministry of foreign affairs in South America in a few years. We have a 4th roommate, and all I know about her is that she&amp;rsquo;s coming in a few days, but I&amp;rsquo;m excited to meet her!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found a really lovely gym right next to my apartment. It has 2 pools and a lot of fitness classes and even a spa all included and would probably be insanely expensive in America but since Zaragoza has a much lower cost of living I can easily afford it. I have absolutely no excuses to not work out a lot at this point, and am excited to try out the yoga and spin classes at the gym. I spent a lot of time cooking, which I&amp;rsquo;m loving - I&amp;rsquo;m slowly learning and able to make more advanced things, and it feels so great to cook healthy things for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So overall, even though there have been ups and downs as expected, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling good about my start in Spain. I&amp;rsquo;m actually loving the city of Zaragoza - it&amp;rsquo;s calm and non-touristy but also has a lot to do. It feels weird to have everyone I love thousands of miles away, and it can be hard to only speak in English some days over a WhatsApp or FaceTime call with a poor connection. There have been times I&amp;rsquo;ve felt a bit lonely, especially in contrast to the very social culture in Spain, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been grateful to always have my family or a friend to call. It&amp;rsquo;s been kind of nice to not know people (well, until I got roommates and started making friends) and have a good reason to just spend a lot of time with myself doing whatever I want to do - I can see why people like solo traveling. &lt;em&gt;(I remember that halfway through my Fulbright I reflected on this initial loneliness I felt as I walked through plazas in Zaragoza full of people socializing with each other, and being very grateful for all the new friends I had made that I explored the city with. It can be really fun to explore a place alone, but personally, I love having people to share the experience and grab a caña with.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have very few expectations and am excited to see where this year takes me. All I do know is that I&amp;rsquo;m going to do what I want to do and prioritize myself, and I&amp;rsquo;m really grateful to have this gift of a year in Spain to do just that!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #2</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 23:29:41 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written September 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived to Madrid pretty exhausted off of a red eye, and went to the Airbnb I was going to stay in for the night with another Dartmouth &amp;lsquo;19 who got a Fulbright to be a TA in Asturias, a region in Northern Spain. I was pretty dead, but decided to head with them to a bar for a pre-orientation Fulbright event. The bar consisted of a lot of people my age talking very loudly and I was soon overwhelmed and exhausted at having to scream to converse, a common thread throughout orientation. I opted to not drink, since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really eaten or slept. I was able to meet some people and they were all really nice, but I was happy to leave after an hour to go meet up with Cristina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cristina is my host sister from a 2-week Spanish exchange back in high school, and we&amp;rsquo;ve stayed in touch ever since. She just passed the exam to become a teacher, and she&amp;rsquo;s now teaching English to middle and high schoolers in Madrid. She&amp;rsquo;s one of the kindest and most genuine people I&amp;rsquo;ve ever met, and it&amp;rsquo;s so nice that I started my Fulbright with at least one friend within a 200 mile radius! We had dinner and went to a rooftop bar (which I enjoyed much more than the last rooftop bar that I went to, Mr. Purple, in NYC), and it was wonderful to catch up and talk about potential vacations &lt;em&gt;(I read the word vacations and first thought it said vaccinations - this pandemic is getting to me. Then I remembered there will be no more vacations for a long while)&lt;/em&gt; around Europe we could take together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then proceeded to knock out for 11 hours, which was very necessary because I had no idea how crazy orientation would be. Our days were packed with important info sessions and required social events from 7 am until past 9 pm, and then dinner time was after 9, per the Spanish eating schedule (a breakfast of basically just coffee at 7, a coffee break at 11, lunch at 2 or 3 or 4, and dinner around 10 pm + very little sleep - hence tons of coffee. This country seems a bit permanently jet lagged but so am I so it&amp;rsquo;s all good). I would drink at least 2 cups of coffee, but they make really strong espresso, and I more than once found my body literally shaking from caffeine. There were so many people to meet - it felt like college orientation all over again, except I knew I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to see most of these people again since we are all living in different parts of Spain &lt;em&gt;(spoiler alert: I was very wrong about this)&lt;/em&gt;. Every day we had a mandatory 7-9pm cocktail event, during which we were drinking free tinto (red wine + lemonade, very delicious) and cerveza (beer) on empty stomachs since we were hungry for dinner. I was pretty overwhelmed and delirious, and felt ungrateful for feeling that way because I also recognize that this is an incredible opportunity and was excited to meet so many really cool and passionate people, but I guess a need for sleep is valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The makeup of the Fulbrighters was interesting. The researchers group is fairly gender-balanced and about as diverse as Dartmouth (so, not that diverse, but also not all white), but the TAs were largely composed of white women. I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt that noticeably in the minority in a long time. Clearly, it&amp;rsquo;s a privilege to get a Fulbright, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a huge privilege to be able to do a Fulbright and choose a year of personal fulfillment and travel over a higher-paying job, and that shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I took notes during a lot of the sessions, because while my brain was only half functional during orientation, the information we received was  important and interesting. We learned what Fulbright expected of us - it&amp;rsquo;s really strict in some ways, for example we can&amp;rsquo;t leave Spain for more than 21 days, but also laid back in others, such as the fact that we don&amp;rsquo;t need to deliver any final product for our research (so while I definitely plan to do good work, work doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be my #1 priority at all times). Also, they told us we should definitely take weekends to relax and explore and definitely not do work - what a concept! &lt;em&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m so happy that I used my weekends in Spain for things other than work.)&lt;/em&gt; We learned about a lot of differences between America and Spain. Everyone uses WhatsApp here, people are generally warmer, even in professional settings, drinking is a huge part of the culture in the way that people will even bring their children to bars, every region has festivals that last all night (and also clubs are open until 7 am - I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I can ever go clubbing here because they open at 2/3 am which is when I like to be solidly asleep).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently Spain is quite progressive when it comes to laws around and percentage of people that identify as queer, especially compared to America, which was great to hear. But it&amp;rsquo;s also far from perfect - they told us that there&amp;rsquo;s a tradition in Spain as part of a festival where people wear blackface, and that it&amp;rsquo;s normal for people to joke about things that would be considered very offensive in the US. I have no idea how much of that is really true, and am interested to see what my experience will be like, especially since Zaragoza is not diverse. While the conversation the presentations started was not very in depth, I did approve of the message they promoted about trying to respect where other people are coming from while also asserting our own boundaries and explaining why certain things are not okay for us, when we feel comfortable engaging. I  believe that everyone has their beliefs in large part because of how they were raised and socialized, and that hopefully if I encounter anything unfortunate it can be a starting point for conversations where people can learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to meet all the other researchers and hear about their projects, which was cool. Out of the 25, there are 2 other CS researchers. The split between humanities and STEM research is pretty even. A lot of the researchers are currently doing their PhD, and they know so much about what they are studying so it was super interesting to get to talk to them! &lt;em&gt;(It&amp;rsquo;s so fun to read this, now knowing the friends mentioned here so much better.)&lt;/em&gt; One is going to be excavating ceramics to search for signs of a plague before the bubonic plague in Barcelona. Another is going to collect nuts in a forest in Granada to get data for her ecology project. I spent a lot of time talking to this awesome woman who just graduated from Harvard law and knows so much about Spanish law and random facts about Spain (do you know that Spain is on the wrong time zone because Franco wanted Spain to have the same time zone as Nazi Germany? More support for this country literally being jet lagged). One guy who is finishing his biophysics PhD at MIT just got married to a Spanish woman he met when she did an exchange at Harvard! What a cool group of people - it&amp;rsquo;s too bad that I&amp;rsquo;m not in the same city as any of them, but we have an active WhatsApp group and a few more meetups than the rest of Fulbright Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orientation passed by in a blur, but the last presentation stuck out, from the American consulate in Spain. They said some stuff to scare us, but I really feel like Spain is much safer than America&amp;hellip;there are basically no guns here, and while Spain has a &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; terrorism threat, the US is much higher. The really stupid things Americans have done in Spain was very entertaining. One guy took a lot of illegal drugs in Ibiza and is currently in Spanish prison, so basically do NOT take a pill in Ibiza. Another guy went to visit a friend, went clubbing with his passport, lost his passport and phone, got separated from his friend and didn&amp;rsquo;t know where his friend lived in and so he went to the consulate, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t log into his Facebook to message his friend or remember his mother&amp;rsquo;s phone number so she could wire him money. Thankfully, emergency contacts exist. Also, don&amp;rsquo;t go clubbing with your passport.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying for the Fulbright Part 1</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/fulbright-app-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 23:29:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/fulbright-app-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When you look at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://us.fulbrightonline.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fulbright website&lt;/a&gt;, you may notice that the amount of different programs you can apply to is huge. There are several axes of freedom where you have to make a decision: the &lt;strong&gt;country&lt;/strong&gt; you apply in, the &lt;strong&gt;program&lt;/strong&gt; you apply for (research/TA/masters), and if you do research, the &lt;strong&gt;host institution&lt;/strong&gt; you work with and the &lt;strong&gt;research project&lt;/strong&gt; you propose. It can feel overwhelming to decide which program to apply for and how to go about the process, so in this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to go over some things I considered and explain how I ended up making a decision. Most of this post will only be applicable for a research Fulbright as part of the US Student program, since that is what I applied for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things to consider as you narrow down what you want to do. Here are some things that I kept in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The acceptance rate varies a lot by country and program. I was able to get some numbers from my school&amp;rsquo;s fellowship office (many universities will help you through this process - definitely use those resources if they are available to you!), and I realized that some countries had an extremely low acceptance rate for research/masters Fulbright&amp;rsquo;s (~2%), whereas others had a much higher acceptance rate (closer to a third of applicants were accepted)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://us.fulbrightonline.org/countries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page specific to a country&lt;/a&gt; you are considering very carefully. There are many variations by country and by programs within a country, such as:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some countries have specific requirements (for example, you may need a masters to do research at a particular institution within a country)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some countries have a preference to fund certain kinds of academic fields, so you could be at an advantage or disadvantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some countries have a language requirement or recommendation. Even if it&amp;rsquo;s a recommendation, it would be wise to only apply to that country if you have that competency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host institution selection
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What city is it in? Do you want to live in that city?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who within the host institution would you be working with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can your host institution meet with you as often as you will need and give you the resources and support that you need?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would you be happy in this environment for 9 months?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research project proposal
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even if your project is purely STEM, it needs to have some connection to where you are, since Fulbright is funding you for a project in a specific place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Needs to be supported by host institution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it meet your personal goals for skills you want to gain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With those considerations in mind, there are different approaches you could take. If you have a research project in mind that you want to undertake, you could think of a country/host institution where it would make sense to propose your research project to. Or, you could take the approach I did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew I wanted to do a research Fulbright in the field of computer science (more narrowly, within computer vision/graphics and computational photography). I also wanted to spend a year somewhere in Europe. Narrowing down countries by their acceptance rates, so that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t applying anywhere that generally took less than 10% of applicants, and also by looking for those where language wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a significant barrier, I decided to look for potential research labs in Spain and Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found professors in those countries by reading previous work that interested me, and asked my research advisor at Dartmouth if he could send an email introducing me to these professors - he knew many of the ones I wanted to work with, and even for the ones he didn&amp;rsquo;t know, a cold email from another respected professor in the field often has a much higher chance of being read than one from a random student. We contacted one professor at a time, and I soon hit it off with the lab in Spain that I ended up working at. Together, we brainstormed a project that I could talk about in my Fulbright application, and soon I was drafting my proposal - more on that in my next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #1</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 23:29:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written September 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first 11 posts in my &amp;ldquo;Neerja en España&amp;rdquo; series will be very lightly edited emails that I sent my friends while I was in Spain. Since a lot has changed since I wrote them, I&amp;rsquo;m adding retrospective comments in italics to the posts that I wrote while I was living through them. Here&amp;rsquo;s the first email I sent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summer after graduation flew by between cherished time at home, travels to Europe with family, and a trip to the East Coast with my best friend to visit some of our college friends who started work. Now I&amp;rsquo;m in Spain, which has already been crazy, but I first wanted to explain what the Fulbright actually is and what I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two broad kinds of Fulbright grants: the English teaching assistant grant (ETA), and the research/masters grant (which I am here on). For both grants, Fulbright pays us a stipend for living expenses and facilitates us getting a visa into Spain and setting us up. Spain has the second-largest Fulbright program, with over 150 ETAs and about 30 research/masters students. The ETAs are all placed in one of 6 regions of Spain where they are assigned a school and teach classes for about 20 hours a week. The research/masters students are all over Spain, since we got to choose our host institution as part of our project proposals. The majority of us are in Madrid or Barcelona, but there are a few like me who are in other cities, such as Seville, Salamanca, Granada, and Leon. After a few days orientation in Madrid, we all go to our respective cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m the only Fulbright student in my city, Zaragoza. Zaragoza is a medium sized city (~700K people), located right in between Madrid and Barcelona - it&amp;rsquo;s a little over an hour on the high speed AVE train to either city (&lt;em&gt;I ended up taking the AVE so many times, and loving it more and more each time)&lt;/em&gt;. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s smaller, it definitely has everything I need, and has a lot to explore, especially compared to Hanover. Also, apparently Zaragoza has the highest amount of bars/clubs per capita in all of Spain. Zaragoza is much less touristy than most other cities its size or bigger in Spain, which is really nice, since the cost of living is lower here and I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to actually immerse myself in Spanish culture. One of Zaragoza&amp;rsquo;s most famous attractions is the huge basilica - here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of it:&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-from-httpscommonswikimediaorgwikifileup_from_the_highest_tower_16079304178jpg&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/zgz_pilar.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;from https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Up_from_the_highest_tower_(16079304178).jpg&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerjathakkar.github.io/img/zgz_pilar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    from &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Up_from_the_highest_tower_(16079304178).jpg&#34;&gt;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Up_from_the_highest_tower_(16079304178).jpg&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty nervous to be the only one in my city, since I know literally no one here and don&amp;rsquo;t have an automatic cushion of American Fulbrighters to fall back on. I expect the first month or so to be a little rough. However, I think that it&amp;rsquo;ll overall be good for me, since I&amp;rsquo;ll hopefully form deeper friendships with people that are not American, which is important to me, and in the meantime I&amp;rsquo;m grateful FaceTime exists! &lt;em&gt;(I ended up befriending many non-Americans, and while I was apprehensive I am so grateful that I specifically ended up in Zaragoza)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my actual project, I will be doing research somewhere within the convex hull of graphics, vision, and computational photography. I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly sure what my project will be, but the lab I&amp;rsquo;ll be working in at Universidad de Zaragoza does a lot of very cool things, so I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get working! I&amp;rsquo;m not sure exactly what my schedule will be like, but I should be doing the same amount of work equivalent to a 9 to 5 job, working in the lab every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year is really going to be what I make of it, in every way. In terms of work, Fulbright doesn&amp;rsquo;t expect us to create any sort of final product with our research, as long as we are working on it consistently. So while publishing a paper would be nice, it&amp;rsquo;s in no way required. I definitely want to get great work done and learn more about my research interests and style, but aside from near deadlines, I don&amp;rsquo;t plan to work as intensely as I will be during my PhD. In terms of the rest of my life, I have a lot of freedom, and I definitely want to use this year in a lot of ways. When I studied abroad in Budapest, I was essentially an American tourist in Budapest and only made friends with other American students, and I absolutely don&amp;rsquo;t want this year to be a repeat of that. My top personal goals/to-dos include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve my Spanish (I&amp;rsquo;ve been pleasantly surprised at how decent it is, but I still have a ways to go in becoming totally fluent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve my cooking abilities and make my health a priority - sleep a lot and work out regularly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make non-American friends and expose myself to new perspectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel to a lot of places in Spain! I&amp;rsquo;m only allowed to leave the country for 21 days, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much to see just in Spain that I&amp;rsquo;ll still be able to travel a ton. I already have the Asturias, southern Spain and the Canary islands at the top of my list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m really happy that I ended up achieving all of these goals to a pretty good extent, except for the places I traveled to ended up being different - I very sadly did not make it to Asturias, Andalucia, or Las Canarias)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that answers some of the questions you guys have been asking me and gives you a sense of what I&amp;rsquo;ll be up to for the next year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello!</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 23:29:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for making your way to my blog! I am excited to see where this new adventure takes me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By way of introducing myself: I grew up in St. Paul, Minnesota with my parents and my little sister, Nitya. In middle school and high school, most of my time outside of school was spent practicing the violin, doing bharatanatyam (a form of Indian dance), and being a part of the math team. In 2015, I moved to Hanover, New Hampshire, to start at Dartmouth College. There, I discovered computer science and fell in love with both a new way of thinking and the potential to make an important impact. I continued violin in my college orchestra and had a lot of fun spending time in the outdoors, getting into hiking and climbing. I also became very involved with sexual violence prevention, eventually serving as a chair on the Student and Presidential Committee on Sexual Assault. I graduated with a double major in Computer Science and Mathematics, experiences both in academia and industry, and admission to the EECS PhD program at UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was excited to start my PhD, but decided to defer for a year. After graduation, I moved to Zaragoza, Spain for a Fulbright research scholarship. I spent the most incredible 6 months in Spain before I had to leave early and return home due to the pandemic. I&amp;rsquo;ve been staying busy at home finishing up my Fulbright research remotely, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make the most of this time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying photography, running, reading, cooking, and now starting this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been good about keeping a consistent journal for years, but when I was in Spain, I started writing more for other people. I sent semi-regular email updates to several friends and family about my adventures in Spain, and really enjoyed sharing what I was up to. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been asked by several people about the process of applying to Fulbright/grad school/scholarships, and I want to post information about that that is hopefully helpful to others, especially other women considering computer science. I have been incredibly fortunate to have so many wonderful mentors and access to resources at an elite institution, and I would love to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned with those who may not have as easy access to this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting lightly edited versions of the emails I sent to my friends (but I won&amp;rsquo;t omit things I have since changed my mind about - it&amp;rsquo;s been fun to reread them and see how things evolved) covering most of my Fulbright experience in Spain, several posts about research/grad school/applying to Fulbright, and other things that come across my mind. If there is anything you would like to hear about, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://neerja.me/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
