<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2020 | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerja.me/tag/2020/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerja.me/tag/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2020</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work by Neerja Thakkar is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
© Neerja Thakkar 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 13:00:25 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerja.me/images/icon_hu709051646b5c016a474294f302c76519_2025058_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>2020</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/tag/2020/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting My PhD, Remotely</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/starting_phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 13:00:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/starting_phd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you might have guessed from a sudden drop in my post frequency, as of about a month ago, I am officially a PhD student!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the pandemic, my program is fully remote, so I’m staying at home in Minnesota for the fall semester and doing everything online. Based on what I’ve heard from other students (and the Bay Area being subject to wildfires), I feel good about this decision - extra time with my family and not paying Berkeley rent prices is very nice. That being said, I really want to move to the west coast at some point in the foreseeable future, so fingers crossed for 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orientation was fully online, so it was definitely anticlimactic, but at the same time, it was exciting and more useful than I thought. It was good to see all of the PhD requirements clearly hashed out, have my questions answered, and learn about the resources available to grad students. I was able to see a clearer path for the next 5-6 years - previously, I had seen my PhD as a rather nebulous concept. Although there weren&amp;rsquo;t very many opportunities to meet people virtually at orientation, I was still able to get a sense of the other people in my cohort, and they all seem amazing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Classes started the next week, and I immediately got very busy between shopping classes and 1-on-1s with students (in addition to research). After debating between many courses, I decided to take Alyosha&amp;rsquo;s Intro to Computer Vision and Computational Photography class and Angjoo&amp;rsquo;s Learning for 3D Vision course. Alyosha&amp;rsquo;s class is mostly an undergraduate class with a small graduate section open, but since there was never a computer vision course offered at my undergrad institution, I decided to take it to fill in knowledge gaps and reinforce my understanding of foundational concepts in my field. Angjoo&amp;rsquo;s class is a graduate level seminar that consists of ~25 vision PhD students. We are reading a 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/berkeley.edu/cs294-173/schedule?authuser=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;fantastic set of papers&lt;/a&gt; and every class involves student presentations and discussions of the papers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to lie, starting a PhD remotely has been pretty bizarre. On one hand, I’m absolutely stoked to be attending this amazing institution. I’ve learned so much in just two weeks from conversations with professors and my new peers. Learning about the innovations that the faculty have made in their fields always astounds me. But on the other hand, doing a PhD remotely feels very isolating. I’ve met a lot of people, but it’s been through having to actively reach out to people and schedule a time to talk, as opposed to just bumping into them on campus or meeting for a coffee. Spontaneous interaction and lunches/coffee every day helped me bond with my labmates in Spain, and it feels like one week in Spain is going to equal one semester of getting to know everyone at Berkeley. It&amp;rsquo;s unfortunate that the first year or so of my PhD will have to be like this, but I&amp;rsquo;m definitely staying positive, appreciating what I&amp;rsquo;m learning, and excited to meet my very intelligent and inspiring peers in person at some point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of what this means for the blog: Over the summer, I was able to get to many posts that I wanted to. If there’s something else you wanted advice on that I haven’t covered, definitely reach out, since I want to keep on writing. I’m hoping to write about my PhD - classes I’m taking, research I’m doing, events I’m attending and life in general (which will probably be significantly more interesting post-pandemic). Posts will definitely become much less frequent, but I love writing in my free time, and I’m excited to see how this blog will evolve!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #16: Reflections on My Time in Spain</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_16/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 2020 13:00:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_16/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe that exactly one year ago I landed in Madrid for my Fulbright orientation! So much has happened in the past year, and as cliche as it sounds, I feel like a pretty different person now than I was then. This post will shine a little light on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny because at the time I was leaving for Spain, I didn&amp;rsquo;t actually want to go. When I found out that I got the Fulbright, part of me was really excited and honored, but another part of me was hoping to just stay in the US with my friends and family. My Spanish was rusty and after spending the past 4 years in Hanover, New Hampshire, I felt very comfortable with my college friends, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to move somewhere where I knew literally no one. But a few weeks into being in Spain, that feeling started to turn around, and now I am grateful in so many ways that I had the opportunity I did to live in Zaragoza for 6 months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my reflections from my Fulbright year on a bunch of different facets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Spain and cultural differences&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few things about adjusting to life in Spain were particularly stressful. Spanish bureaucracy is a nightmare to deal with, especially when your Spanish is far from perfect. Getting my &lt;em&gt;empadonamiento&lt;/em&gt; and TIE took way too long and far too much effort. Spanish food culture largely revolves around eating meat, so being vegetarian was difficult when eating at a lot of Spanish restaurants, especially with the addition of my nut allergy. The Spanish schedule is very different, and while I largely ignored the traditional schedule and worked a more regular 9-5, whenever I wanted to go out to eat with friends dinner was at 9 or later, and &amp;ldquo;going out&amp;rdquo; meant it was difficult to be home before 5 am. The sun rising absurdly late also never sat sit right with me. On the bright side, I was forced to improve my cooking skills, and I discovered some foods in Spain that I really loved - Spain does mushrooms &lt;strong&gt;so&lt;/strong&gt; well. And paella is always at least pretty good. Wow, 6 months out, I actually miss some Spanish food, even though when I was in Spain I craved all the food I eat in America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there were some frustrations, life in Spain was mostly positive and mind-expanding! In general, I felt much less stressed in Spain, compared to undergrad. While a significant part of this had to do with not having schoolwork, it was also also in large part due to being in Spain in particular. People aren&amp;rsquo;t in a rush in Spain. They wait for other people, and want to enjoy life and make lots of time for their friends and family. Although many of my friends in Spain were a bit older than my friends back in America, it was still interesting to note that a much larger portion of my Spanish friends were in committed relationships. It just seems like people in Spain value friends and family over themselves much more. In fact, I told some of my Spanish friends that it seemed like young people here more wanted to invest in relationships, while young people in America wanted to prioritize themselves, and they told me that just the notion of &amp;ldquo;investing&amp;rdquo; in someone else is so American and representative of the capitalism engrained in our society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking of capitalism, I really appreciated the fact that in Spain, people have accepted that a place to live and healthcare and education should be human rights. It&amp;rsquo;s the norm in Spain, and many other parts in the world, to not pay exorbitant amounts of money for college or healthcare. College at the most expensive private university in Spain is under 10,000 euros a year, and on financial aid college can often be completely free and come with a stipend generous enough to cover rent, food and books. The simple fact that Spanish people don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about healthcare or college expenses really changes people&amp;rsquo;s relationships with money, and the lack of obsession with money in Spain was very refreshing after coming from a undergrad instution where many people wanted to go work on Wall Street. In Spain, it’s completely normal for businessmen to be friends with janitors or software engineers to be friends with nail salon workers, and I loved the replacement of social stratification/classism with a general appreciation for humanity. The fact that beer is a euro on average makes going out to bars accessible to everyone, which also makes it easier for software engineers and nail salon workers to get a drink together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On new friends&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My lab was incredible. It was really nice to make some Spanish friends in Spain (which sounds weird, but meeting international people was so much easier than meeting Spainards), and I loved going to work every day and seeing my lab friends. Work was very social, since we ate lunch and took coffee breaks together every day, and also hung out on weekends or juepincho nights occasionally, and as a result I got pretty close to them. I talked the most to 3 of the guys in my building, and a lot of our conversations involved us just joking around and correcting each other&amp;rsquo;s Spanish/English (but half of the time when I corrected their English because something was phrased awkwardly they said &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s British&amp;rdquo;), but I also gained so much from learning about their culture and approach to life and work. As a bonus, since we&amp;rsquo;re in the same field, I know with pretty high probability that I&amp;rsquo;ll see them for many more years at conferences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outside of the lab, I met a lot of international people in Zaragoza, through the &lt;em&gt;auxiliares&lt;/em&gt; program (English teaching assistants funded by the Spanish government), my roommates, and through Aiko&amp;rsquo;s Spanish class. I enjoyed meeting so many different people and just seeing how many things there are to do with your life besides the paths Dartmouth students often choose. These people were from all walks of life and have gone on such cool journeys that led them to Spain, and I had a lot of fun adventures with these friends and loved getting out of the Dartmouth/research lab bubble. Just our converstaions were so different - in America, people would always start by asking me where I went to school or what I was doing professionaly, whereas here, people would start by asking me where I was from, what I thought of Spain, and other questions that felt more personal in a good way. Being around people very different from me gave me a new perspective on my own life path and decisions that I am so appreciative of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, my Fulbright friends are amazing and truly some of the most incredible people I have ever met. I went from being overwhelmed by what felt like networking at orientation to making incredibly genuine friendships with them. We had a blast exploring Spain and going to bars together, and also had wonderful deep and intellectual conversations. Everyone I met through Fulbright is so passionate, caring, kind, and doing awesome things. I&amp;rsquo;m still closely in touch with so many of my fellow Fulbrighters and I absolutely cherish those friendships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having a global network of friends now is amazing, though slightly painful when you&amp;rsquo;re in the country that&amp;rsquo;s handling a pandemic the worst, while your friend in New Zealand has been living a pandemic-free life for months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On research and academic/professional benefits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There have been so many of these! While I had a wonderful time traveling and exploring and socializing, I also got some good work done, and here&amp;rsquo;s what came out of it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I made wonderful connections with the lab in Spain that I had the privilege to work at. Since academia is really small, I am definitely expecting to run into them at conferences in the future, or maybe continue collaborations as I see how my research interests evolve. I still WhatsApp my labmates with random research questions, or about the tapas bars we&amp;rsquo;ll go to when I come back to Spain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I feel more prepared for my PhD. I got better at reading papers and synthesizing important points from them, and I had time to take online courses and read up on things I need to learn. I also learned how to swap out the GPU in a desktop which is a useful skill!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focusing primarily on advanced research in a new area showed me how much knowledge exists that I don&amp;rsquo;t have yet. However, I think that realizing you have a lot to learn is an important part of the PhD process, and learning about the gaps in my knowledge meant that I could start filling them, which I did!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I got to do research in a completely different lab and country from undergrad, so now when I go to Berkeley I won&amp;rsquo;t see the way things are done at Berkeley as the only way to do things. It was generally great to get a different perspective on my field&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immersing myself in research full-time made the frustrations of research much more clear. When you&amp;rsquo;re doing research, you can spend days or weeks or months on an approach that ultimately pans out to nothing. While I had experienced this in college and knew it was a part of research, doing full time research made the extent of frustration I can feel that much clearer, but recognizing this also strengthened my ability to cope with it and showed me what to expect during my PhD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While I respect all research and can recognize scientific merit, I realized that I care most about research that has an immediate societal impact (espcially when I got to attend the FAT* conference), which helped me hone my research interests&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On Personal Growth&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve definitely became more independent and comfortable with new situations, as comes with moving to a foreign country. One surprise was actually realizing that I love alone time. Before, I always thought I was extroverted, but now I think I’m  equally introverted and extroverted. My alone time in Spain was a nice mix between relaxing and intentional time, where I thought about my goals and journaled. I also adored just walking around different Spanish cities and getting lost in my thoughts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely got a lot better at meeting new people and figuring out how to navigate cocktail parties or house parties where I know almost no one - I was shy before, but I actually started to enjoy those situations and always getting to know more people. Before Spain, I would often make close friends and then have fun experiences with them, but in Spain I had a lot of fun experiences with near strangers, a decent amount of who then became good friends. Now, it’s a bummer to not be able to go out and make new friends, but after the pandemic ends I’m very excited to do so again!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was really happy with the fitness progress I was able to make in Spain. I wanted to start running for a while, but when I got to Zaragoza, I could barely run for 5 minutes. I was able to get to the point where I could run 3 straight miles, and was inspired by some of my Fulbright friends to run a 10K in the spring. I had started training when I had to go home, and it became clear that no races would be happening anywhere for a while, but it’s still great to have gotten to a point where I know I can run a race when it’s safe to again. Overall, I feel much healthier in general - it was really nice to take care of myself and actually prioritize my health, which I hope I can continue doing for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just felt (and still feel) so much healthier in every way - it was great to learn how to take care of myself, prioritize my physical and mental health, and learn how to relax. Spanish culture was exactly what I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, my Fulbright year (or I guess 6 months), was incredible. When I studied abroad during my junior year in Budapest, I only talked to other Americans and acted like a tourist the whole time. I knew that I did Budapest wrong, and I was ready to do Spain right. I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo; looked like, but I went to Spain with an attitude of opennes and spirit ready for adventure, and now looking back, my 6 months were so much more fulfilling than I ever thought my whole 9 month grant could be! I am excited to return to Spain and see my friends, but I also want to approach the rest of my life with the attitudes I honed in Spain and see where my next adventures take me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #15: Remote Fulbright</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 13:00:25 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_15/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s crazy that it&amp;rsquo;s been almost 6 months since I was in Spain! In this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about what finishing up a Fulbright remotely was like. My next and final post in this series will reflect on the academic/professional side of my time in Spain and the personal side of my thoughts on my Fulbright year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I got back to the US, everything still felt so chaotic. Many people were very unhappy with the way that Fulbright had handled the pandemic and that we were sent home to a country with an inferior healthcare system. I think that the Fulbright Spain Comission did a wonderful job dealing with a completely unprecedented situation, but that the US goverment&amp;rsquo;s lack of leadership/direction made things really crazy and bad for many people. It&amp;rsquo;s also absolutely horrible that many Fulbrighters lost their health insurance abroad and had to come back to the US uninsured in the middle of a &lt;em&gt;pandemic&lt;/em&gt;, but that is completely the fault of American values and our current administration. After some pressure from Fulbrighters, the Fulbright program did provide reimbursements for all of the travel back and a little extra money to aid the sudden transition back. I was extremely lucky to be able to come back to Minnesota and life with my family, and I won&amp;rsquo;t get into my feelings on this chaos too much more, but you can read some of my friends&amp;rsquo; very well-articulated thoughts 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.baltimoresun.com/opinion/op-ed/bs-ed-op-0320-coronavirus-spain-20200319-ssm2ppsfhvhopmwns22ciwxusm-story.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tennessean.com/story/opinion/2020/03/23/coronavirus-tennessee-native-fulbright-scholar-barcelona/2898350001/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The month of March felt a bit rough between watching the world fall apart, mourning the loss of my time in Spain, and remembering how cold Minnesota is until the end of April. However, as spring started to appear (the second spring of the year for me, actually), I realized that a lot of good things were happening. I had been really burnt out after college, and had regained some of my energy the previous summer, but after a few weeks at home I started to feel extremely energized and ready to take on all sorts of new personal and research-related projects again (like starting this blog, and you can read about some other things I did during this time 
&lt;a href=&#34;%28https://neerja.me/post/how-im-spending-quarantine/%29&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;). I felt deeply re-invested in research and learning, which has been wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also felt extremely connected to other people. There were so many college friends and friends from back home that it had been hard to stay in touch with, between traveling all the time and time zone differences, but now I was able to talk to them more often. I also have stayed in contact with many friends in Spain and friends I made in Spain who returned home to other places, like New Zealand, and it&amp;rsquo;s been really fun and interesting to talk to friends all over the world during a global situation such as this one. It was additionally wonderful to have more time with family than I had ever thought I would at once (I honestly don&amp;rsquo;t understand why American culture takes so much pride in independence and moving away from family).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s also ironic that in leaving my Fulbright program early, I got much closer to many Fulbright friends than I had ever anticipated. Going through the same crazy situation was a great way to bond, and we filled the strange time with game nights and lots of Zoom calls. We even had a virtual Research + Masters journal club a few times, which was really successful and interesting. Overall, I so value my friendships with the other Fulbrighters. A few close friends of mine have also been starting their PhDs/med school right now, and it&amp;rsquo;s been lovely to have good friends who understand the crazy situation I&amp;rsquo;m going through right now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Actually finishing my Fulbright remotely was definitely a very different experience from being in-person. The time difference was significant, and it is completely different to meet once a week over a call than to be in a physical place for ~40 hours a week. So much of the benefit that I got from being at my lab in Spain came through the chats that we had over lunch/coffee breaks, learning from my labmates, getting to go to group meetings, and generally being in a new environment. Going to another country is really about the place, culture, and people, and unfortunately so much cannot be replicated over a computer screen. Of course, staying in Spain and being confined to my apartment wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have fixed any of this, and I&amp;rsquo;m very happy that I was able to return home and spend time with family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fulbright end of year event (over Zoom, of course), was not the weekend of celebration in Madrid that I thought it would be, but nevertheless it was still a fun time. It was fun to see people&amp;rsquo;s faces, and hear recaps of different groups&amp;rsquo; times in Spain. I was also extremely honored to have been voted for two different superlatives - Most Growth from Orientation to Mid-Year (I guess not that hard when you&amp;rsquo;re fresh off a plane and very disoriented when you first meet people), and Best Instagram Documentation (I do love to capture fun moments).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While having to finish up a Fulbright remotely was not what I expected, the 6 months that I did have in Spain were so extremely fulfilling and honestly far exceeded my expectations, so I have absolutely nothing but gratitude for the opportunity and everyone that made my experience what it was!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #14: Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I had discussed in my previous post, the coronavirus was getting progressively worse in Spain. Once Trump made his announcement, I decided to make the most of my remaining time. I am not a spontaneous person, but knowing that I probably at least had 48 hours left in Spain, I decided I was going to go to Barcelona. I booked a train ticket, threw some clothes and toiletries into a bag, and headed to the train station. Train rides were always a fun and special experience for me &amp;mdash; I loved putting on some music and writing in my journal, or just enjoying the beautiful view of the Spanish countryside. But on this train ride, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even put on music. I just stared at some news on my phone and tried to process Spain falling apart (this was a little before it was clear that the entire world was falling apart and the implications of the pandemic were much more dire than just cancelled foreign study programs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got off the train and took the familiar walk through &lt;em&gt;Estacion Sants&lt;/em&gt; and into the metro, and eventually stepped out onto &lt;em&gt;La Rambla&lt;/em&gt; and walked a block through the beautiful Gothic Quarter to get to my friend Anna&amp;rsquo;s place. She opened the door to her apartment and we gave each other a hug (this was before we really understood the concept of social distancing) and the relief I felt was immediate. It was lovely to finally be with someone who understood my position of likely being forced to leave Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ventured out to a bar Anna wanted to show me. It was magical - I was transported to a forest. Next, we went to my favorite bar in Barcelona (and in the world), a classy place that makes custom cocktails that always end up being the best cocktail I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had, and all seven or so friends I&amp;rsquo;ve taken there agree. Then it was time to meet up with the rest of the Barca gang. We first went to a noodle/dumpling bar, and then we went to another place with empañadas. It was incredible to see everyone - the level of comfort that I felt being surrounded by them after a crazy week was unreal. Audrey proclaimed that she was in denial, but she knew we were all going to be sent home. Apparently the ECA (the branch of the government that runs Fulbright) had said that all exchange programs would have a 60 day pause. We had 90 days left, so this was so clearly the end.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-one-last-sangria-in-an-ethereal-cozy-bar&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/forest_bar.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;One last sangria in an ethereal, cozy bar&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/forest_bar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    One last sangria in an ethereal, cozy bar
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, we had a busy day ahead of us. Anna had a list of places she wanted to see in Barcelona before she left - mostly various museums - and we were going to make some progress on it. The day had a surreal energy. I knew that our time here was so limited, by days, maybe even hours. It was crazy and terrifying to watch the world fall apart in ways that I had never imagined, but also a beautiful reminder about how special life is, and how much of a gift it was to be half a world away from everything I had known and held familiar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-places-in-barcelona-that-were-now-familiar-felt-extra-remarkable-and-magical-like-this-plaza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_plaza.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Places in Barcelona that were now familiar felt extra remarkable and magical, like this plaza&amp;hellip;&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_plaza.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Places in Barcelona that were now familiar felt extra remarkable and magical, like this plaza&amp;hellip;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-or-the-hallowed-walls-of-the-gothic-quarter-fun-fact-theres-a-skull-on-the-underside-of-the-pont-del-bisbe&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/gothic_walls.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;&amp;hellip;or the hallowed walls of the Gothic Quarter. Fun fact: there&amp;rsquo;s a skull on the underside of the pont del bisbe&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/gothic_walls.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &amp;hellip;or the hallowed walls of the Gothic Quarter. Fun fact: there&amp;rsquo;s a skull on the underside of the &lt;em&gt;pont del bisbe&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started the day off with me finally visiting the famous Boqueria market. Then we got brunch with Audrey and a college friend of hers who had just arrived in Barcelona as part of world travel on a Watson fellowship. The meal was wonderful - I had been looking for real American-esque brunch food in Spain the entire time I was there and I had finally found it.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-it-only-took-me-5-trips-to-barcelona-to-go-to-one-of-the-biggest-tourist-attractions&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/boqueria.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;It only took me 5 trips to Barcelona to go to one of the biggest tourist attractions&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/boqueria.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    It only took me 5 trips to Barcelona to go to one of the biggest tourist attractions
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-brunch-with-audrey-and-anna-3&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_brunch.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Brunch with Audrey and Anna &amp;lt;3&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_brunch.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Brunch with Audrey and Anna &amp;lt;3
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, Audrey peeled off, and Anna, our new friend, and I took the scenic route through the Gothic quarter and up to Montjuic. Of course, we were talking about how we would probably all have to leave soon. And then, just as we got to the top and started to take in the beautiful view of the city, Anna got an email. What we had all been dreading was here. Her undergrad institution&amp;rsquo;s Fulbright coordinator told us that we were all going to be sent home and should start booking flights. I stood in silence as Anna talked to her family on the phone, and tried to process this news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, I got an email too, sent to all grantees. Spain was now CDC level 3, and we were encouraged to return to the US within the next week. I read the information about closing our bank accounts, how stipend payments would work, and getting a plane ticket, and tried to process this - it felt unreal, even though I knew it had been coming. After Anna and I absorbed this, we tried to go to the Joan Miro museum, but it was closed. The city was shutting down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening, we all gathered at a soccer field near Montjuic with drinks and chocolate and watched the sun set on our Fulbright. We passed sheets of paper around and wrote notes to each other under a one minute time limit. When I got my sheet back, I was amazed at the depth of things that my friends wrote about me, despite me seeing most of them only about 5 times total over the 6 months I had known them. It hit me that I had been a part of and helped create something so special between all of us, and I was so excited to continue building those bonds and enjoying Spain (the castle in Girona that we were all planning to stay at in April really epitomized that), but now it was all just going to end. Later, the pandemic got much worse in America and all of the horrible economic and personal impacts for so many people became clear, but at the time, it just felt like we were being sent home.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-my-friend-sasha-and-i-at-the-soccer-field-overlooking-the-city&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/sasha.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;My friend Sasha and I at the soccer field overlooking the city&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/sasha.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    My friend Sasha and I at the soccer field overlooking the city
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-barca-gangs-last-in-person-rendezvous&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_montjuic.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The Barca gang&amp;rsquo;s last in-person rendezvous&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_montjuic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The Barca gang&amp;rsquo;s last in-person rendezvous
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, Anna, our friend Akshay, and I got brunch; the restaurant was already closed for eating and only open for takeout. We sat in Placa de la Universitat - one of the first places I had ever been to in Barcelona, since my sister and I stayed in a hotel near the university my first time in the city. We sat on a bench and I tried to just enjoy looking at the city and talking to my friends, knowing that this would be one of my last moments of peace before I had to pack up my apartment and deal with a million things. I headed to the train station and bought one last ticket to Zaragoza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got home and tried to contemplate having to pack up my entire apartment in the next 2 days. My flatmates were excited - apparently the president was going to address the country in the evening. As I started packing, messages were flying in every WhatsApp group. Everyone was really confused, and debating whether they should say in Spain or leave. They were angry at the lack of clear guidance on exactly what we needed to do from Fulbright, since the email just &amp;ldquo;strongly recommended&amp;rdquo; that we leave. I personally thought that the Comission was very responsive and helpful during this crazy crisis, but the fault was with the US government for having a lack of a clear plan and leadership at the top, which then trickled down to be confusing for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was definitely conflicted, but I also knew that my family really wanted me to come home, and being with them during this crazy time didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like the worst idea. It also seemed like flights were getting cancelled left and right, so we all had to try to get out of Spain ASAP. My flight was booked for Tuesday originally, but it got cancelled, so I moved to a Monday flight and gave myself less than 24 hours to pack up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening, the president of Spain spoke to the country. He announced that Spain was going to enter a strict lockdown, that people would only be allowed to leave their apartments to get groceries, go to the pharmacy, or go to the doctor. All of a sudden, everyone in Spain started taking the virus really seriously. My flatmates and labmates realized that the virus could spiral out of control and that they needed to listen to their leaders - what a contrast to how Americans responded to the virus. On the bright side, the lockdown meant that Spain somewhat got a handle on the virus. Also, the prospect of spending a lot of the next 3 months in my apartment in Spain made leaving a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day or so was a whirlwind of packing everything up, realizing it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even fit into the 4 suitcases/duffle bags I had, my labmate Julio saving me by both letting me store a few things at his house indefinitely and driving me to the train station, making it back to Barcelona, and hauling my luggage around until I was at the baggage drop and then Delta agent was merciful with extra baggage for the first time in my memory. I very cautiously got on the plane, feeling aware of my proximity to others in a way that I&amp;rsquo;m now familiar with. I was sitting next to a guy who had been studying abroad in Barcelona and had to leave early, a relatable mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screening when I landed on U.S. soil was very lax. They took my temperature, but did no other checks, and I doubt they would have done anything except encourage me to quarantine for 14 days if I did have one. I had low expectations of how America would handle the pandemic, but this was an early indication that it would be even worse. That being said, the gratitude and relief I felt when I saw my family and got home was immense. I missed Spain immediately, but I felt so lucky to have a loving home to return to, to still be on my parents&amp;rsquo; health insurance, and to have my supportive family and wonderful friends to process this unprecedented situation with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #13: My Last Weeks in Spain</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shortly after I drafted my post about mid-year, I had to leave Spain due to the pandemic. From here on out, all of my Spain posts are retrospective. In this one, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about my last couple of weeks in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to the end of February in Zaragoza (which truly feels like another lifetime), I was having a wonderful time. I guess spring comes early in Spain - the weather in Zaragoza was getting warmer, and cherry blossoms were blooming.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-this-photo-was-taken-on-february-11th-right-outside-of-my-apartmentspring-comes-much-earlier-in-spain&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz_flowers.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;This photo was taken on February 11th right outside of my apartment&amp;hellip;spring comes much earlier in Spain&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz_flowers.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    This photo was taken on February 11th right outside of my apartment&amp;hellip;spring comes much earlier in Spain
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally felt at home in my lab and was getting closer every day with my labmates. Miguel was gone from the lab due to a broken leg, but everyone else was still around. Work days consisted of learning lots of new things (and even changing GPUs in computers and some other basic hardware stuff, with the help of labmates), long lunches and lots of coffee breaks (we had a conversation about how to improve lab dynamics given that we were split up into two separate buildings, and the solution was to drink more coffee in the two buildings, resulting in about 3 coffee breaks every day), and frequent trips to the vending machine with Manu and Adrian. Some other fond memories from my last couple of weeks: a lovely, long chat on a Friday afternoon with Johanna, a postdoc from France, about work life balance in academia, and getting a new fancy coffee machine in the lab. Also, going out with Adrian and a bunch of his Spanish friends on a Thursday night and experiencing &lt;em&gt;machacados&lt;/em&gt; (shots of a mixed drink that you cover with a plastic lid and all simultaneously slam on to the bar, hard - success involves breaking a glass - before drinking).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weekends consisted of sunny afternoons, failed hikes and crazy nights with my &lt;em&gt;auxiliares&lt;/em&gt; friends, a trip to the &lt;em&gt;pueblo&lt;/em&gt; of a labmate for a 7 hour lunch (that is not an exaggeration, and this is the norm for &amp;ldquo;lunch&amp;rdquo; at someones home), and more time spent with Aiko and Aparna&amp;rsquo;s class. As you read about in my last post, I had a lot of plans for the rest of my time in Spain, which I was looking forward to. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until early March that I started to suspect that maybe those plans wouldn&amp;rsquo;t happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of my Fulbright friends had promised to come visit. In particular, Ash and Libby were planning to come from Madrid. We were debating between the second and third weekends of March, and thankfully they decided to come on the second weekend, otherwise they would not have made it before the pandemic hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a wonderful time. I took them to my favorite tapas bars and restaurants in Zaragoza and went to some museums I had wanted to go to for a while but was saving/procrastinating going to. A fun fact I learned in the Roman Forum museum - Zaragoza used to be a Roman city called Caesar Agusto. Then, they dropped the &amp;ldquo;cae&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;sar agusto&amp;rdquo; became &amp;ldquo;Zaragoza&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zaragoza-is-famous-for-being-windy-my-friends-really-got-to-experience-that&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/windy_zgz.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Zaragoza is famous for being windy. My friends really got to experience that!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/windy_zgz.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Zaragoza is famous for being windy. My friends really got to experience that!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;




  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-interior-of-the-aljaferia-palace-in-zaragoza-which-inspired-the-famous-alahambra-and-is-truly-stunning&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_wall.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The interior of the Aljaferia palace in Zaragoza, which inspired the famous Alahambra and is truly stunning&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_wall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The interior of the &lt;em&gt;Aljaferia&lt;/em&gt; palace in Zaragoza, which inspired the famous &lt;em&gt;Alahambra&lt;/em&gt; and is truly stunning
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-loved-these-doorways&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_friends.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;We loved these doorways&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_friends.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We loved these doorways
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-i-am-so-nostalgic-for-the-details-of-spanish-architecture-like-these-beautiful-ceilings&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_ceiling.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;I am so nostalgic for the details of Spanish architecture, like these beautiful ceilings&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_ceiling.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    I am so nostalgic for the details of Spanish architecture, like these beautiful ceilings
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really appreciated my city and loved showing my friends around. It&amp;rsquo;s so good I got that they came when they did, because I definitely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have gone to Aljaferia again or hit all of my favorite tapas bars one last time!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-taking-my-friends-to-eat-my-favorite-champi-tapa&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/champi.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Taking my friends to eat my favorite champi tapa&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/champi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Taking my friends to eat my favorite &lt;em&gt;champi&lt;/em&gt; tapa
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-a-dinner-we-made-out-of-tapas-at-a-place-that-specialized-in-cheese---pan-con-tomate-truffled-manchego-artichokes-in-cheese-and-migas-or-breadcrumbs-a-dish-very-typical-to-zaragoza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/tapas.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;A dinner we made out of tapas at a place that specialized in cheese - pan con tomate, truffled manchego, artichokes in cheese, and migas, or breadcrumbs, a dish very typical to Zaragoza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/tapas.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    A dinner we made out of tapas at a place that specialized in cheese - &lt;em&gt;pan con tomate&lt;/em&gt;, truffled &lt;em&gt;manchego&lt;/em&gt;, artichokes in cheese, and &lt;em&gt;migas&lt;/em&gt;, or breadcrumbs, a dish very typical to Zaragoza
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-i-really-wanted-to-see-this-view-from-the-tower-of-the-basilica-photo-generously-provided-by-my-friend-shani-and-show-it-to-my-friends-but-sadly-it-was-closed-that-weekend----one-of-so-many-reasons-i-have-to-go-back-to-spain&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/pilar_tower_view.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;I really wanted to see this view from the tower of the Basilica (photo generously provided by my friend Shani) and show it to my friends, but sadly it was closed that weekend -  one of so many reasons I have to go back to Spain!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/pilar_tower_view.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    I really wanted to see this view from the tower of the Basilica (photo generously provided by my friend Shani) and show it to my friends, but sadly it was closed that weekend -  one of so many reasons I have to go back to Spain!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-i-was-able-to-take-them-inside-the-basilica---this-is-its-ceiling&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/pilar_ceiling.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;I was able to take them inside the Basilica - this is its ceiling&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/pilar_ceiling.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    I was able to take them inside the Basilica - this is its ceiling
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zaragoza-is-so-stunningim-really-happy-i-was-able-to-rediscover-it-with-my-friends-and-appreciate-it-one-last-time&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz%3c3.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Zaragoza is so stunning&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m really happy I was able to rediscover it with my friends and appreciate it one last time&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz%3c3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Zaragoza is so stunning&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m really happy I was able to rediscover it with my friends and appreciate it one last time
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That weekend felt like a very distinct point in which life went from pre pandemic to pandemic. I had talked about coronavirus with my lab mates, but they laughed at me for wanting to buy a mask to wear, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a main conversation point. But Ash and Libby and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop talking about coronavirus - would it become a pandemic? Would it spread to America? Would Fulbright let us stay here? Ash is brilliant - she had just gotten into Harvard med school and she&amp;rsquo;s very interested in epedimiology, so she was the perfect person to talk to about this (and still my go to person for covid-related questions, months later).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-spent-our-last-hour-together-hanging-out-in-the-park-by-my-house&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/park_hanging.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;We spent our last hour together hanging out in the park by my house&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/park_hanging.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We spent our last hour together hanging out in the park by my house
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zaragoza-spring--ash-was-such-a-good-aesthetic&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/park_flower_aesthetic.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Zaragoza spring &amp;#43; Ash was such a good aesthetic&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/park_flower_aesthetic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Zaragoza spring + Ash was such a good aesthetic
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there was a nagging feeling about coronavirus, we still had a lovely time, but as soon as Ash and Libby left, things went downhill. On Monday at the lab I kept on refreshing the Spain coronavirus map and watched the numbers in Madrid triple in a single day. I started to have a sinking feeling as I faced the reality that I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be allowed to stay. That evening, I went with my labmates to &lt;em&gt;cien montaditos&lt;/em&gt; (a chain in Spain) for sandwiches and beer. They made fun of me for my paranoia about the virus and fears about having to leave, and even for washing my hands before the food came! Clearly, they didn&amp;rsquo;t think coronavirus was anything to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week kept on devolving into more confusion and anxiety. Things were very bad in Italy, so I asked the Comission what happened to grantees over there, and they told me that Fulbright Italy was cancelled, and that depending on the region everyone was either encouraged to go home or Fulbright was cancelled and they were required to leave. With Spain quickly devolving into the next Northern Italy, it felt like things were getting worse and worse, but the Department of State wasn&amp;rsquo;t updating Spain&amp;rsquo;s travel advisory level (which would mean we had to leave), and Fulbright wasn&amp;rsquo;t telling us anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t focus on work at all - I was consumed with wondering if we were going to get sent home, if the program would let us stay, if the numbers in Spain would continue to go up like crazy. It felt like I spent all day WhatsApping my Fulbright friends, trying to figure out what was going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had booked a trip to visit a friend in Asturias for that weekend, which would require me to travel to Barcelona on Thursday, and I had no clue if it was safe or reasonable to go or not. On Wednesday night, I woke up at 4:30 am, and saw a bunch of WhatsApp messages and texts from my family. Trump had said that Americans had 48 hours to come back to the country, and Fulbright still hadn&amp;rsquo;t told us anything. I woke up again a few hours later, and Fulbright still hadn&amp;rsquo;t said a word, and I had many more text messages. I&amp;rsquo;m not a spontaneous person normally, but I felt like I needed to be with my friends. So I booked a train ticket to Barcelona, packed enough clothes to suffice for a few days, and left my apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #12: Mid-Year</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written March 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mid-February, Fulbright gathered all of the grantees in Murcia, Spain for 3 days of workshops, presentations, conversations, and festivities. These few days ended up being a huge highlight of my time in Spain so far! &lt;em&gt;(Now I  see them as by far some of the best of 2020&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s crazy that they happened in the same year as today.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before mid-year, I told my labmates that I was going to Murcia, and they were shocked that I was willingly going there. They kept on telling me that Murcia is the worst place in Spain, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing in Murcia, and that even the people there are not great. While I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay too much attention to the Spanish perception of the city, my expectations for Murcia were not high - little did I know that every part of mid-year, even the location, would be wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey to mid-year itself was a fun adventure. I got on the AVE from Zaragoza to Madrid Atocha (Puerta de Atocha is a major train station in Madrid). As soon as I stepped off of the train, I saw one of my friends, a Fulbright Master&amp;rsquo;s candidate in Salamanca, and my orientation roommate. The train to Murcia that most of Fulbright was taking wasn&amp;rsquo;t leaving for a couple of hours, so we had time to buy some food. We walked into a cafe in Atocha and immediately saw a group of people that somehow struck us as American (though them all being about our age helped too), and it turns out they were all ETAs in La Rioja. We had a great time meeting them and learning about how their grant had been going. Soon enough it was time to go to the meeting point, so we headed down to the main level of Atocha. I was immediately overwhelmed with excitement at seeing all my Fulbright friends - the ones I had seen just a couple of weeks ago in Barcelona, but also ones from Madrid and other places. We all made our way to the platform, and it was crazy with about 150 excited Fulbrighters all catching up with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was assigned a seat on the train next to a friend, and two other friends were right in front of us, so we had a great time chatting and watching the scenery. The train ride soon turned into me walking around our train car to talk to everyone I knew, making new friends in the car, and then venturing with a friend into the cafe car. I was shook when I walked into this car and it was literally just a full on mobile bar. Within moments of walking in someone offered me some wine, and I easily spent an hour of the train ride sipping &lt;em&gt;rioja&lt;/em&gt;, talking (well, shouting) to friends new and old, and watching the beautiful landscape of Spain change as we traveled South. (&lt;em&gt;The specific thought of drinking rioja on a train is making me so incredibly nostalgic for Spain).&lt;/em&gt; And then all of a sudden we were in Murcia!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-main-cathedral-of-murcia&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/murcia_cathedral.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The main cathedral of Murcia&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/murcia_cathedral.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The main cathedral of Murcia
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-year itself was a wonderful whirlwind with very little sleep but a lot of fun. In format, it was very similar to orientation and the research seminar. It consisted of presentations, workshops, cocktail parties, exploring the city we were in (Murcia may be unimpressive by Spanish standards, but as an American I was pleasantly surprised), and lots of time to socialize. While the Fulbright name tags and printed out schedules were similar to orientation, the feeling was completely different. Before, meeting people and talking to them felt like awkward networking. Now, it felt fun and relaxed, but also exciting. I enjoyed conversations with people that now felt like friends, where we got to share our experiences, talk about our research, and get to know each other better. Before, the presentations were endless information coming from the Commission, but now they were talks from my friends about their work. Before, the cocktail parties felt exhausting, but now they were a really fun chance to see everyone and enjoy free unlimited wine.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-university-where-mid-year-took-place&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/universidad_murcia.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The university where mid-year took place&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/universidad_murcia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The university where mid-year took place
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other Fulbrighters, especially the researchers (who I spent the most time with), definitely made mid-year what it was -  I am absolutely blessed to be among these incredible people. They are so cool, deeply passionate and intelligent people with really interesting life stories and experiences. We have a lot of respect for each other intellectually and an understanding of each others desires to dive deeply into our disciplines, but also a lot of love for each other, and so much fun together going to bars/clubs until way too late or exploring new cities. Honestly, while I made a lot of incredible friends at Dartmouth, I was disappointed by how many students were only there to spend time in their Greek house before getting a job on Wall Street. Finding my people at Dartmouth took some time, whereas out of the group of about 30 researchers/master&amp;rsquo;s students here, I genuinely liked and had fun and even enlightening conversations with every one of them. &lt;em&gt;(I was video chatting with a couple of Fulbright friends yesterday and we were talking about how cool it is that we are all starting grad/med school in the fall and generally how impressive everyone we met through Fulbright is - the friendships I made have persisted, as has my awe of them!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some highlights of mid-year (or more like small details I don&amp;rsquo;t want to forget):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploring Murcia with some friends right after we got in - the river was beautiful to walk along, there&amp;rsquo;s a casino that&amp;rsquo;s actually a beautiful building that was fun to explore, and afterwards I was able to enjoy a glass of my new favorite drink, vermouth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-exploring-the-casino-with-some-friends&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino_me.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Exploring the casino with some friends!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino_me.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Exploring the casino with some friends!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-im-always-so-amazed-at-how-beautiful-the-details-are-in-european-architecture&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;I&amp;rsquo;m always so amazed at how beautiful the details are in European architecture&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    I&amp;rsquo;m always so amazed at how beautiful the details are in European architecture
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-obviously-seeing-a-mirror-merited-a-mirror-selfie&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino_friends.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Obviously seeing a mirror merited a mirror selfie&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino_friends.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Obviously seeing a mirror merited a mirror selfie
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group lunches that weren&amp;rsquo;t scheduled with enough time (we had 1.5 hours to find a place and eat, in &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt;, where lunch is supposed to be a 2+ hour affair) so we were all late to everything but collectively so it was fun. We really should have broken up but we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the heart to eat in groups smaller than a cool 16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How hard Murcia tourism tried to sell us on the city of Murcia -  they showed us a video of Murcia (after about 18 hours in the city at this point I already recognized many of the places), gave us free stuff, and tried to convince us to come back. Professors at the university also tried to recruit several of us for graduate programs or in my case a research internship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching two close friends of mine give amazing presentations on their research - Anna on complex systems and modeling ants, and Ash on developing an HIV vaccine. My friends are so brilliant! Other Fulbrighters I want to get to know better also gave great presentations on topics such as using social media to learn languages, indigenous languages in Spain, and the role of touch in education for young children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attending some pretty cool grantee-led workshops. One of them was on sustainability in Spain, and it was interesting to explore ways we have observed Spanish culture being more or less sustainable than American culture. I also attended a session where we discussed how we have been adjusting to and enjoying life in Spain, which gave me a lot of new ideas that I want to try here!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A workshop where a male professor was pretty condescending to me and a few of my female friends, but we stood our ground and clapped back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A market in Murcia with a lot of cool food options (there was some vegetarian Murcian food that was actually very good, surprisingly) that we ended up going to on multiple nights. The market also had a secret bar that you opened a window to get into - on the last night, all of Fulbright went there (the Comission included), and then to a bar/club with &amp;ldquo;erasmus&amp;rdquo; in the title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fulbright talent show! A bunch of the ETA regions gave entertaining and funny performances, which was great - everyone in La Rioja took their own bottle of wine up on stage and had a very well done and enthusiastic performance. A research friend of mine did some hilarious stand up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cocktail party to end mid year - unlike the orientation cocktail, where I was exhausted and hungry, it was fun to dress up for this cocktail, enjoy the free unlimited wine, and see all of my friends at once. I will say, Fulbright has made me a lot better at navigating cocktail parties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Mid-Year was a lovely, wonderful time.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-barca-gangs-cocktail-photo-i-really-am-an-honorary-barcelona-researcher&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_cocktail.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The Barca gang&amp;rsquo;s cocktail photo (I really am an honorary Barcelona researcher)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_cocktail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The Barca gang&amp;rsquo;s cocktail photo (I really am an honorary Barcelona researcher)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valencia is on the way back from Murcia to Zaragoza, so I convinced five friends to stop by, and we spent 24 hours in Valencia on the way back! We were all so exhausted (going out until 3 am 2 nights in a row when you have to wake up at 8 am the next day is not ideal) and knocked out for a good 10 hours that night, but we also had a great time. Valencia is beautiful - with its Catalan-esque language (this is actually very contentious, according to two taxi drivers we had), palm trees, and beautiful architecture, it feels like a smaller, warmer and less touristy version of Barcelona. We had a great time eating &lt;em&gt;paella&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;horchata&lt;/em&gt;, seeing the modern arts and sciences center, and exploring  the city center.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-valencia-is-beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/valencia_fountain.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Valencia is beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/valencia_fountain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Valencia is beautiful
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-arts-and-sciences-center-at-night-with-my-friends-ash-olivia-and-miranda&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/valencia_sciences.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The arts and sciences center at night with my friends Ash, Olivia and Miranda&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/valencia_sciences.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The arts and sciences center at night with my friends Ash, Olivia and Miranda
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;




  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-tasting-some-paella&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/paella.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Tasting some paella&amp;hellip;&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/paella.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Tasting some &lt;em&gt;paella&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-and-horchata-with-fartons-food-is-a-true-highlight-of-this-city&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/horchata.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;and horchata with fartons! Food is a true highlight of this city.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/horchata.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    and &lt;em&gt;horchata&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;fartons&lt;/em&gt;! Food is a true highlight of this city.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe that I only have 3 months left in Spain, but I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely going to make the most of them. My best friend is coming and we&amp;rsquo;re going to road trip around Mallorca for a week. My family (including my sister this time) is going to come to do Andalucia and a couple of days in Portugal. I&amp;rsquo;m determined to make it to Northern Spain - &lt;em&gt;pais vasco&lt;/em&gt; and Asturias both seem incredible, especially once it gets a little warmer. A few more friends from the US also want to try to make it over - I am blessed with visitors! It&amp;rsquo;s going to be busy and crazy and I will literally travel every weekend for a month or two, but I&amp;rsquo;m so excited for all of the places I want to explore and people I want to get closer to. &lt;em&gt;(Okay, so obviously none of that happened&amp;hellip;.except for getting closer to people. More on that soon)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #11: FAT*</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written February 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I closed out the insane month of January with a 4-day trip to Barcelona for the FAT* conference, which pulled together computer scientists, lawyers, people in the tech industry, and social scientists to talk about fairness, accountability and transparency in computing. This was my first academic conference ever, and I had an incredible time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go to the conference because it was conveniently a 1-hour train ride away, Fulbright was going to fund my attendance, and it seemed important and relevant to my interests. It ended up being much more meaningful than I had anticipated -  I&amp;rsquo;m so happy I had the opportunity to go! Beyond just talking to CS academics and people in the tech industry, I got to talk to lawyers and professors in non-CS fields. There were so many cool talks that exposed me to ways of thinking I had never experienced before. There were also a handful of Berkeley PhD students there and it was great to meet them and learn about ways I can be involved in similar discussions once I go there. I&amp;rsquo;m definitely excited for what&amp;rsquo;s ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always understood that thinking about the implications and ethics of CS is important, and put effort into educating myself in those areas, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never learned as much about bias in computing, or how to make AI explainable, or challenges in creating AI policies, as I did during this conference. The talks I attended definitely changed my personal evaluation of different AI systems I encounter - right now, neural networks optimize for some loss function that minimizes error, but what they instead were optimized in a way that penalizes bias? I also thought AI explainability was an extremely interesting and important area, since frequently a neural network will give us a result and but we have no idea why it is returning that result, and as a result neural networks lead to all sorts of problems (read 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1710.08864.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; about how a single pixel change can completley fool a neural network).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-miranda-and-anna-at-fat&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/fat*.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me, Miranda, and Anna at FAT*!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/fat*.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me, Miranda, and Anna at FAT*!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the conference, being in Barcelona and with the other Fulbright researchers was incredible. There&amp;rsquo;s a cohort of about 10 Fulbright researchers in Barcelona and they are all amazing people. We had a lot of fun group dinners in the 3 nights I was there, including one with most of us crammed into the corner of a tapas bar and being unnecessarily crazy after one round of beers. At some point in this visit, the Barcelona crew officially adopted me as one of their own, adding me to the group chat and everything, which was adorable. Audrey, a neuroscience researcher who is going to go to med school next year, very graciously hosted me the entire time I was there, and we bonded incredibly. It&amp;rsquo;s rare that you can spend 6 hours one on one with someone, have nonstop conversation the whole time, and then be shocked that 6 whole hours have passed. I attended the conference with Anna and Miranda, the two other CS researchers (both of who are so cool and brilliant and wonderful), and while none of us have explicitly done research in AI fairness or related fields, we had a great time exploring the conference together and talking about how our views on our own research changed throughout it.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-for-some-reason-our-group-photo-after-dinner-one-night-involved-me-being-carried&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_din.HEIC&#34; data-caption=&#34;For some reason, our group photo after dinner one night involved me being carried&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_din.HEIC&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    For some reason, our group photo after dinner one night involved me being carried
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I&#39;m Spending Quarantine</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/how-im-spending-quarantine/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 21:49:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/how-im-spending-quarantine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I first came home from Spain, I was overwhelmed by the craziness of having to suddenly pack up and move back to the US, sadness at my Fulbright suddenly ending and not getting to say goodbye to my new friends, and exhaustion. It took me some time to adjust to a new lifestyle, but since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve been staying busy and having a good time. I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed continuing some things I started prioritizing in Spain, and learning new things!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s nice to feel like I&amp;rsquo;m still living a fulfilling life, even if it&amp;rsquo;s different from the life I thought I would be living right now. It&amp;rsquo;s also been great to finally do things I wanted to do at some point but never would have made time for otherwise. I can honestly say I haven&amp;rsquo;t been bored once since the pandemic started. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ve been up to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Research + Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The bulk of my time has been spent finishing up research I worked on during my Fulbright grant and also starting to meet with my future PhD advisor and joining in on lab meetings. In addition to spending a lot of time on research projects, I have been trying to stay up to date on current work in my fields by reading papers and attending conferences virtually (so far, ICCP, and parts of Eurographics and CVPR). I&amp;rsquo;m also doing an online course on how to get more familiar with various tools that computer science students and researchers use, which has so far been insanely useful - there will likely be a blog post to come on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Family + Friend Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loving all of this time with my family - we were definitely not expecting to have this much time together ever. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to eat all of our meals together, even lunch in the middle of our workdays, and to all go for a walk together every evening. I&amp;rsquo;m very close to my little sister so I have especially adored all of this extra time for us to truly be a part of each others everyday lives! She is a rising sophomore in college and also studying computer science so we have been taking that online course together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have also really valued staying in touch virtually (or on socially distanced walks) with friends from Fulbright, college, and my childhood. In some ways, the pandemic brought me and my Fulbright friends closer together, since we never would have had the crazy shared experience of suddenly leaving Spain and then grappling with the pandemic in the way we faced it otherwise. In general, it&amp;rsquo;s been nice to have time to reconnect with friends I haven&amp;rsquo;t talked with in a while.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prioritizing Health&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been loving consistently getting a solid 8 hours of sleep every night and never having any super late nights, as fun as going to Spanish clubs until 4/5/6/7 am was. I&amp;rsquo;ve been eating healthy and going on walks every day to get plenty of fresh air. I do miss my gym in Spain a lot, but I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten back into a consistent running/HIIT workout schedule and have also started doing yoga regularly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learning Hindi&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I never learned Hindi as a child, but my parents are fluent in it (as well as English and 2 other Indian languages - they are incredible) and I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up watching Bollywood films, so learning Hindi has always been something I wanted to do but never had time for. I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying learning the alphabet and basic phrases, and then practicing with my entire family and asking them questions, making for another bonding activitiy. Having an excuse to watch some more Bollywood has also been an added bonus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Photography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know a lot about how photography works, since a lot of my research for the past year or so has been in computational photography, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t had access to my parents&amp;rsquo; DSLR for an extended period of time until now. It&amp;rsquo;s been so nice to learn new tricks and practice. My photos mostly only consist of the flowers in my backyard, objects in my house, my family, and a few long exposure waterfall shots, so not the most variety, but definitely a lot of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Community Involvement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did a lot of sexual violence prevention work in college, which I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I was a part of, but also became very exhausting, so after college I needed a break from activism. Especially after George Floyd&amp;rsquo;s death just a couple of miles away from me, I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to once again take a more active role in doing helpful, and it&amp;rsquo;s been so nice to have the energy and time to do so. I have been trying to better educate myself and my family/friends, doing research on where to donate, and wrote 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://iamn.org/documents/2020/saari/Youth%20Letter%20to%20IAM.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this letter&lt;/a&gt; with some of my friends to try to better mobilize the South Asian community in Minnesota. If you are reading this, you should go 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blacklivesmatter.carrd.co/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/document/d/1Gwl9omY8l5dUCkK4Y2llKAsfx5asES9zWn4Tr27QhTU/mobilebasic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to sign petitions, find ways to help, and better educate yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve consistently kept a journal for a while, so it&amp;rsquo;s been nice to keep that up, but starting this blog has been a very different adventure! It&amp;rsquo;s fun to write with a little more purpose and try to write about topics that would hopefully actually be helpful for others, or that friends might want to read about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #10: The Longest Winter Break</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:51:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written January 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so happy to go home for the holidays, even though I had to experience a taste of Minnesota winter. It was incredible to be with my family and see friends back home, as always, but it felt especially comforting to have the familiarity and ease of being around the people I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up with who speak English the same way I do. One of the biggest highlights was food - as a vegetarian, traditional Spanish cuisine is not the best for me, and Spain also lacks good Asian food, so I relished in going to all my favorite restaurants back home and eating my mom&amp;rsquo;s food. Another highlight was trying out a free week of hot yoga with my sister and generally getting to spend time with her. Overall, I  realized that there are things in America I love and feel more comfortable with, but there were things about Spain I missed too, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready to leave Spain (and I&amp;rsquo;m still not&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a hard transition back to America). &lt;em&gt;(My transition back ended up being so premature and jarring in a very different way from how I expected.)&lt;/em&gt; Right after New Years, I stopped in NYC for about 48 hours on the way back to meet up with some friends for a truly glorious 48 hours. I&amp;rsquo;m impressed at how much food I was able to consume in those 48 hours. We also discovered a really cool speakeasy and overall had the best time! &lt;em&gt;(Rip NYC - it&amp;rsquo;s crazy that I was there so recently. Definitely happy that I enjoyed it while I could.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-enjoying-some-ethiopian-food-in-nyc-with-my-best-friend&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ethiopian_nyc.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Enjoying some Ethiopian food in NYC with my best friend&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ethiopian_nyc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Enjoying some Ethiopian food in NYC with my best friend
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to Spain on January 5 so that I could spend January 6, &lt;em&gt;Dia de los Reyes&lt;/em&gt;, with my friend Cristina and her family, who live just outside of Madrid. &lt;em&gt;Dia de los Reyes&lt;/em&gt; is the most important day of Christamas in Spain - the day where everyone opens their presents, and then eats &lt;em&gt;roscon&lt;/em&gt;, a traditional cake. It was very cool to experience Christmas as they do. My family doesn&amp;rsquo;t do traditional Christmas gifts, so it was fun to do that with her family (they were very generous!). Her family is the sweetest and I had a lovely time despite the jet lag.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-cristinas-familys-christmas-tree&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/christmas_tree.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cristina&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;rsquo;s Christmas tree&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/christmas_tree.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Cristina&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;rsquo;s Christmas tree
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-roscon-it-has-a-little-toy-baked-into-it&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/roscon.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;The roscon. It has a little toy baked into it&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/roscon.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The &lt;em&gt;roscon&lt;/em&gt;. It has a little toy baked into it
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I went back to Zaragoza for 5 days before I was off to India for a whirlwind 6 day trip! Those few days were truly a warm, crazy fever dream. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really sleep but I did eat so much good food (I really forget how amazing Indian food in India is) and saw an insane amount of family members. My family in India consists of a few hundred people and so the majority of my trip was just me trying to remember the names of the relative I was talking to&amp;hellip;we really need a pocket family tree.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-reunited-with-my-favorite-person-after-a-whole-week-apart-and-also-with-some-of-my-favorite-food&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/nitya_swatis.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Reunited with my favorite person after a whole week apart, and also with some of my favorite food!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/nitya_swatis.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Reunited with my favorite person after a whole week apart, and also with some of my favorite food!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two major highlights of the trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, going to Ahmedabad, where my nana (grandfather on mom&amp;rsquo;s side) grew up and my mom frequently went as a child. We have some family there that I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen that much, so it was nice to see them. Some of them live in a house that has a backyard with trees that grow little baby guavas and real peacocks that hang out there! There was also a kite flying festival when we visited, where all the kids (and many adults) fly kites all day and night. During the day, people try to &amp;ldquo;cut&amp;rdquo; other people&amp;rsquo;s kites out of the sky (the kite strings are made with broken glass and so you can also easily cut yourself while flying a kite), and at night, people string lanterns on kites. Lots of safety/fire hazards, but still an amazing time, and very pretty.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-flying-kites-with-my-sister-dad-and-some-uncles&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites_daylight.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Flying kites with my sister, dad and some uncles&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites_daylight.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Flying kites with my sister, dad and some uncles
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-kites-at-night-were-so-beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The kites at night were so beautiful!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The kites at night were so beautiful!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, the wedding, which was mostly why we were there. Indian weddings are INSANE. This wedding was only 2.5 days long, and it was the shortest Indian wedding I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard of - it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for most weddings to take place over 5 days or even a week. There were 4 different functions, so I of course had to wear 4 different outfits. One of my favorite parts was the &lt;em&gt;baraat&lt;/em&gt;, where the groom&amp;rsquo;s family dances in the streets directly before the actual wedding ceremony. My dad is such a child at heart and it&amp;rsquo;s adorable - he especially enjoyed a lot of the wedding. Overall, it was fun to be surrounded by so much family, and to see my dad with all the people he grew up with!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-love-a-family-photo&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/family_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;We love a family photo!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/family_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We love a family photo!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-all-the-wedding-outfits-are-a-lot-of-fun&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;All the wedding outfits are a lot of fun&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    All the wedding outfits are a lot of fun
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-my-dad-had-a-great-time-at-the-wedding-with-his-cousins&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/dad_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;My dad had a GREAT time at the wedding with his cousins&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/dad_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    My dad had a GREAT time at the wedding with his cousins
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-maybe-13-of-the-cousins-on-my-dads-side-my-grandmother-on-his-side-is-one-of-7-sisters&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/cousins_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Maybe 1/3 of the cousins on my dad&amp;rsquo;s side (my grandmother on his side is one of 7 sisters&amp;hellip;)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/cousins_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Maybe 1/3 of the cousins on my dad&amp;rsquo;s side (my grandmother on his side is one of 7 sisters&amp;hellip;)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello!</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 23:29:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for making your way to my blog! I am excited to see where this new adventure takes me.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_photo.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_photo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By way of introducing myself: I grew up in St. Paul, Minnesota with my parents and my little sister, Nitya. In middle school and high school, most of my time outside of school was spent practicing the violin, doing bharatanatyam (a form of Indian dance), and being a part of the math team. In 2015, I moved to Hanover, New Hampshire, to start at Dartmouth College. There, I discovered computer science and fell in love with both a new way of thinking and the potential to make an important impact. I continued violin in my college orchestra and had a lot of fun spending time in the outdoors, getting into hiking and climbing. I also became very involved with sexual violence prevention, eventually serving as a chair on the Student and Presidential Committee on Sexual Assault. I graduated with a double major in Computer Science and Mathematics, experiences both in academia and industry, and admission to the EECS PhD program at UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was excited to start my PhD, but decided to defer for a year. After graduation, I moved to Zaragoza, Spain for a Fulbright research scholarship. I spent the most incredible 6 months in Spain before I had to leave early and return home due to the pandemic. I&amp;rsquo;ve been staying busy at home finishing up my Fulbright research remotely, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make the most of this time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying photography, running, reading, cooking, and now starting this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been good about keeping a consistent journal for years, but when I was in Spain, I started writing more for other people. I sent semi-regular email updates to several friends and family about my adventures in Spain, and really enjoyed sharing what I was up to. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been asked by several people about the process of applying to Fulbright/grad school/scholarships, and I want to answer those questions in a way that is hopefully helpful to others, especially to women, first gen, and BIPOC students considering computer science or doing research. I have been incredibly fortunate to have so many wonderful mentors and access to resources at an elite institution, and I would love to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned with those who may not have as easy access to this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting lightly edited versions of the emails I sent to my friends (but I won&amp;rsquo;t omit things I have since changed my mind about - it&amp;rsquo;s been fun to reread them and see how things evolved) covering most of my Fulbright experience in Spain, several posts about research/grad school/applying to Fulbright, and other things that come across my mind. If there is anything you would like to hear about, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://neerja.me/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
