<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2020 | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerja.me/tag/2020/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerja.me/tag/2020/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>2020</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work by Neerja Thakkar is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
© Neerja Thakkar 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:51:02 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerja.me/images/icon_hu86b94514bc44f7650ad97bf1bd4dbea1_2402_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>2020</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/tag/2020/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #10</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:51:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written January 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so happy to go home for the holidays, even though I had to experience a taste of Minnesota winter. It was incredible to be with my family and see friends back home, as always, but it felt especially comforting to have the familiarity and ease of being around the people I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up with who speak English the same way I do. One of the biggest highlights was food - as a vegetarian, traditional Spanish cuisine is not the best for me, and Spain also lacks good Asian food, so I relished in going to all my favorite restaurants back home and eating my mom&amp;rsquo;s food. Another highlight was trying out a free week of hot yoga with my sister and generally getting to spend time with her. Overall, I  realized that there are things in America I love and feel more comfortable with, but there were also things about Spain I missed too, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready to leave Spain (and I&amp;rsquo;m still not&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a hard transition back to America). &lt;em&gt;(My transition back ended up being so premature and jarring in a very different way from how I expected.)&lt;/em&gt; Right after New Years, I stopped in NYC for about 48 hours on the way back to meet up with some friends for a truly glorious 48 hours. I&amp;rsquo;m impressed at how much food I was able to consume in those 48 hours. We also discovered a really cool speakeasy and overall had the best time! &lt;em&gt;(Rip NYC - it&amp;rsquo;s crazy that I was there so recently. Definitely happy that I enjoyed it while I could.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-enjoying-some-ethiopian-food-in-nyc-with-my-best-friend&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ethiopian_nyc.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Enjoying some Ethiopian food in NYC with my best friend&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ethiopian_nyc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Enjoying some Ethiopian food in NYC with my best friend
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to Spain on January 5 so that I could spend January 6, &lt;em&gt;Dia de los Reyes&lt;/em&gt;, with my friend Cristina and her family, who live just outside of Madrid. &lt;em&gt;Dia de los Reyes&lt;/em&gt; is the most important day of Christamas in Spain - the day where everyone opens their presents, and then eats &lt;em&gt;roscon&lt;/em&gt;, a traditional cake. It was very cool to experience Christmas as they do. My family doesn&amp;rsquo;t do traditional Christmas gifts, so it was fun to do that with her family (they were very generous!). Her family is the sweetest and I had a lovely time despite the jet lag.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-cristinas-familys-christmas-tree&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/christmas_tree.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cristina&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;rsquo;s Christmas tree&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/christmas_tree.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Cristina&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;rsquo;s Christmas tree
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-roscon-it-has-a-little-toy-baked-into-it&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/roscon.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;The roscon. It has a little toy baked into it&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/roscon.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The &lt;em&gt;roscon&lt;/em&gt;. It has a little toy baked into it
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I went back to Zaragoza for 5 days before I was off to India for a whirlwind 6 day trip! Those few days were truly a warm, crazy fever dream. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really sleep but I did eat so much good food (I really forget how amazing Indian food in India is) and saw an insane amount of family members. My family in India consists of a few hundred people and so the majority of my trip was just me trying to remember the names of the relative I was talking to&amp;hellip;we really need a pocket family tree.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-reunited-with-my-favorite-person-after-a-whole-week-apart-and-also-with-some-of-my-favorite-food&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/nitya_swatis.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Reunited with my favorite person after a whole week apart, and also with some of my favorite food!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/nitya_swatis.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Reunited with my favorite person after a whole week apart, and also with some of my favorite food!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two major highlights of the trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, going to Ahmedabad, where my nana (grandfather on mom&amp;rsquo;s side) grew up and my mom frequently went as a child. We have some family there that I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen that much, so it was nice to see them. Some of them live in a house that has a backyard with trees that grow little baby guavas and real peacocks that hang out there! There was also a kite flying festival when we visited, where all the kids (and many adults) fly kites all day and night. During the day, people try to &amp;ldquo;cut&amp;rdquo; other people&amp;rsquo;s kites out of the sky (the kite strings are made with broken glass and so you can also easily cut yourself while flying a kite), and at night, people string lanterns on kites. Lots of safety/fire hazards, but still an amazing time, and very pretty.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-flying-kites-with-my-sister-dad-and-some-uncles&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites_daylight.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Flying kites with my sister, dad and some uncles&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites_daylight.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Flying kites with my sister, dad and some uncles
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-kites-at-night-were-so-beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The kites at night were so beautiful!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The kites at night were so beautiful!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, the wedding, which was mostly why we were there. Indian weddings are INSANE. This wedding was only 2.5 days long, and it was the shortest Indian wedding I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard of - it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for most weddings to take place over 5 days or even a week. There were 4 different functions, so I of course had to wear 4 different outfits. One of my favorite parts was the &lt;em&gt;bharat&lt;/em&gt;, where the groom&amp;rsquo;s family dances in the streets directly before the actual wedding ceremony. My dad is such a child at heart and it&amp;rsquo;s adorable - he especially enjoyed a lot of the wedding. Overall, it was fun to be surrounded by so much family, and to see my dad with all the people he grew up with!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-love-a-family-photo&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/family_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;We love a family photo!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/family_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We love a family photo!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-all-the-wedding-outfits-are-a-lot-of-fun&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;All the wedding outfits are a lot of fun&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    All the wedding outfits are a lot of fun
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-my-dad-had-a-great-time-at-the-wedding-with-his-cousins&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/dad_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;My dad had a GREAT time at the wedding with his cousins&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/dad_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    My dad had a GREAT time at the wedding with his cousins
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-maybe-13-of-the-cousins-on-my-dads-side-hahaha-my-grandmother-on-his-side-is-one-of-7-sisters&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/cousins_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Maybe 1/3 of the cousins on my dad&amp;rsquo;s side hahaha (my grandmother on his side is one of 7 sisters&amp;hellip;)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/cousins_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Maybe 1/3 of the cousins on my dad&amp;rsquo;s side hahaha (my grandmother on his side is one of 7 sisters&amp;hellip;)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello!</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 23:29:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thanks for making your way to my blog! I am excited to see where this new adventure takes me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By way of introducing myself: I grew up in St. Paul, Minnesota with my parents and my little sister, Nitya. In middle school and high school, most of my time outside of school was spent practicing the violin, doing bharatanatyam (a form of Indian dance), and being a part of the math team. In 2015, I moved to Hanover, New Hampshire, to start at Dartmouth College. There, I discovered computer science and fell in love with both a new way of thinking and the potential to make an important impact. I continued violin in my college orchestra and had a lot of fun spending time in the outdoors, getting into hiking and climbing. I also became very involved with sexual violence prevention, eventually serving as a chair on the Student and Presidential Committee on Sexual Assault. I graduated with a double major in Computer Science and Mathematics, experiences both in academia and industry, and admission to the EECS PhD program at UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was excited to start my PhD, but decided to defer for a year. After graduation, I moved to Zaragoza, Spain for a Fulbright research scholarship. I spent the most incredible 6 months in Spain before I had to leave early and return home due to the pandemic. I&amp;rsquo;ve been staying busy at home finishing up my Fulbright research remotely, and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to make the most of this time. I&amp;rsquo;ve been enjoying photography, running, reading, cooking, and now starting this blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been good about keeping a consistent journal for years, but when I was in Spain, I started writing more for other people. I sent semi-regular email updates to several friends and family about my adventures in Spain, and really enjoyed sharing what I was up to. I&amp;rsquo;ve also been asked by several people about the process of applying to Fulbright/grad school/scholarships, and I want to post information about that that is hopefully helpful to others, especially other women considering computer science. I have been incredibly fortunate to have so many wonderful mentors and access to resources at an elite institution, and I would love to share what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned with those who may not have as easy access to this information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting lightly edited versions of the emails I sent to my friends (but I won&amp;rsquo;t omit things I have since changed my mind about - it&amp;rsquo;s been fun to reread them and see how things evolved) covering most of my Fulbright experience in Spain, several posts about research/grad school/applying to Fulbright, and other things that come across my mind. If there is anything you would like to hear about, don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://neerja.me/#contact&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reach out&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
