<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spain | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerja.me/places/spain/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerja.me/places/spain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Spain</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work by Neerja Thakkar is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
© Neerja Thakkar 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 11:03:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerja.me/images/icon_hu709051646b5c016a474294f302c76519_2025058_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Spain</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/places/spain/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #14: Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I had discussed in my previous post, the coronavirus was getting progressively worse in Spain. Once Trump made his announcement, I decided to make the most of my remaining time. I am not a spontaneous person, but knowing that I probably at least had 48 hours left in Spain, I decided I was going to go to Barcelona. I booked a train ticket, threw some clothes and toiletries into a bag, and headed to the train station. Train rides were always a fun and special experience for me &amp;mdash; I loved putting on some music and writing in my journal, or just enjoying the beautiful view of the Spanish countryside. But on this train ride, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even put on music. I just stared at some news on my phone and tried to process Spain falling apart (this was a little before it was clear that the entire world was falling apart and the implications of the pandemic were much more dire than just cancelled foreign study programs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got off the train and took the familiar walk through &lt;em&gt;Estacion Sants&lt;/em&gt; and into the metro, and eventually stepped out onto &lt;em&gt;La Rambla&lt;/em&gt; and walked a block through the beautiful Gothic Quarter to get to my friend Anna&amp;rsquo;s place. She opened the door to her apartment and we gave each other a hug (this was before we really understood the concept of social distancing) and the relief I felt was immediate. It was lovely to finally be with someone who understood my position of likely being forced to leave Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ventured out to a bar Anna wanted to show me. It was magical - I was transported to a forest. Next, we went to my favorite bar in Barcelona (and in the world), a classy place that makes custom cocktails that always end up being the best cocktail I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had, and all seven or so friends I&amp;rsquo;ve taken there agree. Then it was time to meet up with the rest of the Barca gang. We first went to a noodle/dumpling bar, and then we went to another place with empañadas. It was incredible to see everyone - the level of comfort that I felt being surrounded by them after a crazy week was unreal. Audrey proclaimed that she was in denial, but she knew we were all going to be sent home. Apparently the ECA (the branch of the government that runs Fulbright) had said that all exchange programs would have a 60 day pause. We had 90 days left, so this was so clearly the end.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-one-last-sangria-in-an-ethereal-cozy-bar&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/forest_bar.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;One last sangria in an ethereal, cozy bar&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/forest_bar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    One last sangria in an ethereal, cozy bar
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, we had a busy day ahead of us. Anna had a list of places she wanted to see in Barcelona before she left - mostly various museums - and we were going to make some progress on it. The day had a surreal energy. I knew that our time here was so limited, by days, maybe even hours. It was crazy and terrifying to watch the world fall apart in ways that I had never imagined, but also a beautiful reminder about how special life is, and how much of a gift it was to be half a world away from everything I had known and held familiar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-places-in-barcelona-that-were-now-familiar-felt-extra-remarkable-and-magical-like-this-plaza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_plaza.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Places in Barcelona that were now familiar felt extra remarkable and magical, like this plaza&amp;hellip;&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_plaza.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Places in Barcelona that were now familiar felt extra remarkable and magical, like this plaza&amp;hellip;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-or-the-hallowed-walls-of-the-gothic-quarter-fun-fact-theres-a-skull-on-the-underside-of-the-pont-del-bisbe&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/gothic_walls.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;&amp;hellip;or the hallowed walls of the Gothic Quarter. Fun fact: there&amp;rsquo;s a skull on the underside of the pont del bisbe&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/gothic_walls.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &amp;hellip;or the hallowed walls of the Gothic Quarter. Fun fact: there&amp;rsquo;s a skull on the underside of the &lt;em&gt;pont del bisbe&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started the day off with me finally visiting the famous Boqueria market. Then we got brunch with Audrey and a college friend of hers who had just arrived in Barcelona as part of world travel on a Watson fellowship. The meal was wonderful - I had been looking for real American-esque brunch food in Spain the entire time I was there and I had finally found it.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-it-only-took-me-5-trips-to-barcelona-to-go-to-one-of-the-biggest-tourist-attractions&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/boqueria.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;It only took me 5 trips to Barcelona to go to one of the biggest tourist attractions&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/boqueria.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    It only took me 5 trips to Barcelona to go to one of the biggest tourist attractions
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-brunch-with-audrey-and-anna-3&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_brunch.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Brunch with Audrey and Anna &amp;lt;3&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_brunch.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Brunch with Audrey and Anna &amp;lt;3
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, Audrey peeled off, and Anna, our new friend, and I took the scenic route through the Gothic quarter and up to Montjuic. Of course, we were talking about how we would probably all have to leave soon. And then, just as we got to the top and started to take in the beautiful view of the city, Anna got an email. What we had all been dreading was here. Her undergrad institution&amp;rsquo;s Fulbright coordinator told us that we were all going to be sent home and should start booking flights. I stood in silence as Anna talked to her family on the phone, and tried to process this news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, I got an email too, sent to all grantees. Spain was now CDC level 3, and we were encouraged to return to the US within the next week. I read the information about closing our bank accounts, how stipend payments would work, and getting a plane ticket, and tried to process this - it felt unreal, even though I knew it had been coming. After Anna and I absorbed this, we tried to go to the Joan Miro museum, but it was closed. The city was shutting down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening, we all gathered at a soccer field near Montjuic with drinks and chocolate and watched the sun set on our Fulbright. We passed sheets of paper around and wrote notes to each other under a one minute time limit. When I got my sheet back, I was amazed at the depth of things that my friends wrote about me, despite me seeing most of them only about 5 times total over the 6 months I had known them. It hit me that I had been a part of and helped create something so special between all of us, and I was so excited to continue building those bonds and enjoying Spain (the castle in Girona that we were all planning to stay at in April really epitomized that), but now it was all just going to end. Later, the pandemic got much worse in America and all of the horrible economic and personal impacts for so many people became clear, but at the time, it just felt like we were being sent home.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-my-friend-sasha-and-i-at-the-soccer-field-overlooking-the-city&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/sasha.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;My friend Sasha and I at the soccer field overlooking the city&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/sasha.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    My friend Sasha and I at the soccer field overlooking the city
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-barca-gangs-last-in-person-rendezvous&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_montjuic.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The Barca gang&amp;rsquo;s last in-person rendezvous&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_montjuic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The Barca gang&amp;rsquo;s last in-person rendezvous
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, Anna, our friend Akshay, and I got brunch; the restaurant was already closed for eating and only open for takeout. We sat in Placa de la Universitat - one of the first places I had ever been to in Barcelona, since my sister and I stayed in a hotel near the university my first time in the city. We sat on a bench and I tried to just enjoy looking at the city and talking to my friends, knowing that this would be one of my last moments of peace before I had to pack up my apartment and deal with a million things. I headed to the train station and bought one last ticket to Zaragoza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got home and tried to contemplate having to pack up my entire apartment in the next 2 days. My flatmates were excited - apparently the president was going to address the country in the evening. As I started packing, messages were flying in every WhatsApp group. Everyone was really confused, and debating whether they should say in Spain or leave. They were angry at the lack of clear guidance on exactly what we needed to do from Fulbright, since the email just &amp;ldquo;strongly recommended&amp;rdquo; that we leave. I personally thought that the Comission was very responsive and helpful during this crazy crisis, but the fault was with the US government for having a lack of a clear plan and leadership at the top, which then trickled down to be confusing for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was definitely conflicted, but I also knew that my family really wanted me to come home, and being with them during this crazy time didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like the worst idea. It also seemed like flights were getting cancelled left and right, so we all had to try to get out of Spain ASAP. My flight was booked for Tuesday originally, but it got cancelled, so I moved to a Monday flight and gave myself less than 24 hours to pack up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening, the president of Spain spoke to the country. He announced that Spain was going to enter a strict lockdown, that people would only be allowed to leave their apartments to get groceries, go to the pharmacy, or go to the doctor. All of a sudden, everyone in Spain started taking the virus really seriously. My flatmates and labmates realized that the virus could spiral out of control and that they needed to listen to their leaders - what a contrast to how Americans responded to the virus. On the bright side, the lockdown meant that Spain somewhat got a handle on the virus. Also, the prospect of spending a lot of the next 3 months in my apartment in Spain made leaving a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day or so was a whirlwind of packing everything up, realizing it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even fit into the 4 suitcases/duffle bags I had, my labmate Julio saving me by both letting me store a few things at his house indefinitely and driving me to the train station, making it back to Barcelona, and hauling my luggage around until I was at the baggage drop and then Delta agent was merciful with extra baggage for the first time in my memory. I very cautiously got on the plane, feeling aware of my proximity to others in a way that I&amp;rsquo;m now familiar with. I was sitting next to a guy who had been studying abroad in Barcelona and had to leave early, a relatable mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screening when I landed on U.S. soil was very lax. They took my temperature, but did no other checks, and I doubt they would have done anything except encourage me to quarantine for 14 days if I did have one. I had low expectations of how America would handle the pandemic, but this was an early indication that it would be even worse. That being said, the gratitude and relief I felt when I saw my family and got home was immense. I missed Spain immediately, but I felt so lucky to have a loving home to return to, to still be on my parents&amp;rsquo; health insurance, and to have my supportive family and wonderful friends to process this unprecedented situation with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #13: My Last Weeks in Spain</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-13/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-13/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shortly after I drafted my post about mid-year, I had to leave Spain due to the pandemic. From here on out, all of my Spain posts are retrospective. In this one, I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about my last couple of weeks in Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to the end of February in Zaragoza (which truly feels like another lifetime), I was having a wonderful time. I guess spring comes early in Spain - the weather in Zaragoza was getting warmer, and cherry blossoms were blooming.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-this-photo-was-taken-on-february-11th-right-outside-of-my-apartmentspring-comes-much-earlier-in-spain&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz_flowers.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;This photo was taken on February 11th right outside of my apartment&amp;hellip;spring comes much earlier in Spain&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz_flowers.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    This photo was taken on February 11th right outside of my apartment&amp;hellip;spring comes much earlier in Spain
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally felt at home in my lab and was getting closer every day with my labmates. Miguel was gone from the lab due to a broken leg, but everyone else was still around. Work days consisted of learning lots of new things (and even changing GPUs in computers and some other basic hardware stuff, with the help of labmates), long lunches and lots of coffee breaks (we had a conversation about how to improve lab dynamics given that we were split up into two separate buildings, and the solution was to drink more coffee in the two buildings, resulting in about 3 coffee breaks every day), and frequent trips to the vending machine with Manu and Adrian. Some other fond memories from my last couple of weeks: a lovely, long chat on a Friday afternoon with Johanna, a postdoc from France, about work life balance in academia, and getting a new fancy coffee machine in the lab. Also, going out with Adrian and a bunch of his Spanish friends on a Thursday night and experiencing &lt;em&gt;machacados&lt;/em&gt; (shots of a mixed drink that you cover with a plastic lid and all simultaneously slam on to the bar, hard - success involves breaking a glass - before drinking).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Weekends consisted of sunny afternoons, failed hikes and crazy nights with my &lt;em&gt;auxiliares&lt;/em&gt; friends, a trip to the &lt;em&gt;pueblo&lt;/em&gt; of a labmate for a 7 hour lunch (that is not an exaggeration, and this is the norm for &amp;ldquo;lunch&amp;rdquo; at someones home), and more time spent with Aiko and Aparna&amp;rsquo;s class. As you read about in my last post, I had a lot of plans for the rest of my time in Spain, which I was looking forward to. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until early March that I started to suspect that maybe those plans wouldn&amp;rsquo;t happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few of my Fulbright friends had promised to come visit. In particular, Ash and Libby were planning to come from Madrid. We were debating between the second and third weekends of March, and thankfully they decided to come on the second weekend, otherwise they would not have made it before the pandemic hit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We had a wonderful time. I took them to my favorite tapas bars and restaurants in Zaragoza and went to some museums I had wanted to go to for a while but was saving/procrastinating going to. A fun fact I learned in the Roman Forum museum - Zaragoza used to be a Roman city called Caesar Agusto. Then, they dropped the &amp;ldquo;cae&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;sar agusto&amp;rdquo; became &amp;ldquo;Zaragoza&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zaragoza-is-famous-for-being-windy-my-friends-really-got-to-experience-that&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/windy_zgz.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Zaragoza is famous for being windy. My friends really got to experience that!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/windy_zgz.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Zaragoza is famous for being windy. My friends really got to experience that!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;




  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-interior-of-the-aljaferia-palace-in-zaragoza-which-inspired-the-famous-alahambra-and-is-truly-stunning&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_wall.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The interior of the Aljaferia palace in Zaragoza, which inspired the famous Alahambra and is truly stunning&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_wall.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The interior of the &lt;em&gt;Aljaferia&lt;/em&gt; palace in Zaragoza, which inspired the famous &lt;em&gt;Alahambra&lt;/em&gt; and is truly stunning
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-loved-these-doorways&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_friends.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;We loved these doorways&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_friends.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We loved these doorways
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-i-am-so-nostalgic-for-the-details-of-spanish-architecture-like-these-beautiful-ceilings&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_ceiling.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;I am so nostalgic for the details of Spanish architecture, like these beautiful ceilings&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aljaferia_ceiling.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    I am so nostalgic for the details of Spanish architecture, like these beautiful ceilings
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really appreciated my city and loved showing my friends around. It&amp;rsquo;s so good I got that they came when they did, because I definitely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have gone to Aljaferia again or hit all of my favorite tapas bars one last time!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-taking-my-friends-to-eat-my-favorite-champi-tapa&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/champi.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Taking my friends to eat my favorite champi tapa&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/champi.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Taking my friends to eat my favorite &lt;em&gt;champi&lt;/em&gt; tapa
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-a-dinner-we-made-out-of-tapas-at-a-place-that-specialized-in-cheese---pan-con-tomate-truffled-manchego-artichokes-in-cheese-and-migas-or-breadcrumbs-a-dish-very-typical-to-zaragoza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/tapas.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;A dinner we made out of tapas at a place that specialized in cheese - pan con tomate, truffled manchego, artichokes in cheese, and migas, or breadcrumbs, a dish very typical to Zaragoza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/tapas.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    A dinner we made out of tapas at a place that specialized in cheese - &lt;em&gt;pan con tomate&lt;/em&gt;, truffled &lt;em&gt;manchego&lt;/em&gt;, artichokes in cheese, and &lt;em&gt;migas&lt;/em&gt;, or breadcrumbs, a dish very typical to Zaragoza
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-i-really-wanted-to-see-this-view-from-the-tower-of-the-basilica-photo-generously-provided-by-my-friend-shani-and-show-it-to-my-friends-but-sadly-it-was-closed-that-weekend----one-of-so-many-reasons-i-have-to-go-back-to-spain&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/pilar_tower_view.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;I really wanted to see this view from the tower of the Basilica (photo generously provided by my friend Shani) and show it to my friends, but sadly it was closed that weekend -  one of so many reasons I have to go back to Spain!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/pilar_tower_view.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    I really wanted to see this view from the tower of the Basilica (photo generously provided by my friend Shani) and show it to my friends, but sadly it was closed that weekend -  one of so many reasons I have to go back to Spain!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-i-was-able-to-take-them-inside-the-basilica---this-is-its-ceiling&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/pilar_ceiling.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;I was able to take them inside the Basilica - this is its ceiling&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/pilar_ceiling.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    I was able to take them inside the Basilica - this is its ceiling
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zaragoza-is-so-stunningim-really-happy-i-was-able-to-rediscover-it-with-my-friends-and-appreciate-it-one-last-time&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz%3c3.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Zaragoza is so stunning&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m really happy I was able to rediscover it with my friends and appreciate it one last time&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz%3c3.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Zaragoza is so stunning&amp;hellip;I&amp;rsquo;m really happy I was able to rediscover it with my friends and appreciate it one last time
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That weekend felt like a very distinct point in which life went from pre pandemic to pandemic. I had talked about coronavirus with my lab mates, but they laughed at me for wanting to buy a mask to wear, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a main conversation point. But Ash and Libby and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t stop talking about coronavirus - would it become a pandemic? Would it spread to America? Would Fulbright let us stay here? Ash is brilliant - she had just gotten into Harvard med school and she&amp;rsquo;s very interested in epedimiology, so she was the perfect person to talk to about this (and still my go to person for covid-related questions, months later).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-spent-our-last-hour-together-hanging-out-in-the-park-by-my-house&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/park_hanging.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;We spent our last hour together hanging out in the park by my house&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/park_hanging.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We spent our last hour together hanging out in the park by my house
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-zaragoza-spring--ash-was-such-a-good-aesthetic&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/park_flower_aesthetic.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Zaragoza spring &amp;#43; Ash was such a good aesthetic&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/park_flower_aesthetic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Zaragoza spring + Ash was such a good aesthetic
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there was a nagging feeling about coronavirus, we still had a lovely time, but as soon as Ash and Libby left, things went downhill. On Monday at the lab I kept on refreshing the Spain coronavirus map and watched the numbers in Madrid triple in a single day. I started to have a sinking feeling as I faced the reality that I probably wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be allowed to stay. That evening, I went with my labmates to &lt;em&gt;cien montaditos&lt;/em&gt; (a chain in Spain) for sandwiches and beer. They made fun of me for my paranoia about the virus and fears about having to leave, and even for washing my hands before the food came! Clearly, they didn&amp;rsquo;t think coronavirus was anything to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week kept on devolving into more confusion and anxiety. Things were very bad in Italy, so I asked the Comission what happened to grantees over there, and they told me that Fulbright Italy was cancelled, and that depending on the region everyone was either encouraged to go home or Fulbright was cancelled and they were required to leave. With Spain quickly devolving into the next Northern Italy, it felt like things were getting worse and worse, but the Department of State wasn&amp;rsquo;t updating Spain&amp;rsquo;s travel advisory level (which would mean we had to leave), and Fulbright wasn&amp;rsquo;t telling us anything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t focus on work at all - I was consumed with wondering if we were going to get sent home, if the program would let us stay, if the numbers in Spain would continue to go up like crazy. It felt like I spent all day WhatsApping my Fulbright friends, trying to figure out what was going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had booked a trip to visit a friend in Asturias for that weekend, which would require me to travel to Barcelona on Thursday, and I had no clue if it was safe or reasonable to go or not. On Wednesday night, I woke up at 4:30 am, and saw a bunch of WhatsApp messages and texts from my family. Trump had said that Americans had 48 hours to come back to the country, and Fulbright still hadn&amp;rsquo;t told us anything. I woke up again a few hours later, and Fulbright still hadn&amp;rsquo;t said a word, and I had many more text messages. I&amp;rsquo;m not a spontaneous person normally, but I felt like I needed to be with my friends. So I booked a train ticket to Barcelona, packed enough clothes to suffice for a few days, and left my apartment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #12: Mid-Year</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-12/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written March 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In mid-February, Fulbright gathered all of the grantees in Murcia, Spain for 3 days of workshops, presentations, conversations, and festivities. These few days ended up being a huge highlight of my time in Spain so far! &lt;em&gt;(Now I  see them as by far some of the best of 2020&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s crazy that they happened in the same year as today.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before mid-year, I told my labmates that I was going to Murcia, and they were shocked that I was willingly going there. They kept on telling me that Murcia is the worst place in Spain, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing in Murcia, and that even the people there are not great. While I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay too much attention to the Spanish perception of the city, my expectations for Murcia were not high - little did I know that every part of mid-year, even the location, would be wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The journey to mid-year itself was a fun adventure. I got on the AVE from Zaragoza to Madrid Atocha (Puerta de Atocha is a major train station in Madrid). As soon as I stepped off of the train, I saw one of my friends, a Fulbright Master&amp;rsquo;s candidate in Salamanca, and my orientation roommate. The train to Murcia that most of Fulbright was taking wasn&amp;rsquo;t leaving for a couple of hours, so we had time to buy some food. We walked into a cafe in Atocha and immediately saw a group of people that somehow struck us as American (though them all being about our age helped too), and it turns out they were all ETAs in La Rioja. We had a great time meeting them and learning about how their grant had been going. Soon enough it was time to go to the meeting point, so we headed down to the main level of Atocha. I was immediately overwhelmed with excitement at seeing all my Fulbright friends - the ones I had seen just a couple of weeks ago in Barcelona, but also ones from Madrid and other places. We all made our way to the platform, and it was crazy with about 150 excited Fulbrighters all catching up with each other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was assigned a seat on the train next to a friend, and two other friends were right in front of us, so we had a great time chatting and watching the scenery. The train ride soon turned into me walking around our train car to talk to everyone I knew, making new friends in the car, and then venturing with a friend into the cafe car. I was shook when I walked into this car and it was literally just a full on mobile bar. Within moments of walking in someone offered me some wine, and I easily spent an hour of the train ride sipping &lt;em&gt;rioja&lt;/em&gt;, talking (well, shouting) to friends new and old, and watching the beautiful landscape of Spain change as we traveled South. (&lt;em&gt;The specific thought of drinking rioja on a train is making me so incredibly nostalgic for Spain).&lt;/em&gt; And then all of a sudden we were in Murcia!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-main-cathedral-of-murcia&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/murcia_cathedral.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The main cathedral of Murcia&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/murcia_cathedral.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The main cathedral of Murcia
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mid-year itself was a wonderful whirlwind with very little sleep but a lot of fun. In format, it was very similar to orientation and the research seminar. It consisted of presentations, workshops, cocktail parties, exploring the city we were in (Murcia may be unimpressive by Spanish standards, but as an American I was pleasantly surprised), and lots of time to socialize. While the Fulbright name tags and printed out schedules were similar to orientation, the feeling was completely different. Before, meeting people and talking to them felt like awkward networking. Now, it felt fun and relaxed, but also exciting. I enjoyed conversations with people that now felt like friends, where we got to share our experiences, talk about our research, and get to know each other better. Before, the presentations were endless information coming from the Commission, but now they were talks from my friends about their work. Before, the cocktail parties felt exhausting, but now they were a really fun chance to see everyone and enjoy free unlimited wine.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-university-where-mid-year-took-place&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/universidad_murcia.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The university where mid-year took place&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/universidad_murcia.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The university where mid-year took place
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other Fulbrighters, especially the researchers (who I spent the most time with), definitely made mid-year what it was -  I am absolutely blessed to be among these incredible people. They are so cool, deeply passionate and intelligent people with really interesting life stories and experiences. We have a lot of respect for each other intellectually and an understanding of each others desires to dive deeply into our disciplines, but also a lot of love for each other, and so much fun together going to bars/clubs until way too late or exploring new cities. Honestly, while I made a lot of incredible friends at Dartmouth, I was disappointed by how many students were only there to spend time in their Greek house before getting a job on Wall Street. Finding my people at Dartmouth took some time, whereas out of the group of about 30 researchers/master&amp;rsquo;s students here, I genuinely liked and had fun and even enlightening conversations with every one of them. &lt;em&gt;(I was video chatting with a couple of Fulbright friends yesterday and we were talking about how cool it is that we are all starting grad/med school in the fall and generally how impressive everyone we met through Fulbright is - the friendships I made have persisted, as has my awe of them!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some highlights of mid-year (or more like small details I don&amp;rsquo;t want to forget):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploring Murcia with some friends right after we got in - the river was beautiful to walk along, there&amp;rsquo;s a casino that&amp;rsquo;s actually a beautiful building that was fun to explore, and afterwards I was able to enjoy a glass of my new favorite drink, vermouth&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-exploring-the-casino-with-some-friends&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino_me.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Exploring the casino with some friends!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino_me.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Exploring the casino with some friends!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-im-always-so-amazed-at-how-beautiful-the-details-are-in-european-architecture&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;I&amp;rsquo;m always so amazed at how beautiful the details are in European architecture&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    I&amp;rsquo;m always so amazed at how beautiful the details are in European architecture
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-obviously-seeing-a-mirror-merited-a-mirror-selfie&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino_friends.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Obviously seeing a mirror merited a mirror selfie&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/casino_friends.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Obviously seeing a mirror merited a mirror selfie
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Group lunches that weren&amp;rsquo;t scheduled with enough time (we had 1.5 hours to find a place and eat, in &lt;strong&gt;Spain&lt;/strong&gt;, where lunch is supposed to be a 2+ hour affair) so we were all late to everything but collectively so it was fun. We really should have broken up but we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the heart to eat in groups smaller than a cool 16&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How hard Murcia tourism tried to sell us on the city of Murcia -  they showed us a video of Murcia (after about 18 hours in the city at this point I already recognized many of the places), gave us free stuff, and tried to convince us to come back. Professors at the university also tried to recruit several of us for graduate programs or in my case a research internship&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watching two close friends of mine give amazing presentations on their research - Anna on complex systems and modeling ants, and Ash on developing an HIV vaccine. My friends are so brilliant! Other Fulbrighters I want to get to know better also gave great presentations on topics such as using social media to learn languages, indigenous languages in Spain, and the role of touch in education for young children&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attending some pretty cool grantee-led workshops. One of them was on sustainability in Spain, and it was interesting to explore ways we have observed Spanish culture being more or less sustainable than American culture. I also attended a session where we discussed how we have been adjusting to and enjoying life in Spain, which gave me a lot of new ideas that I want to try here!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A workshop where a male professor was pretty condescending to me and a few of my female friends, but we stood our ground and clapped back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A market in Murcia with a lot of cool food options (there was some vegetarian Murcian food that was actually very good, surprisingly) that we ended up going to on multiple nights. The market also had a secret bar that you opened a window to get into - on the last night, all of Fulbright went there (the Comission included), and then to a bar/club with &amp;ldquo;erasmus&amp;rdquo; in the title&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Fulbright talent show! A bunch of the ETA regions gave entertaining and funny performances, which was great - everyone in La Rioja took their own bottle of wine up on stage and had a very well done and enthusiastic performance. A research friend of mine did some hilarious stand up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cocktail party to end mid year - unlike the orientation cocktail, where I was exhausted and hungry, it was fun to dress up for this cocktail, enjoy the free unlimited wine, and see all of my friends at once. I will say, Fulbright has made me a lot better at navigating cocktail parties&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Mid-Year was a lovely, wonderful time.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-barca-gangs-cocktail-photo-i-really-am-an-honorary-barcelona-researcher&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_cocktail.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The Barca gang&amp;rsquo;s cocktail photo (I really am an honorary Barcelona researcher)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_cocktail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The Barca gang&amp;rsquo;s cocktail photo (I really am an honorary Barcelona researcher)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valencia is on the way back from Murcia to Zaragoza, so I convinced five friends to stop by, and we spent 24 hours in Valencia on the way back! We were all so exhausted (going out until 3 am 2 nights in a row when you have to wake up at 8 am the next day is not ideal) and knocked out for a good 10 hours that night, but we also had a great time. Valencia is beautiful - with its Catalan-esque language (this is actually very contentious, according to two taxi drivers we had), palm trees, and beautiful architecture, it feels like a smaller, warmer and less touristy version of Barcelona. We had a great time eating &lt;em&gt;paella&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;horchata&lt;/em&gt;, seeing the modern arts and sciences center, and exploring  the city center.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-valencia-is-beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/valencia_fountain.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Valencia is beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/valencia_fountain.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Valencia is beautiful
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-arts-and-sciences-center-at-night-with-my-friends-ash-olivia-and-miranda&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/valencia_sciences.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The arts and sciences center at night with my friends Ash, Olivia and Miranda&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/valencia_sciences.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The arts and sciences center at night with my friends Ash, Olivia and Miranda
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;




  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-tasting-some-paella&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/paella.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Tasting some paella&amp;hellip;&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/paella.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Tasting some &lt;em&gt;paella&lt;/em&gt;&amp;hellip;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-and-horchata-with-fartons-food-is-a-true-highlight-of-this-city&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/horchata.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;and horchata with fartons! Food is a true highlight of this city.&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/horchata.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    and &lt;em&gt;horchata&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;fartons&lt;/em&gt;! Food is a true highlight of this city.
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe that I only have 3 months left in Spain, but I&amp;rsquo;m absolutely going to make the most of them. My best friend is coming and we&amp;rsquo;re going to road trip around Mallorca for a week. My family (including my sister this time) is going to come to do Andalucia and a couple of days in Portugal. I&amp;rsquo;m determined to make it to Northern Spain - &lt;em&gt;pais vasco&lt;/em&gt; and Asturias both seem incredible, especially once it gets a little warmer. A few more friends from the US also want to try to make it over - I am blessed with visitors! It&amp;rsquo;s going to be busy and crazy and I will literally travel every weekend for a month or two, but I&amp;rsquo;m so excited for all of the places I want to explore and people I want to get closer to. &lt;em&gt;(Okay, so obviously none of that happened&amp;hellip;.except for getting closer to people. More on that soon)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #11: FAT*</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written February 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I closed out the insane month of January with a 4-day trip to Barcelona for the FAT* conference, which pulled together computer scientists, lawyers, people in the tech industry, and social scientists to talk about fairness, accountability and transparency in computing. This was my first academic conference ever, and I had an incredible time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go to the conference because it was conveniently a 1-hour train ride away, Fulbright was going to fund my attendance, and it seemed important and relevant to my interests. It ended up being much more meaningful than I had anticipated -  I&amp;rsquo;m so happy I had the opportunity to go! Beyond just talking to CS academics and people in the tech industry, I got to talk to lawyers and professors in non-CS fields. There were so many cool talks that exposed me to ways of thinking I had never experienced before. There were also a handful of Berkeley PhD students there and it was great to meet them and learn about ways I can be involved in similar discussions once I go there. I&amp;rsquo;m definitely excited for what&amp;rsquo;s ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always understood that thinking about the implications and ethics of CS is important, and put effort into educating myself in those areas, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never learned as much about bias in computing, or how to make AI explainable, or challenges in creating AI policies, as I did during this conference. The talks I attended definitely changed my personal evaluation of different AI systems I encounter - right now, neural networks optimize for some loss function that minimizes error, but what they instead were optimized in a way that penalizes bias? I also thought AI explainability was an extremely interesting and important area, since frequently a neural network will give us a result and but we have no idea why it is returning that result, and as a result neural networks lead to all sorts of problems (read 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1710.08864.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; about how a single pixel change can completley fool a neural network).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-miranda-and-anna-at-fat&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/fat*.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me, Miranda, and Anna at FAT*!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/fat*.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me, Miranda, and Anna at FAT*!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the conference, being in Barcelona and with the other Fulbright researchers was incredible. There&amp;rsquo;s a cohort of about 10 Fulbright researchers in Barcelona and they are all amazing people. We had a lot of fun group dinners in the 3 nights I was there, including one with most of us crammed into the corner of a tapas bar and being unnecessarily crazy after one round of beers. At some point in this visit, the Barcelona crew officially adopted me as one of their own, adding me to the group chat and everything, which was adorable. Audrey, a neuroscience researcher who is going to go to med school next year, very graciously hosted me the entire time I was there, and we bonded incredibly. It&amp;rsquo;s rare that you can spend 6 hours one on one with someone, have nonstop conversation the whole time, and then be shocked that 6 whole hours have passed. I attended the conference with Anna and Miranda, the two other CS researchers (both of who are so cool and brilliant and wonderful), and while none of us have explicitly done research in AI fairness or related fields, we had a great time exploring the conference together and talking about how our views on our own research changed throughout it.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-for-some-reason-our-group-photo-after-dinner-one-night-involved-me-being-carried&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_din.HEIC&#34; data-caption=&#34;For some reason, our group photo after dinner one night involved me being carried&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_din.HEIC&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    For some reason, our group photo after dinner one night involved me being carried
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #10: The Longest Winter Break</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 13:51:02 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-10/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written January 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was so happy to go home for the holidays, even though I had to experience a taste of Minnesota winter. It was incredible to be with my family and see friends back home, as always, but it felt especially comforting to have the familiarity and ease of being around the people I&amp;rsquo;ve grown up with who speak English the same way I do. One of the biggest highlights was food - as a vegetarian, traditional Spanish cuisine is not the best for me, and Spain also lacks good Asian food, so I relished in going to all my favorite restaurants back home and eating my mom&amp;rsquo;s food. Another highlight was trying out a free week of hot yoga with my sister and generally getting to spend time with her. Overall, I  realized that there are things in America I love and feel more comfortable with, but there were things about Spain I missed too, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready to leave Spain (and I&amp;rsquo;m still not&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a hard transition back to America). &lt;em&gt;(My transition back ended up being so premature and jarring in a very different way from how I expected.)&lt;/em&gt; Right after New Years, I stopped in NYC for about 48 hours on the way back to meet up with some friends for a truly glorious 48 hours. I&amp;rsquo;m impressed at how much food I was able to consume in those 48 hours. We also discovered a really cool speakeasy and overall had the best time! &lt;em&gt;(Rip NYC - it&amp;rsquo;s crazy that I was there so recently. Definitely happy that I enjoyed it while I could.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-enjoying-some-ethiopian-food-in-nyc-with-my-best-friend&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ethiopian_nyc.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Enjoying some Ethiopian food in NYC with my best friend&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ethiopian_nyc.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Enjoying some Ethiopian food in NYC with my best friend
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went back to Spain on January 5 so that I could spend January 6, &lt;em&gt;Dia de los Reyes&lt;/em&gt;, with my friend Cristina and her family, who live just outside of Madrid. &lt;em&gt;Dia de los Reyes&lt;/em&gt; is the most important day of Christamas in Spain - the day where everyone opens their presents, and then eats &lt;em&gt;roscon&lt;/em&gt;, a traditional cake. It was very cool to experience Christmas as they do. My family doesn&amp;rsquo;t do traditional Christmas gifts, so it was fun to do that with her family (they were very generous!). Her family is the sweetest and I had a lovely time despite the jet lag.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-cristinas-familys-christmas-tree&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/christmas_tree.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cristina&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;rsquo;s Christmas tree&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/christmas_tree.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Cristina&amp;rsquo;s family&amp;rsquo;s Christmas tree
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-roscon-it-has-a-little-toy-baked-into-it&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/roscon.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;The roscon. It has a little toy baked into it&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/roscon.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The &lt;em&gt;roscon&lt;/em&gt;. It has a little toy baked into it
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I went back to Zaragoza for 5 days before I was off to India for a whirlwind 6 day trip! Those few days were truly a warm, crazy fever dream. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really sleep but I did eat so much good food (I really forget how amazing Indian food in India is) and saw an insane amount of family members. My family in India consists of a few hundred people and so the majority of my trip was just me trying to remember the names of the relative I was talking to&amp;hellip;we really need a pocket family tree.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-reunited-with-my-favorite-person-after-a-whole-week-apart-and-also-with-some-of-my-favorite-food&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/nitya_swatis.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Reunited with my favorite person after a whole week apart, and also with some of my favorite food!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/nitya_swatis.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Reunited with my favorite person after a whole week apart, and also with some of my favorite food!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were two major highlights of the trip:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, going to Ahmedabad, where my nana (grandfather on mom&amp;rsquo;s side) grew up and my mom frequently went as a child. We have some family there that I haven&amp;rsquo;t seen that much, so it was nice to see them. Some of them live in a house that has a backyard with trees that grow little baby guavas and real peacocks that hang out there! There was also a kite flying festival when we visited, where all the kids (and many adults) fly kites all day and night. During the day, people try to &amp;ldquo;cut&amp;rdquo; other people&amp;rsquo;s kites out of the sky (the kite strings are made with broken glass and so you can also easily cut yourself while flying a kite), and at night, people string lanterns on kites. Lots of safety/fire hazards, but still an amazing time, and very pretty.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-flying-kites-with-my-sister-dad-and-some-uncles&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites_daylight.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Flying kites with my sister, dad and some uncles&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites_daylight.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Flying kites with my sister, dad and some uncles
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-kites-at-night-were-so-beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The kites at night were so beautiful!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/kites.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The kites at night were so beautiful!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then, the wedding, which was mostly why we were there. Indian weddings are INSANE. This wedding was only 2.5 days long, and it was the shortest Indian wedding I&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard of - it&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for most weddings to take place over 5 days or even a week. There were 4 different functions, so I of course had to wear 4 different outfits. One of my favorite parts was the &lt;em&gt;baraat&lt;/em&gt;, where the groom&amp;rsquo;s family dances in the streets directly before the actual wedding ceremony. My dad is such a child at heart and it&amp;rsquo;s adorable - he especially enjoyed a lot of the wedding. Overall, it was fun to be surrounded by so much family, and to see my dad with all the people he grew up with!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-love-a-family-photo&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/family_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;We love a family photo!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/family_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We love a family photo!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-all-the-wedding-outfits-are-a-lot-of-fun&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;All the wedding outfits are a lot of fun&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    All the wedding outfits are a lot of fun
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-my-dad-had-a-great-time-at-the-wedding-with-his-cousins&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/dad_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;My dad had a GREAT time at the wedding with his cousins&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/dad_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    My dad had a GREAT time at the wedding with his cousins
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-maybe-13-of-the-cousins-on-my-dads-side-my-grandmother-on-his-side-is-one-of-7-sisters&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/cousins_wedding.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Maybe 1/3 of the cousins on my dad&amp;rsquo;s side (my grandmother on his side is one of 7 sisters&amp;hellip;)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/cousins_wedding.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Maybe 1/3 of the cousins on my dad&amp;rsquo;s side (my grandmother on his side is one of 7 sisters&amp;hellip;)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #9: December in Spain</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 16:01:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written December 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holiday season in Spain was incredible! I could feel the spirit in the air in a much more visceral way than when I was in America. This was definitely due to everyone&amp;rsquo;s joyful attitudes, but also in part due to the Christmas markets and decorations - all of the cities put up gorgeous lights.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-heres-a-taste-of-what-zaragoza-looked-like-for-all-of-december&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz_lights.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Here&amp;rsquo;s a taste of what Zaragoza looked like for all of December&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz_lights.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Here&amp;rsquo;s a taste of what Zaragoza looked like for all of December
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-and-heres-one-of-my-favorite-plazas-in-madrid&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/madrid_lights.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;And here&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite plazas in Madrid&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/madrid_lights.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    And here&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite plazas in Madrid
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over their winter break, more of my Dartmouth friends came to Spain. Two of them came to visit me in Zaragoza, and then we went to Barcelona together and met up with a few more friends! By that point, I was very comfortable in Zaragoza, so it was a blast to show them around the city, introduce them to my Spanish friends, and take them to my favorite bars for &lt;em&gt;juepincho&lt;/em&gt;. It is so special to share a place you love with people you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barcelona was a blast, as always. &lt;em&gt;(And it would just keep on getting better&amp;hellip;that city has a very special place in my heart).&lt;/em&gt; We ate a lot of good food (finding great Korean food in Barcelona was a dream come true), did a Freixenet &lt;em&gt;cava&lt;/em&gt; tasting and tour, and explored some parts of the city I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen before. The highlight was definitely taking my Dartmouth friends to a party with all of the 10 or so Barcelona Fulbright researchers. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to actually see and get to know them more, I adore the other Fulbright grantees. We had a ton of fun that night just talking until it didn&amp;rsquo;t even make sense to leave my friend&amp;rsquo;s apartment and go to a bar, and it made me very excited that I&amp;rsquo;ll be returning to Barcelona in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for visiting friends, I had the best time with you guys! Here are some photos from our adventures in Barca:&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-it-took-me-going-to-la-sagrada-familia-3-times-to-get-a-photo-in-front-of-it-by-the-way-its-just-as-impressive-every-single-time&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/sagrada.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;It took me going to la Sagrada Familia 3 times to get a photo in front of it. By the way, it&amp;rsquo;s just as impressive every single time&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/sagrada.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    It took me going to &lt;em&gt;la Sagrada Familia&lt;/em&gt; 3 times to get a photo in front of it. By the way, it&amp;rsquo;s just as impressive every single time
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-cava-tastings-are-always-fun-but-a-little-less-so-when-its-11-am-and-you-were-at-your-friends-apartment-until-very-late-the-night-before&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/freixenet.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cava tastings are always fun, but a little less so when it&amp;rsquo;s 11 am and you were at your friends apartment until very late the night before&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/freixenet.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cava&lt;/em&gt; tastings are always fun, but a little less so when it&amp;rsquo;s 11 am and you were at your friends apartment until very late the night before
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-showing-my-friends-around-the-gothic-quarter&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/gothic.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Showing my friends around the gothic quarter&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/gothic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Showing my friends around the gothic quarter
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-watching-the-sunset-from-the-bunkers-del-carmel&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/bunkers.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Watching the sunset from the Bunkers del Carmel&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/bunkers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Watching the sunset from the &lt;em&gt;Bunkers del Carmel&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my friends left, I had a little over a week in Zaragoza before I headed home for the holidays. In this time we had a lab Christmas dinner, which was a lot of fun - after a blissfully early 8 pm dinner we all went to a bar for 4 full hours. I had an amusing conversation in Spanish with the head PI of my lab about the Minnesota Vikings (which he became a fan of during a year abroad in the Midwest but I know very little about - but my dad is a huge fan so when I told him about this he was thrilled) around 2 am. In addition to festivities with the lab, one of the woman in Aiko&amp;rsquo;s class who is from Vietnam opened an incredible Vietnamese restaurant, so we all started going there a lot. We also had a group Christmas dinner there -  I guess people are really into Christmas dinner here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I was all of a sudden back in Madrid for a night before an early morning flight back home! By a stroke of luck there ended up being a Fulbright party the one Wednesday night I was in Madrid, so I got a chance to see a lot of my research friends, as well as meet a bunch of the english teaching assistant grantees. This year has already made me a lot better at navigating parties/cocktails where I don&amp;rsquo;t know a lot of people - I used to be very shy when meeting new people, but now I have a blast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the end of 2019 in Spain was a great time. I also did some work that month too, but for once, not that much work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #8: Enjoying Life in Spain</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 23:02:21 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written December 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, so much has been happening, that it&amp;rsquo;s been hard to keep up with regular emails. So here are some highlights from the end of October to November:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents visited! I guess they are coping with now being empty nesters by traveling more? The timing worked out nicely because I got to spend my birthday with them, the weather was nice, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too touristy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first stop was Barcelona. They did all the touristy stuff, and on my birthday we went to Montserrat and then the Sagrada Familia which are both absolutely stunning, so we basically went to the prettiest places in the world that day. That night, we had some amazing &lt;em&gt;paella&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;vino&lt;/em&gt; for dinner, and then after a little too much wine I ran to the train station and thought I was going to miss my train, but turns out the train station was shut down due to protests (from the Catalan independence movement), so that was a bit of an adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some photos from our time in Catalunya:&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-loved-this-catalonian-wine-that-is-made-out-of-volcanic-ash-my-parents-and-i-have-a-shared-love-of-wine&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ash_wine.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;We loved this Catalonian wine that is made out of volcanic ash (my parents and I have a shared love of wine)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ash_wine.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We loved this Catalonian wine that is made out of volcanic ash (my parents and I have a shared love of wine)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-exploring-the-nearby-city-of-girona&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/girona.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Exploring the nearby city of Girona&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/girona.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Exploring the nearby city of Girona
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-montserrat-is-beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/montserrat1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Montserrat is beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/montserrat1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Montserrat is beautiful
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we went to Zaragoza. Zaragoza isn&amp;rsquo;t that big so I already felt like I knew at least the center of the city really well, and it was so fun to be able to show them around. Apparently my dad was at first very skeptical of Zaragoza, but after seeing it and doing the few touristy things you can do here, he &amp;ldquo;was very impressed&amp;rdquo;. Both of my parents ended up loving the city. &lt;em&gt;(Wow, I miss Zaragoza.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we went to Madrid, which was so much fun. We had a nice dinner with the host families me and Nitya had when we did a Spanish exchange program in high school, and overall had a great time in the city! One highlight was going to a Thai restaurant - I had been craving good Thai for a while, since most Spanish cities really lack Asian food of any type. I love discovering more cool spots and delicious new restaurants every time I visit Madrid and Barcelona, which has ended up being quite a bit already. &lt;em&gt;(And it would just be more and more - I really miss both of those cities now, but I&amp;rsquo;m also really happy with how well I know them now.)&lt;/em&gt; Also, we went to Toledo, which is absolutely breathtaking - I would highly recommend going there.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-outside-the-palacio-real-de-madrid&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/palace_madrid.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me outside the Palacio Real de Madrid&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/palace_madrid.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me outside the &lt;em&gt;Palacio Real de Madrid&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once my parents left, a lot of other events and new friendships made Zaragoza really start to feel like home, and led to a lot of fun memories being made!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to Logroño, the capital of &lt;em&gt;La Rioja&lt;/em&gt;, the region of Spain where &lt;em&gt;rioja&lt;/em&gt; wine is made. Aiko and I roadtripped with Miguel, one of my lab friends. We all bonded a lot singing along to random songs and going to a &lt;em&gt;bodega&lt;/em&gt; tour/wine tasting together, tried &lt;em&gt;pinchos&lt;/em&gt; typical to &lt;em&gt;La Rioja&lt;/em&gt;, and overall had a very lovely day.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-aiko-and-i-touring-the-bodega-with-miguel-thankfully-there-to-translate-the-half-of-the-spanish-tour-i-didnt-pick-up&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aiko_logrono.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Aiko and I touring the bodega with Miguel thankfully there to translate the half of the Spanish tour I didn&amp;rsquo;t pick up&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aiko_logrono.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Aiko and I touring the &lt;em&gt;bodega&lt;/em&gt; with Miguel thankfully there to translate the half of the Spanish tour I didn&amp;rsquo;t pick up
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met a new friend from Florida through mutual friends and we immediately hit it off. She&amp;rsquo;s here through the &lt;em&gt;auxiliares&lt;/em&gt; program, which is similar to the english teaching branch of the Fulbright program. As much as I have appreciated and enjoyed primarily spending my time with Spanish people and other non-Americans, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have other people who better understand what you&amp;rsquo;re going through. She also knows a lot of people through the &lt;em&gt;auxiliares&lt;/em&gt; and erasmus programs, so I&amp;rsquo;ve met a lot of new people through her. One highlight of this was eating pizza that Italian erasmus students made&amp;hellip;it was very good pizza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to get closer to people in Zaragoza. Aiko&amp;rsquo;s Spanish class hangs out a lot and we started doing frequent Sunday potluck lunches. I started going to &lt;em&gt;juepincho&lt;/em&gt; (extra cheap &lt;em&gt;pinchos&lt;/em&gt; (tapas) hopping on Thursday, 1-2 euros for a drink and food!) almost every week. My favorite vegetarian pinchos are &lt;em&gt;croquetas de boletus&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;queso de cabra&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;champinones&lt;/em&gt; (grilled mushrooms with garlic and salt on bread), and any of the selections of cheese at a bar entirely dedicated to different kinds of cheese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanksgiving made me feel a bit homesick &lt;em&gt;(now it seems weird that I felt homesick, when now I&amp;rsquo;ve been home for much more than I thought I ever would)&lt;/em&gt;, since that&amp;rsquo;s normally the one time I&amp;rsquo;m always home, but knowing that I was going home for the holidays just 3 weeks later made it better. On Thanksgiving day I had dinner with some friends at a Mexican restaurant in Zaragoza - that describes the absurdity and magic of this year and I love it. I also had a lovely friendsgiving with my new American friend and some other &lt;em&gt;auxiliares&lt;/em&gt; that weekend where we cooked an amazing meal!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-our-friendsgiving-spread&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/friendsgiving.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Our friendsgiving spread&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/friendsgiving.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Our friendsgiving spread
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I started taking Spanish lessons at a language school here, which has been extremely helpful for grammatical concepts I had forgotten. It&amp;rsquo;s truly a throwback to high school with all of the worksheets and conversation/listening activities, and has helped me noticeably improve my Spanish!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #7: The Fulbright Research Seminar</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 09:53:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-7/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written November 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late November, the Fulbright research seminar gave me an incredible weekend in Madrid. &lt;em&gt;(Wow, I have a lot of nostalgia for that weekend.)&lt;/em&gt; The Spanish Fulbright Commission brought us all to Madrid for a couple of days to talk about our research and hang out, and it was a ton of fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My weekend started on a Thursday: two of my college friends visited Spain, so I got to Madrid a day early to hang out. It felt surreal to hear stories that mentioned &amp;ldquo;flitzes&amp;rdquo; (a flirty blitz - asking someone out via email), a term that only exists very specifically within the Dartmouth bubble, after so many weeks without even talking to any Americans. We spent a great afternoon and evening walking around the city, going to museums, and getting tapas. Three highlights: getting some delicious sangria at a tapas bar, finally going to the &lt;em&gt;Museo Reina Sofia&lt;/em&gt;, and discovering the best chocolate croissant of my life the next morning at my friend Jiachen&amp;rsquo;s recommendation to try out the famous and very crowded Madrid bakery La Mallorquina. &lt;em&gt;(I definitely made it back to that bakery in future trips to Madrid).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I parted ways with my friends, it was time for the research seminar! Everyone was arriving at different times, so after checking into the hotel, me and a few other Fulbrighters walked around and discovered an amazing place with great healthy, vegetarian options. Then, after a quick cafe con leche, we made our way to the university where the seminar was held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The seminar consisted of a mix of remarks from alumni, people at the commission and even someone from the embassy, small group workshops, poster presentations, and individual presentations. It was great to reconnect with everyone, hear about the research they were getting into, and hear about how they were adjusting to living in their various cities in Spain. I loved learning about my fellow grantee&amp;rsquo;s research projects, spanning disciplines from the implications of fashion in Spanish history to using complex systems to model the behavior of ants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to orientation, I felt a lot less overwhelmed, and that I actually knew people better this time, so gatherings felt much less like networking events and more like a wonderful chance to hang out and catch up. The moments throughout the seminar where we got to talk and the big dinner most of us went out to didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like nearly enough. Every conversation felt meaningful, whether it was about marathon training or interdisciplinary research or Spanish politics or adjusting to our host cities. I had assumed that the other grantees would be very accomplished and interesting, and that assumption was proved extremely true as I got to know them, but I also got to see how passionate, caring and kind the other Fulbrighters are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the second day of the seminar, I got to present my research. I don&amp;rsquo;t love public speaking and felt a bit nervous, but this was a really great opportunity. After I presented many friends, even some with non-STEM backgrounds, told me that felt like they had an idea of what I was doing with my research, which was pretty awesome :)&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-during-my-presentation&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/fulbright_presentation.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me during my presentation!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/fulbright_presentation.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me during my presentation!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The seminar ended with a Thanksgiving lunch, which was the sweetest ending note possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night after the seminar, I stayed in Madrid and hung out with Fulbright friends. One of my new Fulbright friends who is doing her Master&amp;rsquo;s in the city graciously hosted me, and I had a lovely time getting to know her better. A bunch of us went out to the famous &lt;em&gt;Teatro Barceló&lt;/em&gt; until 6 am (I said I would do it once, and now I never want to again) and it was a fun experience. Not quite as fun, but still an experience, was waking up at 11 am the next morning for the Spanish Civil War tour. A Fulbright grantee who is currently doing his PhD in Spanish history led us around Madrid and showed us places of significance in the Spanish Civil War - so cool and a unique view of a city I&amp;rsquo;m getting to know and love. Overall, lots of memories were made and much bonding occurred that weekend!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #6: Fiestas del Pilar</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 23:29:04 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written October 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fiestas del Pilar,&lt;/em&gt; commonly called &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;pilares&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo; is an ~11 day long citywide festival in Zaragoza. For these 11 days, there are concerts and events from 8 am to early into the next morning (basically 8 am to 7 am). The biggest event happened towards the end, on Saturday 12/10 (look at me using European dates now - that&amp;rsquo;s October 12) with the &lt;em&gt;ofrenda de flores&lt;/em&gt;, but there were countless social, religious and cultural events throughout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never experienced anything similar in the US. Let me start by describing the city of Zaragoza a bit more, to situate &lt;em&gt;pilares&lt;/em&gt;: Zaragoza seems to be optimized for socialization. One central tram line runs down the city, and along it, there are endless plazas surrounded by restaurants with ample outdoor seating. You can walk through the main center of the city in about 20 minutes. One major plaza, Plaza España, leads into the &lt;em&gt;casco antiguo&lt;/em&gt;, or old town, known for its narrow, windy streets full of tapas bars. There are very few tourist attractions in this city - it&amp;rsquo;s all about the locals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Except maybe this weekend, when hordes of people from the surrounding region of Aragon, and also Madrid, Barcelona, la Rioja and other places, came down for &lt;em&gt;pilares&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;em&gt;Pilares&lt;/em&gt; was a much bigger and culturally-rich version of Green Key, Dartmouth&amp;rsquo;s spring music festival, or any other music festival I&amp;rsquo;ve been to in the states. Instead of being 3 days, it was 11. Instead of being limited to a college campus, it was in the whole city, and you could walk for 45 mins through Zaragoza and hear different concerts throughout the whole walk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of just college students celebrating, it was everyone. Entire families, elderly people, literal babies with their parents, college students, people of various ability levels, actually everyone. I loved how so many more partook in Pilar than I normally see when I went to bars/clubs in the US. &lt;em&gt;(This pattern holds for bars in general in Spain - it&amp;rsquo;s normal for whole families to go out together, young children included.)&lt;/em&gt; The amount of people that came out and filled the plazas was genuinely amazing. It was also funny to literally see a beer bottle on the ground next to a child in a stroller. Probably a consequence of people being around alcohol literally since infancy, the people here actually seem to party much more responsibly than I&amp;rsquo;m used to at Dartmouth. I expected everyone partying all the time to be gross, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t see any excessive trash on the ground or vomit or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, some highlights of Pilar:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First weekend: checked out some concerts and went to a food/music festival close to the city center.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the week: Went to more concerts, hung out in the plaza, etc, but mostly tried to conserve my energy. One valuable thing I did take away from Dartmouth is to treat festivals like a marathon, not a sprint.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-and-aiko-at-a-concert-held-by-the-city-wearing-the-red-and-black-bandanas-that-all-women-traditionally-wear-during-pilares&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_aiko_pilares.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me and Aiko at a concert held by the city, wearing the red and black bandanas that all women traditionally wear during pilares&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/neerja_aiko_pilares.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me and Aiko at a concert held by the city, wearing the red and black bandanas that all women traditionally wear during pilares
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many people were out at all times like wow look at this PACKED plaza: &lt;em&gt;(It&amp;rsquo;s crazy remembering this, the biggest crowd I ever saw, now in the time of coronavirus)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/pilares_plaza.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/pilares_plaza.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second weekend: More concerts and hanging out. The highlight was on Saturday, with the &lt;em&gt;ofrenda de flores&lt;/em&gt;, where lots of people participate in a parade that ends up with offering flowers, which is then arranged into a literal floral mountain. The flowers were incredible. Aiko decided to walk with the Japanese society of Aragon, so we met a bunch of people through that and ended the day at a cafe with new friends, which made for a very fun day.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/flores.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/flores.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, we went to an event with giant caricatures of famous Spanish people that we realized had a target audience of children aged 2-7, but was nonetheless still fun.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-caricatures-and-an-audience-of-children-with-their-parents&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/caricatures.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Caricatures and an audience of children with their parents&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/caricatures.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Caricatures and an audience of children with their parents
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final day of festivities ended with some of the best fireworks I&amp;rsquo;ve ever seen. What a wonderful end to an amazing 11 days!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, the next week we were all exhausted and got sick but it&amp;rsquo;s okay because basically from the beginning of October until New Year&amp;rsquo;s is lots of holidays (I have a long weekend for Halloween and a 4 day weekend at the beginning of December&amp;hellip;I love Spain).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #5:  Adjusting to life in Spain</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 23:18:39 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written October 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, here&amp;rsquo;s an update about everything in my non-work life, which for once is actually a very significant part of my life!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loving my apartment. We got a 4th roommate and her name is Genesis. She is from Venezuela but has lived in Spain for a few years and knows so much about life here that I am clueless about. For example, one night she suggested ordering in food, which I had somehow not realized was something you could do in Spain. And then she proceeded to show me 4 or 5 different apps that I had no idea existed.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-aiko-and-genesis-bonding-on-our-way-to-dominos---turns-out-dominos-is-a-roommate-bonding-mechanism-worldwide&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/flatmates.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me, Aiko, and Genesis bonding on our way to Domino&amp;rsquo;s - turns out Domino&amp;rsquo;s is a roommate bonding mechanism worldwide):&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/flatmates.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me, Aiko, and Genesis bonding on our way to Domino&amp;rsquo;s - turns out Domino&amp;rsquo;s is a roommate bonding mechanism worldwide):
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of other friends, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten to know Aparna, a woman in Aiko&amp;rsquo;s intensive 20-hours-a-week Spanish class. She&amp;rsquo;s a professional yoga instructor from India and here to learn Spanish to take her yoga business to other countries (I&amp;rsquo;m being exposed to so many meaningful things people do with their lives that would have never occurred to me back at Dartmouth). Aparna, Aiko and I all go to the same gym and have had fun exploring the city together.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-yoga-in-the-park-next-to-my-apartment&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/yoga.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Yoga in the park next to my apartment&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/yoga.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Yoga in the park next to my apartment
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-tapas-y-cerveza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aikoaparna.JPG&#34; data-caption=&#34;Tapas y cerveza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aikoaparna.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Tapas y cerveza&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting how everyone I hang out with is at least about 4 years older than me - such a change from college! I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying meeting new people, but I still feel pretty connected to people far away (my favorite times of the day are tied between when I have my afternoon cup of coffee and when my family and close friends Sarah and Sean wake up and text me every day without fail). I&amp;rsquo;m also enjoying having more time to myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been so cool to live and work with people from completely varied backgrounds. Almost every day at lunch with my labmates, we fall into talking about a given subject and how it compares in Spain vs the US vs France (we have a postdoc from Nice) - meal sizes/times, how leaders are elected, mushrooms, coffee, PhD programs, cheese, really anything&amp;hellip;it&amp;rsquo;s funny how the smallest things can be so different from place to place. And the small things really matter. For example, I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that people here care more about waiting for others. If we&amp;rsquo;re walking back from a group meeting or lunch and someone for any reason wants to have a quick conversation with someone, we all wait for them and then walk back to our lab together. While this action is unnatural to me after a lifetime in America, I love the concept and practice of treating people like they are more important than maximal productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today during our post-lunch coffee break (a daily ritual here), we were talking about stereotypes people have about other countries. Someone said that Spain is known as being all about &amp;ldquo;siesta and fiesta&amp;rdquo; and honestly&amp;hellip;not an inaccurate way to describe my life. I&amp;rsquo;m actually learning how to chill! (I do have some problems with the concept of &amp;ldquo;chill&amp;rdquo; the way it is frequently used, but I think that relaxing is nice.) When I was in college, I would do work all the time, even on breaks. But now, I&amp;rsquo;ve actually decided to stop working when I leave work, and to relax over the weekends, and to prioritize my sleep and health and friendships over or at least on par with work. I know that there&amp;rsquo;s so much more to life than work, but I haven&amp;rsquo;t always lived my life that way, and right now is the perfect time for me to develop a sustainable balance. I left Dartmouth so burnt out and don&amp;rsquo;t want to feel the same way during/after my PhD, because life is too short to be exhausted and stressed out all the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Speaking Spanish has been an adventure. I have a certain sense of humor in English, and I also have a sense of humor in Spanish (or maybe I just make people laugh by sounding stupid), but they&amp;rsquo;re distinct. The way I form thoughts in English is so different from how I have to think through Spanish, and speaking a lot of Spanish has deepened my appreciation of the ease of speaking in my native language. I feel like my Spanish is improving but not as much as I want it to. When I speak with groups of Spainards, I still have a hard time understanding what they are saying, and coming up with responses in the pace of the conversation. When I speak one-on-one with people, I can have a pretty full conversation and am sometimes surprised at perfect phrases I whip out, but there&amp;rsquo;s a depth at which I can&amp;rsquo;t express myself that I can in English. I feel like I can&amp;rsquo;t connect with people when speaking in Spanish in the same way that I can with English-speaking friends, which is a bit frustrating. I&amp;rsquo;m considering taking Spanish classes to improve my language abilities. &lt;em&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m so happy I ended up taking classes!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Things have been inevitably frustrating at times: when I misspeak in Spanish, or when I think I said something correctly, but someone still speaks English back to me. When I realize I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing something one way but there was a much easier way. Having to deal with Spanish bureaucracy (don&amp;rsquo;t get me started on empadronamiento or tarjeta identidad extranjeria). But it&amp;rsquo;s kind of cool that my first time adulting for real is here, because it&amp;rsquo;s going to be amazing to go back to America and know with conviction that the bottled sauce I bought is indeed for pasta, or negotiate a lease in my native language, or to be able to find things like tofu and edamame easily. Things haven&amp;rsquo;t been always easy, but I am so grateful for these experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of what&amp;rsquo;s ahead - my parents are visiting soon and we&amp;rsquo;re going to go to Barcelona (or maybe not, because there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of protests happening there right now&amp;hellip;we&amp;rsquo;ll see) and Madrid and I&amp;rsquo;m so excited! Down the line, some friends are going to be spending part of their winter break in Spain which I cannot wait for. I might also make a trip to La Rioja with Aiko to basically just do a bunch of wine tasting sometime in November. Basically, I&amp;rsquo;ll be traveling a little more than every other weekend and then coming home for Christmas, so the rest of 2019 is going to be crazy in the most wonderful way possible. &lt;em&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I traveled while I could.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #4: My Research Grant</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2020 11:07:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written October 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can&amp;rsquo;t believe that I&amp;rsquo;ve been in Spain for over a month. It&amp;rsquo;s flown by, and strangely feels like this is my life now, and I&amp;rsquo;m loving it! There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of exciting non-work related stuff happening, but I&amp;rsquo;ll save that for the next update - I want to take this one to explain what I&amp;rsquo;m doing here work-wise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m working in the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://graphics.unizar.es/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Graphics and Imaging lab&lt;/a&gt; at University of Zaragoza. There are 3 or 4 professors in the lab, a handful of postdocs, and a decent amount of PhD students, making for a total of about 20 people, which is pretty large. The lab is full of incredibly smart, impressive people. &lt;em&gt;(In addition to being smart, they&amp;rsquo;re also very nice and fun - I ended up having some fun adventures with my lab mates and am still close to many of them).&lt;/em&gt; They publish at amazing conferences, collaborate with places such as MIT and Stanford (and Dartmouth), and the students intern at top graphics places in industry such as Adobe Research and Disney. I&amp;rsquo;m really honored to get to be working with people that know so much, and I&amp;rsquo;ve already learned a ton. They also seem to be very well-funded, and have encouraged me to attend a conference (there&amp;rsquo;s a few in France/Switzerland in the next few months), which is awesome and such a cool opportunity!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m getting started on a really interesting project here: combining deep learning and compressed sensing, and important technique in signal processing. Here&amp;rsquo;s the basic idea of compressed sensing: Normally when we acquire a signal (I&amp;rsquo;ll use the example of taking a picture), we get way more data than we can actually transport, so we immediately compress it. So an image is always immediately reduced to a JPEG or another form, by finding all of the unimportant information and getting rid of it. With compressed sensing, we only acquire a small fraction of the information (so for a 100x100 pixel image, instead of getting values for all 10,000 pixels, we might just get values for 1,000 of them) through a measurement mask, and then we can reconstruct the original image. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of fascinating math that shows that we can with very high probability reconstruct the image if certain conditions hold, and we can perform these computations in a reasonable amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-left-the-measurement-mask-used-to-capture-an-image-of-a-scene-middle-the-captured-image-with-missing-information-right-the-reconstructed-image&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/CS_overview.png&#34; data-caption=&#34;left: the measurement mask used to capture an image of a scene; middle: the captured image, with missing information; right: the reconstructed image&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/CS_overview.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    left: the measurement mask used to capture an image of a scene; middle: the captured image, with missing information; right: the reconstructed image
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some very cool results with this. One of my favorite is a paper where researchers took a single image, that to the naked eye just looks like a normal, slightly blurry photo, but were actually able to get pixels at slightly different times and then from that single photo reconstruct 30 frames for a resulting 1 second video! More recently, with the rise of machine learning, people are combining the mathematical basis of compressed sensing with neural networks to get amazing results in a lot of applications. So my research is generally within this area! I&amp;rsquo;ve only had one meeting for my project so far, but it went well, and I like the people I&amp;rsquo;m working with. &lt;em&gt;(It&amp;rsquo;s fun remembering the beginnings of my project, now seeing what it has evolved into.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my daily/weekly schedule, it&amp;rsquo;s pretty much what I want. We have a weekly lab meeting, and I have regular meetings for my deep compressed sensing project. Aside from those meetings, there isn&amp;rsquo;t any time I am required to be in the lab, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found a regular schedule to be helpful. I also have a lot of flexibility to work remotely and take vacation when I want to, as long as it&amp;rsquo;s not in excess, which is really nice. My daily routine is typically something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~8:15 wake up, get ready&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:00 head to take the tram to work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:30 get to work, say hi to everyone, and start working. This involves a mixture of reading papers, coding, data analysis, and writing, depending on what I have to do for the day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1:30 break for lunch. We all go eat together and take a full hour for lunch or sometimes more. This is an early lunch by Spanish standards, but the cafeteria fills up at 2 so we try to get there before that&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2:30 hit the coffee machine after lunch. There&amp;rsquo;s a vending machine that will make you any sort of coffee/hot chocolate beverage you want (very common in Europe, we need these in America), but I prefer these machines - 40 cents for some of the best coffee! My lab mates think it&amp;rsquo;s unremarkable and that the bad coffee in America has ruined my standards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;





  











&lt;figure &gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/coffee_machine.jpg&#34; &gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/coffee_machine.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;400&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;



&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;~2:45/3, depending on how long a coffee break we take: back to work! Often around now I&amp;rsquo;ll start getting distracted because all my friends/family in the US will wake up and start sending me messages :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;5:30 head out, though sometimes I stay longer if I have more to do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;6:00 go to gym or go for a run!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7:30 make dinner, I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to eat at 8:30/9 but often am hungry much earlier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:00 until bedtime: sometimes more work if I have to, oftentimes reading/watching Spanish TV/talking to friends in America. Sometimes I&amp;rsquo;ll go out for dinner or grab a drink with friends, which will always be at 9 pm or later&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m loving this lifestyle. I might try to join a club or take formal Spanish lessons soon, but for now it&amp;rsquo;s nice to just focus on work and then on enjoying life. I adore doing research full time. It&amp;rsquo;s nice to not have to put time into classes and to be able to make doing research/learning what I need to learn for research my top priority. I love spending my days making progress on my projects and learning a TON and having freedom in what to work on. I&amp;rsquo;m learning a lot about my research style and strengths/weaknesses, which I think will be super helpful when I pursue my PhD back in America. There are definitely stressful points, when code doesn&amp;rsquo;t work or something doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense, or the fact that in research you&amp;rsquo;re literally trying to stretch the boundaries of knowledge which means a lot of times ideas won&amp;rsquo;t pan out. &lt;em&gt;(I ended up feeling these points a lot, but nontheless really enjoyed what I did).&lt;/em&gt; I&amp;rsquo;m also working on 2 projects right now, since I&amp;rsquo;m continuing a project I started at Dartmouth last year, but the intensity of Dartmouth prepared me well, and it&amp;rsquo;s so nice to focus on doing fewer things but doing them well. I also really like the lab environment - I&amp;rsquo;m so happy that I ended up here!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #3: Settling into Zaragoza</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 23:29:41 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written September 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After orientation, I hopped on the AVE (a high speed train, we really need this in America) and got to Zaragoza! I was exhausted from the combination of orientation and traveling with 2 suitcases that together weigh about as much as me, so I was ready to eat some food and crash. Despite being really hungry, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go into a restaurant, a little bit because I have a fear of eating alone in public, especially in a country as social as Spain, and mostly because most restaurants don&amp;rsquo;t serve dinner until 9 pm in Zaragoza. Wanting to find a grocery store to make some easy pasta, I typed grocery store in Google maps, and nothing came up. Then, I tried translating &amp;ldquo;grocery store&amp;rdquo; to Spanish, plugged that word in to maps, and the only things that came up were sex shops&amp;hellip;.so not helpful at all. I gave up and had some McDonalds for dinner. (The next day I realized I needed to be searching for &amp;ldquo;supermarket/supemercado&amp;rdquo;, oops). So my start to living in Zaragoza was sitting in my Airbnb alone eating some fries - hopefully it&amp;rsquo;ll all be uphill from there. &lt;em&gt;(Thankfully, it was all very uphill!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was busy the next several days with a lot of adult errands. I opened a bank account, and even before Fulbright had sent me my first payment, it was  exciting that my empty bank account said 0 euros instead of dollars - yay to no international transaction fees! I started the apartment hunt, going to places I had found on idealista. Thankfully, my Spanish somehow sufficed. The first 3 apartments I saw were: a place where 2 other Erasmus students lived (European college students that study abroad in other parts of Europe mostly so that they can party relentlessly for 6 months, and remember that the clubs are open until 7 am here), a place that reeked of cigarette smoke everywhere, and a place that had 4 boys living there (not for me). But then I found &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; apartment and luckily things worked out! I have lots of closet space, a dishwasher, a huge living room, air conditioning, and a kitchen that was gorgeous once we deep cleaned it. My roommates are awesome - there&amp;rsquo;s Miguel, a 29 year old from Madrid who is studying to become some sort of lawyer, and Aiko, a 25 year old from Japan who is here to learn Spanish so she can work in the ministry of foreign affairs in South America in a few years. We have a 4th roommate, and all I know about her is that she&amp;rsquo;s coming in a few days, but I&amp;rsquo;m excited to meet her!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found a really lovely gym right next to my apartment. It has 2 pools and a lot of fitness classes and even a spa all included and would probably be insanely expensive in America but since Zaragoza has a much lower cost of living I can easily afford it. I have absolutely no excuses to not work out a lot at this point, and am excited to try out the yoga and spin classes at the gym. I spent a lot of time cooking, which I&amp;rsquo;m loving - I&amp;rsquo;m slowly learning and able to make more advanced things, and it feels so great to cook healthy things for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So overall, even though there have been ups and downs as expected, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling good about my start in Spain. I&amp;rsquo;m actually loving the city of Zaragoza - it&amp;rsquo;s calm and non-touristy but also has a lot to do. It feels weird to have everyone I love thousands of miles away, and it can be hard to only speak in English some days over a WhatsApp or FaceTime call with a poor connection. There have been times I&amp;rsquo;ve felt a bit lonely, especially in contrast to the very social culture in Spain, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been grateful to always have my family or a friend to call. It&amp;rsquo;s been kind of nice to not know people (well, until I got roommates and started making friends) and have a good reason to just spend a lot of time with myself doing whatever I want to do - I can see why people like solo traveling. &lt;em&gt;(I remember that halfway through my Fulbright I reflected on this initial loneliness I felt as I walked through plazas in Zaragoza full of people socializing with each other, and being very grateful for all the new friends I had made that I explored the city with. It can be really fun to explore a place alone, but personally, I love having people to share the experience and grab a caña with.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have very few expectations and am excited to see where this year takes me. All I do know is that I&amp;rsquo;m going to do what I want to do and prioritize myself, and I&amp;rsquo;m really grateful to have this gift of a year in Spain to do just that!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #2: Orientation</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 23:29:41 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written September 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I arrived to Madrid pretty exhausted off of a red eye, and went to the Airbnb I was going to stay in for the night with another Dartmouth &amp;lsquo;19 who got a Fulbright to be a TA in Asturias, a region in Northern Spain. I was pretty dead, but decided to head with them to a bar for a pre-orientation Fulbright event. The bar consisted of a lot of people my age talking very loudly and I was soon overwhelmed and exhausted at having to scream to converse, a common thread throughout orientation. I opted to not drink, since I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really eaten or slept. I was able to meet some people and they were all really nice, but I was happy to leave after an hour to go meet up with Cristina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cristina is my host sister from a 2-week Spanish exchange back in high school, and we&amp;rsquo;ve stayed in touch ever since. She just passed the exam to become a teacher, and she&amp;rsquo;s now teaching English to middle and high schoolers in Madrid. She&amp;rsquo;s one of the kindest and most genuine people I&amp;rsquo;ve ever met, and it&amp;rsquo;s so nice that I started my Fulbright with at least one friend within a 200 mile radius! We had dinner and went to a rooftop bar (which I enjoyed much more than the last rooftop bar that I went to, Mr. Purple, in NYC), and it was wonderful to catch up and talk about potential vacations &lt;em&gt;(I read the word vacations and first thought it said vaccinations - this pandemic is getting to me. Then I remembered there will be no more vacations for a long while)&lt;/em&gt; around Europe we could take together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then proceeded to knock out for 11 hours, which was very necessary because I had no idea how crazy orientation would be. Our days were packed with important info sessions and required social events from 7 am until past 9 pm, and then dinner time was after 9, per the Spanish eating schedule (a breakfast of basically just coffee at 7, a coffee break at 11, lunch at 2 or 3 or 4, and dinner around 10 pm + very little sleep - hence tons of coffee. This country seems a bit permanently jet lagged but so am I so it&amp;rsquo;s all good). I would drink at least 2 cups of coffee, but they make really strong espresso, and I more than once found my body literally shaking from caffeine. There were so many people to meet - it felt like college orientation all over again, except I knew I wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to see most of these people again since we are all living in different parts of Spain &lt;em&gt;(spoiler alert: I was very wrong about this)&lt;/em&gt;. Every day we had a mandatory 7-9pm cocktail event, during which we were drinking free tinto (red wine + lemonade, very delicious) and cerveza (beer) on empty stomachs since we were hungry for dinner. I was pretty overwhelmed and delirious, and felt ungrateful for feeling that way because I also recognize that this is an incredible opportunity and was excited to meet so many really cool and passionate people, but I guess a need for sleep is valid.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The makeup of the Fulbrighters was interesting. The researchers group is fairly gender-balanced and about as diverse as Dartmouth (so, not that diverse, but also not all white), but the TAs were largely composed of white women. I haven&amp;rsquo;t felt that noticeably in the minority in a long time. Clearly, it&amp;rsquo;s a privilege to get a Fulbright, but it&amp;rsquo;s also a huge privilege to be able to do a Fulbright and choose a year of personal fulfillment and travel over a higher-paying job, and that shows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I took notes during a lot of the sessions, because while my brain was only half functional during orientation, the information we received was  important and interesting. We learned what Fulbright expected of us - it&amp;rsquo;s really strict in some ways, for example we can&amp;rsquo;t leave Spain for more than 21 days, but also laid back in others, such as the fact that we don&amp;rsquo;t need to deliver any final product for our research (so while I definitely plan to do good work, work doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be my #1 priority at all times). Also, they told us we should definitely take weekends to relax and explore and definitely not do work - what a concept! &lt;em&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m so happy that I used my weekends in Spain for things other than work.)&lt;/em&gt; We learned about a lot of differences between America and Spain. Everyone uses WhatsApp here, people are generally warmer, even in professional settings, drinking is a huge part of the culture in the way that people will even bring their children to bars, every region has festivals that last all night (and also clubs are open until 7 am - I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I can ever go clubbing here because they open at 2/3 am which is when I like to be solidly asleep).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently Spain is quite progressive when it comes to laws around and percentage of people that identify as queer, especially compared to America, which was great to hear. But it&amp;rsquo;s also far from perfect - they told us that there&amp;rsquo;s a tradition in Spain as part of a festival where people wear blackface, and that it&amp;rsquo;s normal for people to joke about things that would be considered very offensive in the US. I have no idea how much of that is really true, and am interested to see what my experience will be like, especially since Zaragoza is not diverse. While the conversation the presentations started was not very in depth, I did approve of the message they promoted about trying to respect where other people are coming from while also asserting our own boundaries and explaining why certain things are not okay for us, when we feel comfortable engaging. I  believe that everyone has their beliefs in large part because of how they were raised and socialized, and that hopefully if I encounter anything unfortunate it can be a starting point for conversations where people can learn and grow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got to meet all the other researchers and hear about their projects, which was cool. Out of the 25, there are 2 other CS researchers. The split between humanities and STEM research is pretty even. A lot of the researchers are currently doing their PhD, and they know so much about what they are studying so it was super interesting to get to talk to them! &lt;em&gt;(It&amp;rsquo;s so fun to read this, now knowing the friends mentioned here so much better.)&lt;/em&gt; One is going to be excavating ceramics to search for signs of a plague before the bubonic plague in Barcelona. Another is going to collect nuts in a forest in Granada to get data for her ecology project. I spent a lot of time talking to this awesome woman who just graduated from Harvard law and knows so much about Spanish law and random facts about Spain (do you know that Spain is on the wrong time zone because Franco wanted Spain to have the same time zone as Nazi Germany? More support for this country literally being jet lagged). One guy who is finishing his biophysics PhD at MIT just got married to a Spanish woman he met when she did an exchange at Harvard! What a cool group of people - it&amp;rsquo;s too bad that I&amp;rsquo;m not in the same city as any of them, but we have an active WhatsApp group and a few more meetups than the rest of Fulbright Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Orientation passed by in a blur, but the last presentation stuck out, from the American consulate in Spain. They said some stuff to scare us, but I really feel like Spain is much safer than America&amp;hellip;there are basically no guns here, and while Spain has a &amp;ldquo;medium&amp;rdquo; terrorism threat, the US is much higher. The really stupid things Americans have done in Spain was very entertaining. One guy took a lot of illegal drugs in Ibiza and is currently in Spanish prison, so basically do NOT take a pill in Ibiza. Another guy went to visit a friend, went clubbing with his passport, lost his passport and phone, got separated from his friend and didn&amp;rsquo;t know where his friend lived in and so he went to the consulate, but couldn&amp;rsquo;t log into his Facebook to message his friend or remember his mother&amp;rsquo;s phone number so she could wire him money. Thankfully, emergency contacts exist. Also, don&amp;rsquo;t go clubbing with your passport.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #1: Hola!</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 23:29:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written September 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first 11 posts in my &amp;ldquo;Neerja en España&amp;rdquo; series will be very lightly edited emails that I sent my friends while I was in Spain. Since a lot has changed since I wrote them, I&amp;rsquo;m adding retrospective comments in italics to the posts that I wrote while I was living through them. Here&amp;rsquo;s the first email I sent:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The summer after graduation flew by between cherished time at home, travels to Europe with family, and a trip to the East Coast with my best friend to visit some of our college friends who started work. Now I&amp;rsquo;m in Spain, which has already been crazy, but I first wanted to explain what the Fulbright actually is and what I&amp;rsquo;ll be doing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two broad kinds of Fulbright grants: the English teaching assistant grant (ETA), and the research/masters grant (which I am here on). For both grants, Fulbright pays us a stipend for living expenses and facilitates us getting a visa into Spain and setting us up. Spain has the second-largest Fulbright program, with over 150 ETAs and about 30 research/masters students. The ETAs are all placed in one of 6 regions of Spain where they are assigned a school and teach classes for about 20 hours a week. The research/masters students are all over Spain, since we got to choose our host institution as part of our project proposals. The majority of us are in Madrid or Barcelona, but there are a few like me who are in other cities, such as Seville, Salamanca, Granada, and Leon. After a few days orientation in Madrid, we all go to our respective cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m the only Fulbright student in my city, Zaragoza. Zaragoza is a medium sized city (~700K people), located right in between Madrid and Barcelona - it&amp;rsquo;s a little over an hour on the high speed AVE train to either city (&lt;em&gt;I ended up taking the AVE so many times, and loving it more and more each time)&lt;/em&gt;. Even though it&amp;rsquo;s smaller, it definitely has everything I need, and has a lot to explore, especially compared to Hanover. Also, apparently Zaragoza has the highest amount of bars/clubs per capita in all of Spain. Zaragoza is much less touristy than most other cities its size or bigger in Spain, which is really nice, since the cost of living is lower here and I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to actually immerse myself in Spanish culture. One of Zaragoza&amp;rsquo;s most famous attractions is the huge basilica - here&amp;rsquo;s a photo of it:&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-from-httpscommonswikimediaorgwikifileup_from_the_highest_tower_16079304178jpg&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz_pilar.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;from https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Up_from_the_highest_tower_(16079304178).jpg&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz_pilar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;  &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    from &lt;a href=&#34;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Up_from_the_highest_tower_(16079304178).jpg&#34;&gt;https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Up_from_the_highest_tower_(16079304178).jpg&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m pretty nervous to be the only one in my city, since I know literally no one here and don&amp;rsquo;t have an automatic cushion of American Fulbrighters to fall back on. I expect the first month or so to be a little rough. However, I think that it&amp;rsquo;ll overall be good for me, since I&amp;rsquo;ll hopefully form deeper friendships with people that are not American, which is important to me, and in the meantime I&amp;rsquo;m grateful FaceTime exists! &lt;em&gt;(I ended up befriending many non-Americans, and while I was apprehensive I am so grateful that I specifically ended up in Zaragoza)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my actual project, I will be doing research somewhere within the convex hull of graphics, vision, and computational photography. I&amp;rsquo;m not exactly sure what my project will be, but the lab I&amp;rsquo;ll be working in at Universidad de Zaragoza does a lot of very cool things, so I&amp;rsquo;m excited to get working! I&amp;rsquo;m not sure exactly what my schedule will be like, but I should be doing the same amount of work equivalent to a 9 to 5 job, working in the lab every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This year is really going to be what I make of it, in every way. In terms of work, Fulbright doesn&amp;rsquo;t expect us to create any sort of final product with our research, as long as we are working on it consistently. So while publishing a paper would be nice, it&amp;rsquo;s in no way required. I definitely want to get great work done and learn more about my research interests and style, but aside from near deadlines, I don&amp;rsquo;t plan to work as intensely as I will be during my PhD. In terms of the rest of my life, I have a lot of freedom, and I definitely want to use this year in a lot of ways. When I studied abroad in Budapest, I was essentially an American tourist in Budapest and only made friends with other American students, and I absolutely don&amp;rsquo;t want this year to be a repeat of that. My top personal goals/to-dos include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve my Spanish (I&amp;rsquo;ve been pleasantly surprised at how decent it is, but I still have a ways to go in becoming totally fluent)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve my cooking abilities and make my health a priority - sleep a lot and work out regularly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make non-American friends and expose myself to new perspectives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travel to a lot of places in Spain! I&amp;rsquo;m only allowed to leave the country for 21 days, but there&amp;rsquo;s so much to see just in Spain that I&amp;rsquo;ll still be able to travel a ton. I already have the Asturias, southern Spain and the Canary islands at the top of my list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m really happy that I ended up achieving all of these goals to a pretty good extent, except for the places I traveled to ended up being different - I very sadly did not make it to Asturias, Andalucia, or Las Canarias)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that answers some of the questions you guys have been asking me and gives you a sense of what I&amp;rsquo;ll be up to for the next year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
