<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zaragoza | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/places/zaragoza/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerjathakkar.github.io/places/zaragoza/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Zaragoza</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 23:29:41 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/images/icon_hu86b94514bc44f7650ad97bf1bd4dbea1_2402_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Zaragoza</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/places/zaragoza/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja in Espana #3</title>
      <link>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 23:29:41 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerjathakkar.github.io/post/neerja-espana-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After orientation, I hopped on the AVE (a high speed train, we really need this in America) and got to Zaragoza! I was exhausted from the combination of orientation and traveling with 2 suitcases that together weigh about as much as me, so I was ready to eat some food and crash. Despite being really hungry, I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to go into a restaurant, a little bit because I have a fear of eating alone in public, especially in a country as social as Spain, and mostly because most restaurants don&amp;rsquo;t serve dinner until 9 pm in Zaragoza. Wanting to find a grocery store to make some easy pasta, I typed grocery store in Google maps, and nothing came up. Then, I tried translating &amp;ldquo;grocery store&amp;rdquo; to Spanish, plugged that word in to maps, and the only things that came up were sex shops&amp;hellip;.so not helpful at all. I gave up and had some McDonalds for dinner. (The next day I realized I needed to be searching for &amp;ldquo;supermarket/supemercado&amp;rdquo;, oops). So my start to living in Zaragoza was sitting in my Airbnb alone eating some fries - hopefully it&amp;rsquo;ll all be uphill from there. &lt;em&gt;(Thankfully, it was all very uphill!)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was busy the next several days with a lot of adult errands. I opened a bank account, and even before Fulbright had sent me my first payment, it was  exciting that my empty bank account said 0 euros instead of dollars - yay to no international transaction fees! I started the apartment hunt, going to places I had found on idealista. Thankfully, my Spanish somehow sufficed. The first 3 apartments I saw were: a place where 2 other Erasmus students lived (European college students that study abroad in other parts of Europe mostly so that they can party relentlessly for 6 months, and remember that the clubs are open until 7 am here), a place that reeked of cigarette smoke everywhere, and a place that had 4 boys living there (not for me). But then I found &lt;strong&gt;the&lt;/strong&gt; apartment and luckily things worked out! I have lots of closet space, a dishwasher, a huge living room, air conditioning, and a kitchen that was gorgeous once we deep cleaned it. My roommates are awesome - there&amp;rsquo;s Miguel, a 29 year old from Madrid who is studying to become some sort of lawyer, and Aiko, a 25 year old from Japan who is here to learn Spanish so she can work in the ministry of foreign affairs in South America in a few years. We have a 4th roommate, and all I know about her is that she&amp;rsquo;s coming in a few days, but I&amp;rsquo;m excited to meet her!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found a really lovely gym right next to my apartment. It has 2 pools and a lot of fitness classes and even a spa all included and would probably be insanely expensive in America but since Zaragoza has a much lower cost of living I can easily afford it. I have absolutely no excuses to not work out a lot at this point, and am excited to try out the yoga and spin classes at the gym. I spent a lot of time cooking, which I&amp;rsquo;m loving - I&amp;rsquo;m slowly learning and able to make more advanced things, and it feels so great to cook healthy things for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So overall, even though there have been ups and downs as expected, I&amp;rsquo;m feeling good about my start in Spain. I&amp;rsquo;m actually loving the city of Zaragoza - it&amp;rsquo;s calm and non-touristy but also has a lot to do. It feels weird to have everyone I love thousands of miles away, and it can be hard to only speak in English some days over a WhatsApp or FaceTime call with a poor connection. There have been times I&amp;rsquo;ve felt a bit lonely, especially in contrast to the very social culture in Spain, but I&amp;rsquo;ve been grateful to always have my family or a friend to call. It&amp;rsquo;s been kind of nice to not know people (well, until I got roommates and started making friends) and have a good reason to just spend a lot of time with myself doing whatever I want to do - I can see why people like solo traveling. &lt;em&gt;(I remember that halfway through my Fulbright I reflected on this initial loneliness I felt as I walked through plazas in Zaragoza full of people socializing with each other, and being very grateful for all the new friends I had made that I explored the city with. It can be really fun to explore a place alone, but personally, I love having people to share the experience and grab a caña with.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have very few expectations and am excited to see where this year takes me. All I do know is that I&amp;rsquo;m going to do what I want to do and prioritize myself, and I&amp;rsquo;m really grateful to have this gift of a year in Spain to do just that!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
