<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fulbright application | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerja.me/tag/fulbright-application/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerja.me/tag/fulbright-application/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Fulbright application</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work by Neerja Thakkar is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
© Neerja Thakkar 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 21:36:08 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerja.me/images/icon_hu709051646b5c016a474294f302c76519_2025058_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Fulbright application</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/tag/fulbright-application/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying for the Fulbright Part 3</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/fulbright-app-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 21:36:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/fulbright-app-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neerja Thakkar graduated from Dartmouth in 2019 with a BA in Computer Science and Mathematics. For the past year, she was doing computational photography research in Spain on a Fulbright research scholarship, and in Fall 2020 she will be starting her PhD in EECS at UC Berkeley.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the last post in my series on applying for the Fulbright. In it, I cover a recommended Fulbright application timeline and some other thoughts that I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet covered. If there&amp;rsquo;s anything else you would like to hear about regarding applying for a Fulbright please don&amp;rsquo;t hesitate to contact me!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My first post is 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neerja.me/post/fulbright-app-1/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and the second 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neerja.me/post/fulbright-app-2/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended Timeline&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Assuming an early October deadline)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you&amp;rsquo;re applying, keep in mind that it can take a long time to contact professors abroad, wait to hear back, schedule meetings (especially given time differences), and iterate on a research proposal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Spring: Start the process of deciding on a country/program/research field and reaching out to host institutions - see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neerja.me/post/fulbright-app-1/&#34;&gt;my first post&lt;/a&gt; for some thoughts on how to go about this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;June: Decide on a host institution, do background research, and talk to your advisor in the host institution about your research proposal. Start thinking about your personal statement and brushing up on the language of your host country, if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;July: Draft your research proposal and personal statement. Continue practicing your language. Reach out to letter writers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;August: Iterate on your research proposal with your host institution and continue to work on your personal statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;September: Take your language evaluation. Ask friends and family to look over your essays and suggest changes. If you have to translate your statements into another language, give yourself ample time and see if you can find native speakers to proofread. Revise, revise, revise!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;October: Proofread and submit your application at least a day or two before the official deadline, since the system gets slow towards the end&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fulbright Advisors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many universities have a designated office/advisor for fellowships such as the Fulbright - look up your school&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;fellowship office&amp;rdquo;. Dartmouth has a designated Fulbright advisor, and she was an invaluable resource for me through the process. She was able to give me guidance as I found a host institution, wrote my personal statement, and developed my research proposal. She also provided me with statistics on past applicants from my school and other useful information. If you have such a resource available at your institution, definitely utilize it - any fellowship advisors at your school are there to help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After you submit the application&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After I submitted my application, I didn&amp;rsquo;t hear anything until the end of January, when I found out that I was selected as a semi-finalist. At this point, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to do anything, but I have heard that some countries require more information or interviews (potentially not in English) from semi-finalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, at the end of March, I heard that I was a Finalist (aka I had received the grant)! One important thing to know is that once you get a Fulbright, you have to make a decision about if you want to do it relatively soon, so that you can start the visa process. I was on the fence for a bit while waiting to see if I could defer grad school, and this led to me being a bit behind on getting my visa at first.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fulbright often selects alternates. I have no idea about how many alternates end up being selected, but I do know anecdotally that some definitely are, so don&amp;rsquo;t lose hope if you are an alternate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Best of luck if you choose to apply for Fulbright grant!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying for the Fulbright Part 2</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/fulbright-app-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 21:26:08 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/fulbright-app-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neerja Thakkar graduated from Dartmouth in 2019 with a BA in Computer Science and Mathematics. For the past year, she was doing computational photography research in Spain on a Fulbright research scholarship, and in Fall 2020 she will be starting her PhD in EECS at UC Berkeley.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this post, I break down the most significant components of the Fulbright application. My 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://neerja.me/post/fulbright-app-1/&#34;&gt;first post&lt;/a&gt; on applying for a Fulbright research grant covers focusing your application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This statement is your chance to present who you are and why you deserve a Fulbright grant. The people I met through Fulbright were not only extremely intelligent and accomplished, but they were all incredible humans - caring, passionate, kind, and determined to do good in the world - and I&amp;rsquo;m sure that their personal statements showed this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Obviously, the content of your statement vary greatly depending on who you are. When brainstorming, consider a wide variety of questions such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who you are? Where you are from?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is important to you? What are your values?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What unique experiences have shaped you?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What you have done in and/or after college?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What do you want to do with your life?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, craft a cohesive narrative about yourself. There are a lot of fantastic sources of advise for personal statement writing, so I won&amp;rsquo;t go too in depth, but a few thoughts relevant to Fulbright in particular:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While you don&amp;rsquo;t need to discuss Fulbright or your host country in this statement, think about the culture and values of Fulbright and the country you are applying to, as well as the research you are proposing, and make sure that they align with what you propose and show you fitting in the Fulbright community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This statement should complement your Statement of Grant Purpose - make sure that they paint a cohesive and complete picture of who you are, both intellectually and personally. When revising, you can move some information from one to the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Statement of Grant Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this statement, you should explain the research you&amp;rsquo;re going to do during your grant, and also convince the readers of why a Fulbright grant specifically in your country will help you do your research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One very important thing to keep in mind is that the audience of this statement will probably know nothing about your research area, so you will have to make it extremely accessible. This statement is only two pages, so this will mean that you leave a lot of details critical to your project out, and while this can feel very weird, it&amp;rsquo;s completely okay in this situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should also include some information about how you plan to engage with your host country, since your grant isn&amp;rsquo;t just about your research, but also about cultural exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a broad outline of the statement I wrote:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Broad, accessible introduction to problem/research area&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More detailed technical description of research area/problem&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview of previous work and limitations/room for future work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description of what I will be doing and the methods I will use, and a breakdown of how I will spend the 9 months of my grant year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explanation of why I need to be in Spain and working with this lab in particular for this project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other things I will do in Spain to engage with the community, explanation of my Spanish skills and how I plan to improve them before moving to Spain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How my experience has given me the skills and positioned me to be successful at this project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How this grant ties into my future career goals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Letters of Recommendation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultivating close relationships with professors can only happen far before you apply for a Fulbright, but there&amp;rsquo;s still a lot you can do as you apply to ensure that your letters are the strongest they can be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give your letter writers ample time to write for you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reach out to ask (reminding them of who you are/what classes you took with them if they might not know), and when they say yes, respond with your CV, a summary of what program and kind of research you are applying for, and a list of things you would like them to talk about. You should absolutely mention small details or accomplishements that feel minor which the professor might not recall - the worst thing that can happen is that the professor chooses to not mention it in the letter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be sure to remind your writers about the letter 1 month before the deadline, and again a week before if they haven&amp;rsquo;t submitted it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Language Evaluation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Different programs have different language requirements. I was recommended to demonstrate intermediate Spanish proficiency, but this varies by country/program - some have strict requirements and some don&amp;rsquo;t even have recommendations. The evaluation itself likely varies a lot by language and school and program, so I can only speak to my experience. I had studied Spanish in high school, so I knew a lot at one point, but I hadn&amp;rsquo;t spoken it in almost 4 years by the time I applied for Fulbright. I brushed up by using Duolingo, watching Spanish TV, and speaking it with friends who spoke Spanish. My actual evaluation consisted of a 15 minute conversation with a Spanish professor at Dartmouth, and since I also used past and future tenses, I ended up getting an advanced rating. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that different levels had different requirements, so check in advance with whoever will be conducting your evaluation in order to tailor your practice.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applying for the Fulbright Part 1</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/fulbright-app-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 23:29:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/fulbright-app-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neerja Thakkar graduated from Dartmouth in 2019 with a BA in Computer Science and Mathematics. For the past year, she was doing computational photography research in Spain on a Fulbright research scholarship, and in Fall 2020 she will be starting her PhD in EECS at UC Berkeley.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you look at the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://us.fulbrightonline.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Fulbright website&lt;/a&gt;, you may notice that the amount of different programs you can apply to is huge. There are several axes of freedom where you have to make a decision: the &lt;strong&gt;country&lt;/strong&gt; you apply in, the &lt;strong&gt;program&lt;/strong&gt; you apply for (research/TA/masters), and if you do research, the &lt;strong&gt;host institution&lt;/strong&gt; you work with and the &lt;strong&gt;research project&lt;/strong&gt; you propose. It can feel overwhelming to decide which program to apply for and how to go about the process, so in this post I&amp;rsquo;m going to go over some things I considered and explain how I ended up making a decision. Most of this post will only be applicable for a research Fulbright as part of the US Student program, since that is what I applied for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things to consider as you narrow down what you want to do. Here are some things that I kept in mind:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The acceptance rate varies a lot by country and program. I was able to get some numbers from my school&amp;rsquo;s fellowship office (many universities will help you through this process - definitely use those resources if they are available to you!), and I realized that some countries had an extremely low acceptance rate for research/masters Fulbright&amp;rsquo;s (~2%), whereas others had a much higher acceptance rate (closer to a third of applicants were accepted)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://us.fulbrightonline.org/countries&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;page specific to a country&lt;/a&gt; you are considering very carefully. There are many variations by country and by programs within a country, such as:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some countries have specific requirements (for example, you may need a masters to do research at a particular institution within a country)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some countries have a preference to fund certain kinds of academic fields, so you could be at an advantage or disadvantage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some countries have a language requirement or recommendation. Even if it&amp;rsquo;s a recommendation, it would be wise to only apply to that country if you have that competency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host institution selection
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What city is it in? Do you want to live in that city?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who within the host institution would you be working with?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can your host institution meet with you as often as you will need and give you the resources and support that you need?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would you be happy in this environment for 9 months?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research project proposal
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even if your project is purely STEM, it needs to have some connection to where you are, since Fulbright is funding you for a project in a specific place&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Needs to be supported by host institution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does it meet your personal goals for skills you want to gain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With those considerations in mind, there are different approaches you could take. If you have a research project in mind that you want to undertake, you could think of a country/host institution where it would make sense to propose your research project to. Or, you could take the approach I did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I knew I wanted to do a research Fulbright in the field of computer science (more narrowly, within computer vision/graphics and computational photography). I also wanted to spend a year somewhere in Europe. Narrowing down countries by their acceptance rates, so that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t applying anywhere that generally took less than 10% of applicants, and also by looking for those where language wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a significant barrier, I decided to look for potential research labs in Spain and Switzerland.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found professors in those countries by reading previous work that interested me, and asked my research advisor at Dartmouth if he could send an email introducing me to these professors - he knew many of the ones I wanted to work with, and even for the ones he didn&amp;rsquo;t know, a cold email from another respected professor in the field often has a much higher chance of being read than one from a random student. We contacted one professor at a time, and I soon hit it off with the lab in Spain that I ended up working at. Together, we brainstormed a project that I could talk about in my Fulbright application, and soon I was drafting my proposal - more on that in my next post.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
