<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Barcelona | Neerja Thakkar</title>
    <link>https://neerja.me/places/barcelona/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://neerja.me/places/barcelona/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Barcelona</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>This work by Neerja Thakkar is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International License.
© Neerja Thakkar 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 11:03:42 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://neerja.me/images/icon_hu709051646b5c016a474294f302c76519_2025058_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Barcelona</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/places/barcelona/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #14: Pandemic</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_14/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja_espana_14/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I had discussed in my previous post, the coronavirus was getting progressively worse in Spain. Once Trump made his announcement, I decided to make the most of my remaining time. I am not a spontaneous person, but knowing that I probably at least had 48 hours left in Spain, I decided I was going to go to Barcelona. I booked a train ticket, threw some clothes and toiletries into a bag, and headed to the train station. Train rides were always a fun and special experience for me &amp;mdash; I loved putting on some music and writing in my journal, or just enjoying the beautiful view of the Spanish countryside. But on this train ride, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t even put on music. I just stared at some news on my phone and tried to process Spain falling apart (this was a little before it was clear that the entire world was falling apart and the implications of the pandemic were much more dire than just cancelled foreign study programs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got off the train and took the familiar walk through &lt;em&gt;Estacion Sants&lt;/em&gt; and into the metro, and eventually stepped out onto &lt;em&gt;La Rambla&lt;/em&gt; and walked a block through the beautiful Gothic Quarter to get to my friend Anna&amp;rsquo;s place. She opened the door to her apartment and we gave each other a hug (this was before we really understood the concept of social distancing) and the relief I felt was immediate. It was lovely to finally be with someone who understood my position of likely being forced to leave Spain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We ventured out to a bar Anna wanted to show me. It was magical - I was transported to a forest. Next, we went to my favorite bar in Barcelona (and in the world), a classy place that makes custom cocktails that always end up being the best cocktail I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had, and all seven or so friends I&amp;rsquo;ve taken there agree. Then it was time to meet up with the rest of the Barca gang. We first went to a noodle/dumpling bar, and then we went to another place with empañadas. It was incredible to see everyone - the level of comfort that I felt being surrounded by them after a crazy week was unreal. Audrey proclaimed that she was in denial, but she knew we were all going to be sent home. Apparently the ECA (the branch of the government that runs Fulbright) had said that all exchange programs would have a 60 day pause. We had 90 days left, so this was so clearly the end.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-one-last-sangria-in-an-ethereal-cozy-bar&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/forest_bar.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;One last sangria in an ethereal, cozy bar&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/forest_bar.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    One last sangria in an ethereal, cozy bar
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, we had a busy day ahead of us. Anna had a list of places she wanted to see in Barcelona before she left - mostly various museums - and we were going to make some progress on it. The day had a surreal energy. I knew that our time here was so limited, by days, maybe even hours. It was crazy and terrifying to watch the world fall apart in ways that I had never imagined, but also a beautiful reminder about how special life is, and how much of a gift it was to be half a world away from everything I had known and held familiar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-places-in-barcelona-that-were-now-familiar-felt-extra-remarkable-and-magical-like-this-plaza&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_plaza.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Places in Barcelona that were now familiar felt extra remarkable and magical, like this plaza&amp;hellip;&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_plaza.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Places in Barcelona that were now familiar felt extra remarkable and magical, like this plaza&amp;hellip;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-or-the-hallowed-walls-of-the-gothic-quarter-fun-fact-theres-a-skull-on-the-underside-of-the-pont-del-bisbe&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/gothic_walls.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;&amp;hellip;or the hallowed walls of the Gothic Quarter. Fun fact: there&amp;rsquo;s a skull on the underside of the pont del bisbe&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/gothic_walls.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &amp;hellip;or the hallowed walls of the Gothic Quarter. Fun fact: there&amp;rsquo;s a skull on the underside of the &lt;em&gt;pont del bisbe&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We started the day off with me finally visiting the famous Boqueria market. Then we got brunch with Audrey and a college friend of hers who had just arrived in Barcelona as part of world travel on a Watson fellowship. The meal was wonderful - I had been looking for real American-esque brunch food in Spain the entire time I was there and I had finally found it.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-it-only-took-me-5-trips-to-barcelona-to-go-to-one-of-the-biggest-tourist-attractions&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/boqueria.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;It only took me 5 trips to Barcelona to go to one of the biggest tourist attractions&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/boqueria.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    It only took me 5 trips to Barcelona to go to one of the biggest tourist attractions
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-brunch-with-audrey-and-anna-3&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_brunch.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Brunch with Audrey and Anna &amp;lt;3&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_brunch.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Brunch with Audrey and Anna &amp;lt;3
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, Audrey peeled off, and Anna, our new friend, and I took the scenic route through the Gothic quarter and up to Montjuic. Of course, we were talking about how we would probably all have to leave soon. And then, just as we got to the top and started to take in the beautiful view of the city, Anna got an email. What we had all been dreading was here. Her undergrad institution&amp;rsquo;s Fulbright coordinator told us that we were all going to be sent home and should start booking flights. I stood in silence as Anna talked to her family on the phone, and tried to process this news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few minutes later, I got an email too, sent to all grantees. Spain was now CDC level 3, and we were encouraged to return to the US within the next week. I read the information about closing our bank accounts, how stipend payments would work, and getting a plane ticket, and tried to process this - it felt unreal, even though I knew it had been coming. After Anna and I absorbed this, we tried to go to the Joan Miro museum, but it was closed. The city was shutting down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening, we all gathered at a soccer field near Montjuic with drinks and chocolate and watched the sun set on our Fulbright. We passed sheets of paper around and wrote notes to each other under a one minute time limit. When I got my sheet back, I was amazed at the depth of things that my friends wrote about me, despite me seeing most of them only about 5 times total over the 6 months I had known them. It hit me that I had been a part of and helped create something so special between all of us, and I was so excited to continue building those bonds and enjoying Spain (the castle in Girona that we were all planning to stay at in April really epitomized that), but now it was all just going to end. Later, the pandemic got much worse in America and all of the horrible economic and personal impacts for so many people became clear, but at the time, it just felt like we were being sent home.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-my-friend-sasha-and-i-at-the-soccer-field-overlooking-the-city&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/sasha.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;My friend Sasha and I at the soccer field overlooking the city&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/sasha.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    My friend Sasha and I at the soccer field overlooking the city
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-the-barca-gangs-last-in-person-rendezvous&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_montjuic.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;The Barca gang&amp;rsquo;s last in-person rendezvous&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_montjuic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;700&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    The Barca gang&amp;rsquo;s last in-person rendezvous
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next morning, Anna, our friend Akshay, and I got brunch; the restaurant was already closed for eating and only open for takeout. We sat in Placa de la Universitat - one of the first places I had ever been to in Barcelona, since my sister and I stayed in a hotel near the university my first time in the city. We sat on a bench and I tried to just enjoy looking at the city and talking to my friends, knowing that this would be one of my last moments of peace before I had to pack up my apartment and deal with a million things. I headed to the train station and bought one last ticket to Zaragoza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got home and tried to contemplate having to pack up my entire apartment in the next 2 days. My flatmates were excited - apparently the president was going to address the country in the evening. As I started packing, messages were flying in every WhatsApp group. Everyone was really confused, and debating whether they should say in Spain or leave. They were angry at the lack of clear guidance on exactly what we needed to do from Fulbright, since the email just &amp;ldquo;strongly recommended&amp;rdquo; that we leave. I personally thought that the Comission was very responsive and helpful during this crazy crisis, but the fault was with the US government for having a lack of a clear plan and leadership at the top, which then trickled down to be confusing for us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was definitely conflicted, but I also knew that my family really wanted me to come home, and being with them during this crazy time didn&amp;rsquo;t seem like the worst idea. It also seemed like flights were getting cancelled left and right, so we all had to try to get out of Spain ASAP. My flight was booked for Tuesday originally, but it got cancelled, so I moved to a Monday flight and gave myself less than 24 hours to pack up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That evening, the president of Spain spoke to the country. He announced that Spain was going to enter a strict lockdown, that people would only be allowed to leave their apartments to get groceries, go to the pharmacy, or go to the doctor. All of a sudden, everyone in Spain started taking the virus really seriously. My flatmates and labmates realized that the virus could spiral out of control and that they needed to listen to their leaders - what a contrast to how Americans responded to the virus. On the bright side, the lockdown meant that Spain somewhat got a handle on the virus. Also, the prospect of spending a lot of the next 3 months in my apartment in Spain made leaving a lot easier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next day or so was a whirlwind of packing everything up, realizing it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even fit into the 4 suitcases/duffle bags I had, my labmate Julio saving me by both letting me store a few things at his house indefinitely and driving me to the train station, making it back to Barcelona, and hauling my luggage around until I was at the baggage drop and then Delta agent was merciful with extra baggage for the first time in my memory. I very cautiously got on the plane, feeling aware of my proximity to others in a way that I&amp;rsquo;m now familiar with. I was sitting next to a guy who had been studying abroad in Barcelona and had to leave early, a relatable mood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The screening when I landed on U.S. soil was very lax. They took my temperature, but did no other checks, and I doubt they would have done anything except encourage me to quarantine for 14 days if I did have one. I had low expectations of how America would handle the pandemic, but this was an early indication that it would be even worse. That being said, the gratitude and relief I felt when I saw my family and got home was immense. I missed Spain immediately, but I felt so lucky to have a loving home to return to, to still be on my parents&amp;rsquo; health insurance, and to have my supportive family and wonderful friends to process this unprecedented situation with.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #11: FAT*</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 11:03:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-11/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written February 2020&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I closed out the insane month of January with a 4-day trip to Barcelona for the FAT* conference, which pulled together computer scientists, lawyers, people in the tech industry, and social scientists to talk about fairness, accountability and transparency in computing. This was my first academic conference ever, and I had an incredible time!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to go to the conference because it was conveniently a 1-hour train ride away, Fulbright was going to fund my attendance, and it seemed important and relevant to my interests. It ended up being much more meaningful than I had anticipated -  I&amp;rsquo;m so happy I had the opportunity to go! Beyond just talking to CS academics and people in the tech industry, I got to talk to lawyers and professors in non-CS fields. There were so many cool talks that exposed me to ways of thinking I had never experienced before. There were also a handful of Berkeley PhD students there and it was great to meet them and learn about ways I can be involved in similar discussions once I go there. I&amp;rsquo;m definitely excited for what&amp;rsquo;s ahead!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always understood that thinking about the implications and ethics of CS is important, and put effort into educating myself in those areas, but I&amp;rsquo;ve never learned as much about bias in computing, or how to make AI explainable, or challenges in creating AI policies, as I did during this conference. The talks I attended definitely changed my personal evaluation of different AI systems I encounter - right now, neural networks optimize for some loss function that minimizes error, but what they instead were optimized in a way that penalizes bias? I also thought AI explainability was an extremely interesting and important area, since frequently a neural network will give us a result and but we have no idea why it is returning that result, and as a result neural networks lead to all sorts of problems (read 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/1710.08864.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this paper&lt;/a&gt; about how a single pixel change can completley fool a neural network).&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-miranda-and-anna-at-fat&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/fat*.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me, Miranda, and Anna at FAT*!&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/fat*.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me, Miranda, and Anna at FAT*!
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beyond the conference, being in Barcelona and with the other Fulbright researchers was incredible. There&amp;rsquo;s a cohort of about 10 Fulbright researchers in Barcelona and they are all amazing people. We had a lot of fun group dinners in the 3 nights I was there, including one with most of us crammed into the corner of a tapas bar and being unnecessarily crazy after one round of beers. At some point in this visit, the Barcelona crew officially adopted me as one of their own, adding me to the group chat and everything, which was adorable. Audrey, a neuroscience researcher who is going to go to med school next year, very graciously hosted me the entire time I was there, and we bonded incredibly. It&amp;rsquo;s rare that you can spend 6 hours one on one with someone, have nonstop conversation the whole time, and then be shocked that 6 whole hours have passed. I attended the conference with Anna and Miranda, the two other CS researchers (both of who are so cool and brilliant and wonderful), and while none of us have explicitly done research in AI fairness or related fields, we had a great time exploring the conference together and talking about how our views on our own research changed throughout it.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-for-some-reason-our-group-photo-after-dinner-one-night-involved-me-being-carried&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_din.HEIC&#34; data-caption=&#34;For some reason, our group photo after dinner one night involved me being carried&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/barca_din.HEIC&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    For some reason, our group photo after dinner one night involved me being carried
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #9: December in Spain</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 16:01:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written December 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holiday season in Spain was incredible! I could feel the spirit in the air in a much more visceral way than when I was in America. This was definitely due to everyone&amp;rsquo;s joyful attitudes, but also in part due to the Christmas markets and decorations - all of the cities put up gorgeous lights.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-heres-a-taste-of-what-zaragoza-looked-like-for-all-of-december&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz_lights.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Here&amp;rsquo;s a taste of what Zaragoza looked like for all of December&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/zgz_lights.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Here&amp;rsquo;s a taste of what Zaragoza looked like for all of December
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-and-heres-one-of-my-favorite-plazas-in-madrid&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/madrid_lights.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;And here&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite plazas in Madrid&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/madrid_lights.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    And here&amp;rsquo;s one of my favorite plazas in Madrid
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over their winter break, more of my Dartmouth friends came to Spain. Two of them came to visit me in Zaragoza, and then we went to Barcelona together and met up with a few more friends! By that point, I was very comfortable in Zaragoza, so it was a blast to show them around the city, introduce them to my Spanish friends, and take them to my favorite bars for &lt;em&gt;juepincho&lt;/em&gt;. It is so special to share a place you love with people you love.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barcelona was a blast, as always. &lt;em&gt;(And it would just keep on getting better&amp;hellip;that city has a very special place in my heart).&lt;/em&gt; We ate a lot of good food (finding great Korean food in Barcelona was a dream come true), did a Freixenet &lt;em&gt;cava&lt;/em&gt; tasting and tour, and explored some parts of the city I hadn&amp;rsquo;t seen before. The highlight was definitely taking my Dartmouth friends to a party with all of the 10 or so Barcelona Fulbright researchers. Now that I&amp;rsquo;ve had a chance to actually see and get to know them more, I adore the other Fulbright grantees. We had a ton of fun that night just talking until it didn&amp;rsquo;t even make sense to leave my friend&amp;rsquo;s apartment and go to a bar, and it made me very excited that I&amp;rsquo;ll be returning to Barcelona in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for visiting friends, I had the best time with you guys! Here are some photos from our adventures in Barca:&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-it-took-me-going-to-la-sagrada-familia-3-times-to-get-a-photo-in-front-of-it-by-the-way-its-just-as-impressive-every-single-time&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/sagrada.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;It took me going to la Sagrada Familia 3 times to get a photo in front of it. By the way, it&amp;rsquo;s just as impressive every single time&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/sagrada.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    It took me going to &lt;em&gt;la Sagrada Familia&lt;/em&gt; 3 times to get a photo in front of it. By the way, it&amp;rsquo;s just as impressive every single time
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-cava-tastings-are-always-fun-but-a-little-less-so-when-its-11-am-and-you-were-at-your-friends-apartment-until-very-late-the-night-before&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/freixenet.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Cava tastings are always fun, but a little less so when it&amp;rsquo;s 11 am and you were at your friends apartment until very late the night before&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/freixenet.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    &lt;em&gt;Cava&lt;/em&gt; tastings are always fun, but a little less so when it&amp;rsquo;s 11 am and you were at your friends apartment until very late the night before
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-showing-my-friends-around-the-gothic-quarter&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/gothic.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Showing my friends around the gothic quarter&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/gothic.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Showing my friends around the gothic quarter
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-watching-the-sunset-from-the-bunkers-del-carmel&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/bunkers.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Watching the sunset from the Bunkers del Carmel&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/bunkers.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Watching the sunset from the &lt;em&gt;Bunkers del Carmel&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After my friends left, I had a little over a week in Zaragoza before I headed home for the holidays. In this time we had a lab Christmas dinner, which was a lot of fun - after a blissfully early 8 pm dinner we all went to a bar for 4 full hours. I had an amusing conversation in Spanish with the head PI of my lab about the Minnesota Vikings (which he became a fan of during a year abroad in the Midwest but I know very little about - but my dad is a huge fan so when I told him about this he was thrilled) around 2 am. In addition to festivities with the lab, one of the woman in Aiko&amp;rsquo;s class who is from Vietnam opened an incredible Vietnamese restaurant, so we all started going there a lot. We also had a group Christmas dinner there -  I guess people are really into Christmas dinner here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I was all of a sudden back in Madrid for a night before an early morning flight back home! By a stroke of luck there ended up being a Fulbright party the one Wednesday night I was in Madrid, so I got a chance to see a lot of my research friends, as well as meet a bunch of the english teaching assistant grantees. This year has already made me a lot better at navigating parties/cocktails where I don&amp;rsquo;t know a lot of people - I used to be very shy when meeting new people, but now I have a blast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the end of 2019 in Spain was a great time. I also did some work that month too, but for once, not that much work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neerja en España #8: Enjoying Life in Spain</title>
      <link>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 23:02:21 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://neerja.me/post/neerja-espana-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally written December 2019&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow, so much has been happening, that it&amp;rsquo;s been hard to keep up with regular emails. So here are some highlights from the end of October to November:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My parents visited! I guess they are coping with now being empty nesters by traveling more? The timing worked out nicely because I got to spend my birthday with them, the weather was nice, and it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too touristy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our first stop was Barcelona. They did all the touristy stuff, and on my birthday we went to Montserrat and then the Sagrada Familia which are both absolutely stunning, so we basically went to the prettiest places in the world that day. That night, we had some amazing &lt;em&gt;paella&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;vino&lt;/em&gt; for dinner, and then after a little too much wine I ran to the train station and thought I was going to miss my train, but turns out the train station was shut down due to protests (from the Catalan independence movement), so that was a bit of an adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some photos from our time in Catalunya:&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-we-loved-this-catalonian-wine-that-is-made-out-of-volcanic-ash-my-parents-and-i-have-a-shared-love-of-wine&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ash_wine.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;We loved this Catalonian wine that is made out of volcanic ash (my parents and I have a shared love of wine)&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/ash_wine.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    We loved this Catalonian wine that is made out of volcanic ash (my parents and I have a shared love of wine)
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-exploring-the-nearby-city-of-girona&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/girona.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Exploring the nearby city of Girona&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/girona.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Exploring the nearby city of Girona
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;






  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-montserrat-is-beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/montserrat1.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Montserrat is beautiful&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/montserrat1.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Montserrat is beautiful
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we went to Zaragoza. Zaragoza isn&amp;rsquo;t that big so I already felt like I knew at least the center of the city really well, and it was so fun to be able to show them around. Apparently my dad was at first very skeptical of Zaragoza, but after seeing it and doing the few touristy things you can do here, he &amp;ldquo;was very impressed&amp;rdquo;. Both of my parents ended up loving the city. &lt;em&gt;(Wow, I miss Zaragoza.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, we went to Madrid, which was so much fun. We had a nice dinner with the host families me and Nitya had when we did a Spanish exchange program in high school, and overall had a great time in the city! One highlight was going to a Thai restaurant - I had been craving good Thai for a while, since most Spanish cities really lack Asian food of any type. I love discovering more cool spots and delicious new restaurants every time I visit Madrid and Barcelona, which has ended up being quite a bit already. &lt;em&gt;(And it would just be more and more - I really miss both of those cities now, but I&amp;rsquo;m also really happy with how well I know them now.)&lt;/em&gt; Also, we went to Toledo, which is absolutely breathtaking - I would highly recommend going there.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-me-outside-the-palacio-real-de-madrid&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/palace_madrid.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Me outside the Palacio Real de Madrid&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/palace_madrid.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Me outside the &lt;em&gt;Palacio Real de Madrid&lt;/em&gt;
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once my parents left, a lot of other events and new friendships made Zaragoza really start to feel like home, and led to a lot of fun memories being made!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to Logroño, the capital of &lt;em&gt;La Rioja&lt;/em&gt;, the region of Spain where &lt;em&gt;rioja&lt;/em&gt; wine is made. Aiko and I roadtripped with Miguel, one of my lab friends. We all bonded a lot singing along to random songs and going to a &lt;em&gt;bodega&lt;/em&gt; tour/wine tasting together, tried &lt;em&gt;pinchos&lt;/em&gt; typical to &lt;em&gt;La Rioja&lt;/em&gt;, and overall had a very lovely day.&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-aiko-and-i-touring-the-bodega-with-miguel-thankfully-there-to-translate-the-half-of-the-spanish-tour-i-didnt-pick-up&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aiko_logrono.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Aiko and I touring the bodega with Miguel thankfully there to translate the half of the Spanish tour I didn&amp;rsquo;t pick up&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/aiko_logrono.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Aiko and I touring the &lt;em&gt;bodega&lt;/em&gt; with Miguel thankfully there to translate the half of the Spanish tour I didn&amp;rsquo;t pick up
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met a new friend from Florida through mutual friends and we immediately hit it off. She&amp;rsquo;s here through the &lt;em&gt;auxiliares&lt;/em&gt; program, which is similar to the english teaching branch of the Fulbright program. As much as I have appreciated and enjoyed primarily spending my time with Spanish people and other non-Americans, it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have other people who better understand what you&amp;rsquo;re going through. She also knows a lot of people through the &lt;em&gt;auxiliares&lt;/em&gt; and erasmus programs, so I&amp;rsquo;ve met a lot of new people through her. One highlight of this was eating pizza that Italian erasmus students made&amp;hellip;it was very good pizza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to get closer to people in Zaragoza. Aiko&amp;rsquo;s Spanish class hangs out a lot and we started doing frequent Sunday potluck lunches. I started going to &lt;em&gt;juepincho&lt;/em&gt; (extra cheap &lt;em&gt;pinchos&lt;/em&gt; (tapas) hopping on Thursday, 1-2 euros for a drink and food!) almost every week. My favorite vegetarian pinchos are &lt;em&gt;croquetas de boletus&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;queso de cabra&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;champinones&lt;/em&gt; (grilled mushrooms with garlic and salt on bread), and any of the selections of cheese at a bar entirely dedicated to different kinds of cheese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanksgiving made me feel a bit homesick &lt;em&gt;(now it seems weird that I felt homesick, when now I&amp;rsquo;ve been home for much more than I thought I ever would)&lt;/em&gt;, since that&amp;rsquo;s normally the one time I&amp;rsquo;m always home, but knowing that I was going home for the holidays just 3 weeks later made it better. On Thanksgiving day I had dinner with some friends at a Mexican restaurant in Zaragoza - that describes the absurdity and magic of this year and I love it. I also had a lovely friendsgiving with my new American friend and some other &lt;em&gt;auxiliares&lt;/em&gt; that weekend where we cooked an amazing meal!&lt;/p&gt;





  











&lt;figure id=&#34;figure-our-friendsgiving-spread&#34;&gt;


  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;&#34; href=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/friendsgiving.jpg&#34; data-caption=&#34;Our friendsgiving spread&#34;&gt;


  &lt;img src=&#34;https://neerja.me/img/friendsgiving.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; &gt;
&lt;/a&gt;


  
  
  &lt;figcaption&gt;
    Our friendsgiving spread
  &lt;/figcaption&gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, I started taking Spanish lessons at a language school here, which has been extremely helpful for grammatical concepts I had forgotten. It&amp;rsquo;s truly a throwback to high school with all of the worksheets and conversation/listening activities, and has helped me noticeably improve my Spanish!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
